<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>security on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/security/</link><description>Recent content in security on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 08:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GitHub Security enforcer action</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/github/security-enforcer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/github/security-enforcer/</guid><description>GitHub takes security seriously and gives you some nice capabilities to improve security of your code through all its lifecycle. GitHub actions can be used to automatically run a security code analysis in your repositories, a task that should be run for all of your repositories in your organization.
Security scanning should be enabled on all repositories
Some days ago in a GitHub blog post a new action was announced called Advanced-Security-Enforcer that is aimed to automate the task of adding GitHub Workflow to perform code analysis.</description></item><item><title>TryHackMe Writeup: Daily Bugle</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/writeups/daily-bugle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 08:13:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/writeups/daily-bugle/</guid><description>Security is one of my side passion on computer engineering, and if you also like security, Try Hack Me is a nice place to keep under your radar. This morning I had some fun with Daily Bugle machine so I decided to publish my raw writeup.
Scan the machine A standard NMap reveals ssh and port 80 opened hosting a nice joomla web site. If you do not want to be especially stealthy, you can let nmap test for vulnerability with standard script, nothing special.</description></item><item><title>GitHub security scan - an example</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/github-security-scanning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 15:10:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/github-security-scanning/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve already blogged on the security scanning capability offered by GitHub and in this post I want to give you another example on a possible output. In previous example I&amp;rsquo;ve shown a result that is quite simple the library identified a usage of ECB in AES encryption and flagged it as a wrong usage of crypto api. It is interesting but less impressive, after all it simply spotted the usage of an enum value related to a vulnerable CypherMode, something that it easy to spot.</description></item><item><title>Playing with Cryptography, Part 1</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/playing-with-cryptography-part1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 09:13:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/playing-with-cryptography-part1/</guid><description>Cryptography is a fascinating subject, surely complex, but as a developer you probably have some predefined libraries in your language/environment of choice that you can use. DotNet is not an exception, so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to create a sample repository to play a little bit with all cryptography primitives to show how easy is to use them https://github.com/alkampfergit/DotNetCoreCryptography.
This is not a tutorial, it is more a repository where I played with API to gain more confidence with .</description></item><item><title>Security Onion 2020 - The hunt</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/security-onion-hunt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 10:13:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/security-onion-hunt/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve done another couple of videos about Security Onion focusing on how I can use The hunt to look for anomalies in network traffic. As for the previous video I give a disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m not a Security Onion expert, and those video are meant to keep track of my progress and to help others to familiarize with the tool.
In first video I start from an alert from Strelka and then proceed to identify possible compromised machine in the network as well as finding external malicious IPs.</description></item><item><title>Kali Linux in Hyper-V system</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/kali-linux-in-hyper-v/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/kali-linux-in-hyper-v/</guid><description>Kali Linux on Windows Most of the time a Kali Linux instance running in WSL is more than enough to have some fun in a Windows box. Using WSL is really simple but I have a couple of annoying problems that make my experience uncomfortable.
UI experience is sluggish, and annoying I have very little control over networking. Point 2 is the major pain point in my situation, I usually buy some inexpensive Intel i350 T2 cards on Ebay, to allow me to have at least three Network Card on my workstation.</description></item><item><title>Security onion in Hyper-V</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/security-onion-hyper-v/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 11:14:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/security-onion-hyper-v/</guid><description>If you want to setup a real lab to test Network Security Monitor solution, like Security Onion probably you will start with some virtual machine where to install everything. While we can agree that VmWare is probably the best solution (I have a test ESXi node) Hyper-V can be a viable solution, but you need to be aware of some glitches.
Most of the information I&amp;rsquo;ve found in internet are outdated and probably not valid for Windows Server 2019, as you can see in Figure 2.</description></item><item><title>Use multiple techniques to protect your data</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/protect-data-with-multiple-technique/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/protect-data-with-multiple-technique/</guid><description>The problem Several years ago I had a friend called me for a problem with MongoDb, it turns out that someone, from an IP geolocated in China, accessed the instances during the night and wiped out everything.
The problem was due to some misconfiguration or human error or whatever that:
turned off Windows firewall and port 27017 was open to the internet MongoDb was installed with no password. MongoDb was bound to all ip addresses of the machine When it is time to protect your data, you should add as many layers / techniques of protection as you can, this because, if one if them is failing, another one can still offer protection.</description></item><item><title>Double T shaped professional</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/double-t-shaped-professional/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 18:40:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/double-t-shaped-professional/</guid><description>The term T-Shaped Professional or T-Shaped Skills is widely used to identify a person that has a good deep knowledge in a specific area and a broad knowledge on other areas.
This kind of professional is perfect to fit into DevOps culture, because it can collaborate better with others in the team. As an example, a front-end Developer usually has the leg of his T in web technologies (angular, Typescript, HTML, etc.</description></item><item><title>Danger of public IPs</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/danger-of-public-ip/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 10:13:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/danger-of-public-ip/</guid><description>This morning I come across this article about another data exposure and I could not avoid to notice that it is another Elasticsearch exposed to the public.
894 GB of data was stored in an unsecured Elasticsearch cluster.
Due to personnel changes caused by COVID-19, we’ve not found bugs in server firewall rules immediately, which will lead to the potential risk of being hacked. And now it has been fixed.</description></item><item><title>Access your azure VM with Azure Bastion</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/azure/azure-bastion/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 10:45:18 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/azure/azure-bastion/</guid><description>There are lots of reasons to use a classic VM in Azure, even if PAAS is the preferred way to approach the cloud, IAAS is still strong especially because not every product is ready to run on cloud providers.
If you have the need to create a standard VM, both Linux or Windows, you probably want an access with SSH or RDP to configure and manage it and using a public address is probably the quickest, but less secure way, to do it.</description></item><item><title>Principle of least privilege</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/principle-of-least-privilege/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 08:13:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/principle-of-least-privilege/</guid><description>This is the fourth article in a series of post dealing on why it is important to strictly validate user input.
Do not trust user input part 1 Do not trust user input part 2 Do not trust user input part 3 Validate User Input part 4 Do not disclose errors to the User part 5 A brief recap Let&amp;rsquo;s return to the beginning, the very first version of the vulnerable function.</description></item><item><title>Do Not Disclose Errors to the User</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/do-not-disclose-error-to-the-user/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 22:13:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/do-not-disclose-error-to-the-user/</guid><description>This is the fourth article in a series of post dealing on why it is important to strictly validate user input.
Do not trust user input part 1 Do not trust user input part 2 Do not trust user input part 3 Validate User Input part 4 In the last post we analyzed how it is not fully possible to limit user input in some functions like search. The user could almost search for every character and it is not easy to impose a maximum length.</description></item><item><title>Use Kali linux in Windows Subsystem for Linux</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/kali-linux-in-wsl2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/kali-linux-in-wsl2/</guid><description>Kali Linux on Windows Thanks to the new Windows Subsystem for Linux version 2, shortly called WSL2, we have now a real Linux kernel running in a real VM as the core of WSL. This allows finally to use Kali Linux in WSL environment; if you tried in WSL you probably encountered some errors with network tools like NMap. With WSL2 everything seems to run just fine giving you a quick way to have a Kali Linux running in your Windows system while having full integration between file systems.</description></item><item><title>Play security in a secure environment</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/play-security-in-a-secure-environment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/play-security-in-a-secure-environment/</guid><description>Security is one of my long passions, I’ve spent lots of time on C++ and Assembly (both x86 and other architectures) and in that environment I&amp;rsquo;ve started exploring buffer overflow and other vulnerabilities. Over the course of years security remained only a passion and not my primary skill, but I spent constantly a little amount of time on it through the years.
When it is time to study offensive security, it is quite common to download and install test vulnerable Virtual Machines to test some offensive strategies and I’m quite surprised that most of the online tutorial simply tells you to use Virtual Box (sometimes VmWare workstation), in a very basic way and completely avoid exploring more advanced scenarios.</description></item><item><title>Validate User Input Step 4</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/validate-user-input-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 20:14:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/validate-user-input-4/</guid><description>This is the fourth article in a series of post dealing on why it is important to strictly validate user input.
Do not trust user input part 1 Do not trust user input part 2 Do not trust user input part 3 In this fourth part I will examine another problematic piece of code, obviously vulnerable to sql injection: an API to search in products.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 [SwaggerResponse(typeof(IEnumerable&amp;lt;Product&amp;gt;))] [HttpGet] [MapToApiVersion(&amp;#34;1.</description></item><item><title>Strange Error uploading artifacts in Azure DevOps pipeline</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/04/strange-error-uploading-artifacts-in-azure-devops-pipeline-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/04/strange-error-uploading-artifacts-in-azure-devops-pipeline-2/</guid><description>I have a library that is entirely written in.NET core that deal with some self signed X509 certificates used to encrypt and digitally sign some data. Software runs perfectly and is composed by a server and client part.
At a certain point we decided that the client should be used not only by software that runs.NET core, but also software with full framework , so I’ve changed target framework to target both netstandard 2.</description></item><item><title>Do not trust user input part 3</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/02/do-not-trust-user-input-part-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/02/do-not-trust-user-input-part-3/</guid><description>In part 2 we continued our journey to prevent malicious users to receive dangerous data, limiting customer id to be a 5 letters string value. We have two aspect to improve because usually I got 2 complains when I show that code.
First one: Customer object, has a composite id, serialized value is somewhat clumsy to access from client code as you can see in Figure 1. Second: if you forget to create a CustomerId from value passed from the user, you are still victim of SQL Injection.</description></item><item><title>Do not trust user input part 2</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/01/do-not-trust-user-input-part-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/01/do-not-trust-user-input-part-2/</guid><description>After we fixed our code in part 1 of this serie, we continue to expand our API adding a method to select a Customer. Northwind database Customer table has an id of type string, so we could start with this very bad, bad, bad piece of code.
Figure 1: Another bad example of API vulnerable with Sql Injection
Again the question is: what is the most critical error in that piece of code?</description></item><item><title>Do not trust user input</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/01/do-not-trust-user-input-enforce-whitelists-narrow-allowable-input/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 21:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/01/do-not-trust-user-input-enforce-whitelists-narrow-allowable-input/</guid><description>It is time to start blogging a little bit about security, because injection is still high in OWASP TOP 10 and this implies that people still trust their users. Remember, you should not trust your users, never, never, never, because for 10.000 good users there could be 1 bad user, and he/she is enough to damage your organization.
Here you have a really bad, bad, bad, bad, piece of code that is meant to allow product retrieval from northwind database Products table.</description></item><item><title>Why I love DevOps and hate DevSecOps</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/01/why-i-love-devops-and-hate-devsecops/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/01/why-i-love-devops-and-hate-devsecops/</guid><description>DevOps is becoming a buzzword, it makes hype and everyone want to be part of it, even if he/she does not know exactly what DevOps is. One of the symptoms of this is the “DevOpsEngineer”, a title that does not fit in my head. We could debate for days or years on the right definition of DevOps, but essentially is a cultural approach on building software focused on building the right thing with the maximum quality and satisfaction for the customer.</description></item><item><title>Check for Malware in a Azure DevOps Pipeline</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/12/check-for-malware-in-a-azure-devops-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/12/check-for-malware-in-a-azure-devops-pipeline/</guid><description>In a previous post I’ve showed Credential Scanner, a special task part of Microsoft Security Code Analysis available in Azure, today I want to have a quick peek at Anti Malware scanner task.
First of all a simple consideration: I’ve been asked several times if there is any need to have an AntiVirus or AntiMalware tools in build machines, after all the code that is build is developed by own developer, so there should be no need of such tools, right?</description></item><item><title>BruteForcing login with Hydra</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/11/bruteforcing-login-with-hydra/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/11/bruteforcing-login-with-hydra/</guid><description>Without any doubt, Hydra is one of the best tool to bruteforce passwords. It has support for many protocols, but it can be used with standard web sites as well forcing a standard POST based login. The syntax is a little bit different from a normal scan, like SSH and is similar to this cmdline.
./hydra -l username -P x:\temp\rockyou.txt hostname –s port http-post-form “/loginpage-address:user=^USER^&amp;amp;password=^PASS^:Invalid password!”
Dissecting the parameters you have</description></item><item><title>Security in 2019 still unprotected ElasticSearch instance exists</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/11/security-in-2019-still-unprotected-elasticsearch-instance-exists/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/11/security-in-2019-still-unprotected-elasticsearch-instance-exists/</guid><description>I’ve received today a notification from https://haveibeenpwned.com/ because one of my emails was present in a data breach.
Ok, it happens, but two things disturbed me, the first is that I really never heard of those guys (People Data Labs), this because they are one of the companies that harvest public data from online sources, aggregates them and re-sell as “Data enrichment”. This means that they probably have only public data on me.</description></item><item><title>GitHub security Alerts</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/10/github-security-alerts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/10/github-security-alerts/</guid><description>I really love everything about security and I’m really intrigued by GitHub security tab that is now present on you repository. In your project usually it is disabled by default.
Figure 1: GitHub Security tab on your repository
If you enable it you start receiving suggestion based on code that you check in on the repository , as an example, GitHub will scan your npm packages source to find dependencies with libraries that are insecure.</description></item><item><title>Exploiting VulnHub Tr0ll2 machine</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/09/exploiting-vulnhub-tr0ll2-machine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/09/exploiting-vulnhub-tr0ll2-machine/</guid><description>This is an unusual post, it deal on how I exploited Tr0ll2 machine of vulnhub. Practicing with real machine helps you to put in practice some of the stuff you learn on security. It was a real long time (almost 20 years) that I do not immerse myself in security, doing some exercise on the machine is good to spent some hours :).
I run all the machine in VMWare esxi servers, in an isolated network, behind a router and a firewall with a DNS on my kali linux machine.</description></item><item><title>Azure DevOps and SecDevOps</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/05/azure-devops-and-secdevops/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/05/azure-devops-and-secdevops/</guid><description>One of the cool aspect of Azure DevOps is the extendibility through marketplace api, and for security you can find a nice marketplace addin called Owasp ZAP (https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=kasunkodagoda.owasp-zap-scan) that can be used to automate OWASP test for web application.
You can also check this nice article in MSDN https://devblogs.microsoft.com/premier-developer/azure-devops-pipelines-leveraging-owasp-zap-in-the-release-pipeline/ that explain how you can leverage OWASP ZAP analysis during a deploy with release pipeline.
REally good stuff to read / use.</description></item><item><title>Using vmWare machine when you have Hyper-V</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/10/using-vmware-machine-when-you-have-hyper-v/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/10/using-vmware-machine-when-you-have-hyper-v/</guid><description>There are lots of VM containing Demo, Labs etc around the internet and surely Hyper-V is not the primary target as virtualization system. This because it is present on desktop OS only from Windows 8, it is not free (present in windows professional) and bound to windows. If you have to create a VM to share in internet, 99% of the time you want to target vmWare or Virtual Box and a linux guest system (no license needed).</description></item><item><title>The Dreadful IIS Loopback Check</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/09/the-dreadful-iis-loopback-check/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/09/the-dreadful-iis-loopback-check/</guid><description>This is something that from times to times bites me, both as TFS Consultant and when I’m developing code. The problem is the following: you have a site hosted with IIS in the computer you are logged in, the site has windows authentication, but you cannot login using a FQDN, but only with localhost. This is a Security Feature, because it avoid a reflection attack if the machine gets compromised. Sometimes this is annoying when you develop, because you are usually using your IIS machine to host site while you are developing, accessing it with localhost; then it is necessary to verify that everything works with real site names.</description></item><item><title>Load Security Alerts in Azure Application Insight</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/08/load-security-alert-in-azure-application-insight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/08/load-security-alert-in-azure-application-insight/</guid><description>Security is one of the big problem of the modern web, business moved to web application and security become an important part of application development. One side of the problem is adding standard and proved procedure to avoid risk of basic attacks like SQL or NO SQL injection, but big part of security was programmed at application level. If you are using SPA with some client framework like Angular and have business logic exposed with API, (Ex ASP NET Web API), you cannot trust the client, thus you need to validate every server call for authorization and authentication.</description></item><item><title>How to security expose my test TFS on the internet</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/09/how-to-security-expose-my-test-tfs-on-the-internet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/09/how-to-security-expose-my-test-tfs-on-the-internet/</guid><description>I’m not a security expert, but I have a basic knowledge on the argument, so when it is time to expose my test TFS on the outside world I took some precautions. First of all this is a test TFS instance that is running in my test network, it is not a production instance and I need to access it only sometimes when I’m outside my network.
Instead of mapping 8080 port on my firewall I’ve deployed a Linux machine, enabled SSH and added google two factor authentication, then I expose port 22 on another external port.</description></item><item><title>Using PAT to authenticate your tools</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/10/using-pat-to-authenticate-your-tools/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/10/using-pat-to-authenticate-your-tools/</guid><description>One of the strength point of VSTS / TFS is the extensibility through API , and now that we have a really nice set of REST API, it is quite normal to write little tools that interacts with your VSTS / TFS instances.
Whenever you write tools that interact with VSTS / TFS you need to decide how to authenticate to the server. While for TFS is quite simple because you can simply run the tool with Active Directory user and use AD integration, in VSTS integrating with your AD requires more work and it is not always a feasible solution.</description></item><item><title>Using certificate for SSH in Azure Linux VM</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/10/using-certificate-for-ssh-in-azure-linux-vm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/10/using-certificate-for-ssh-in-azure-linux-vm/</guid><description>If you like to use certificate to connect via SSH to your Linux machine you will probably use that technique to access all of your VMs, even those one hosted on Azure.
This operation is really simple, because Azure Portal allow you to specify the public key during VM creation and everything else is managed by VM Creation Scripts. In the same blade where you specify username and password you can opt in to use a certificate instead of a password.</description></item><item><title>How to add a user to Project Collection Service Account in TFS VSO</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/10/how-to-add-a-user-to-project-collection-service-account-in-tfs-vso/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/10/how-to-add-a-user-to-project-collection-service-account-in-tfs-vso/</guid><description>VSO and TFS have a special group called: Project Collection Service Account that has really powerful permission, and usually no user should be part of that group. There are specific circumstances, like running TFS Integration platform to move code to TFS, where the account used to access VSO needs to be part of this group to temporary have special permission.
Sadly enough, the UI does not allow you to directly add a user to that group , because the add button is disabled if you select that group.</description></item><item><title>Make easy storing secure password in TFS Build with DPAPI</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/07/make-easy-storing-secure-password-in-tfs-build-with-dpapi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/07/make-easy-storing-secure-password-in-tfs-build-with-dpapi/</guid><description>I’ve blogged some days ago on Securing the password in build definition. I want to make a disclaimer on this subject. The technique described in that article permits you to use encrypted password in a build definition, but this password cannot be decrypted only if you have no access to the build machine. If you are a malicious user and you can schedule a build, you can simply * schedule a new build that launch a custom script that decrypts the password and sends clear password by email or dump to the build output.</description></item><item><title>Is there a reason to put restriction on password</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/is-there-a-reason-to-put-restriction-on-password/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/is-there-a-reason-to-put-restriction-on-password/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve stumbled upon this funny comic
I usually use long Random generated password, that I store in KeePass for all services that I really care about, (home banking, amazon account that has my credit card, etc), and tend to use easy to remember password for services I do not care very much (stupid online games, or stuff like that).
This funny comics suggests that choosing some four random common words can be a viable solution (complex to guess, but easy to remember), but sadly enough some online services does not permits you to use long password, or password that use special chars etc.</description></item><item><title>How to check if a user belong to a certain role in ASPNet</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/10/how-to-check-if-a-user-belong-to-a-certain-role-in-asp-net/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/10/how-to-check-if-a-user-belong-to-a-certain-role-in-asp-net/</guid><description>This question is really simple to answer&amp;hellip; or no? Suppose you need to verify, in a service, if the user belongs to the xxxx group, and then take a different path of execution if the condition is true.
1 2 3 4 if (Roles.IsUserInRole(&amp;#34;xxxx&amp;#34;)) { ... } Ok, this seems such a piece of innocent code, but actually it caused me a bad bug. The reason is really simple, the same service is called from a program written in windows forms, (a windows service) and a web site.</description></item><item><title>Desiging a authentication layer with cryptoagility</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/08/desiging-a-authentication-layer-with-cryptoagility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/08/desiging-a-authentication-layer-with-cryptoagility/</guid><description>Today I was working a little bit on Dexter, and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to update the security system, the actual login system is based on a membership provider quite old, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to update it to be CryptoAgile. First of all here is the class UserDto (the name Dto should be changed because it is really a domain class but we are in the middle of a reorganization so do not mind the name ) that has some methods to manage authentication.</description></item><item><title>Wcf over https authentication with aspnet membership</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/wcf-over-https-authentication-with-asp-net-membership/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2009 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/wcf-over-https-authentication-with-asp-net-membership/</guid><description>In last article I explained how to configure WCF to secure a service with https, with no authentication, now I want to show you the configuration needed to enable role and user membership using a standard asp.net provider.
Here is the service definition on the server
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 &amp;lt;service behaviorConfiguration=&amp;#34;WsHttpWithAuthBehavior&amp;#34; name=&amp;#34;MyProject.DoSomethingService&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;endpoint address=&amp;#34;https://mydomain.it/DoSomethingService.svc&amp;#34; binding=&amp;#34;wsHttpBinding&amp;#34; name=&amp;#34;MyService&amp;#34; bindingConfiguration=&amp;#34;wsHttps&amp;#34; contract=&amp;#34;MyProject.IDoSomethingService&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;identity&amp;gt; &amp;lt;dns value=&amp;#34;mydomain.</description></item><item><title>Wcf over secure transport</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/wcf-over-secure-transport/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/wcf-over-secure-transport/</guid><description>In some older posts, I dealt with wcf configuration to manage authentication of a service with the asp.net membership provider.
Now I need to modify configuration, because in another project, all the site is forced over https, and the configuration I used in the other project cannot be used anymore. In older post in fact, I explained how to send credentials over http with message security, using self issued certificates. Now I have transport security, so I can avoid the need to distribute certificates to people that will use the service.</description></item><item><title>Generate a certificate for Wcf service with windows server 2003</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/09/generate-a-certificate-for-wcf-service-with-windows-server-2003/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/09/generate-a-certificate-for-wcf-service-with-windows-server-2003/</guid><description>In the previous post, I showed how to setup authentication with asp.net membership in wsHttpBinding for a Wcf server, and in that post I showed how to use the utility makecert.exe to generate temporary certificates. In production environment you should generate certificates with a Certification Authority.
If you search in the internet how to generate a certificate with windows server 2003 CA, you find very little information, here is how I did it.</description></item></channel></rss>