<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tools and Library on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/tools-and-library/</link><description>Recent content in Tools and Library on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 07:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/tools-and-library/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Git is fantastic but IMHO too complex to use</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/git-is-fantastic-but-imho-too-complex-to-use/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/git-is-fantastic-but-imho-too-complex-to-use/</guid><description>I’ve blogged some time ago on the basic fact that I’m not a Git lover and a couple of days ago I stumbled upon this post (10 things I hate about Git), where the author did a full explanation of various reason why he does not like Git.
If you have read in the past the excellent book by David Platt Why Software Sucks you should agree that, while Git is surely a really good, fast, powerful, complete source control system, that permits you to do marvelous stuff, it lacks simplicity.</description></item><item><title>Red-Gate Webinars</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/01/red-gate-webinar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/01/red-gate-webinar/</guid><description>If you work with Sql Server and like Red-Gate tools, you can find a couple of interesting webinars to see some features of their exceptional tools in action. If you are interested you can find all the details here; webinars are free and require only a registration, so go and take a look at what Red Gate can offer :).
Gian Maria.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting Microsoft Dynamic CRM 2011 connection with Outlook</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/07/troubleshooting-microsoft-dynamic-crm-2011-connection-with-outlook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/07/troubleshooting-microsoft-dynamic-crm-2011-connection-with-outlook/</guid><description>I should specify that I really do not know Microsoft Dynamic CRM 2011, but this morning a friend of mine called me to troubleshoot a problem with Outlook integration. The problem with Outlook connection is that it is based upon a WCF service and my friend told me that the service did not start, each time he tried to browser to the service with a browser (http://crm.mycompany.com:5555/XRMServices/2011/discovery.svc) he got an error and watching the Event Viewer he found the exception message, but he was not able to understand what was wrong.</description></item><item><title>A useful tool Microsoft Baseline security Analyzer</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/a-useful-tool-microsoft-baseline-security-analyzer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/a-useful-tool-microsoft-baseline-security-analyzer/</guid><description>MBSA is a great tool, today I&amp;rsquo;m configuring a new production server, after I configure everything I simply run it and immediately it found some issues
What I love of MBSA is that he immediately tells you how to solve the specific problem, in this situation I&amp;rsquo;ve installed a redistributable component, and mbsa tells me that he needs a critical update, and it points me immediately to the result
It permits to immediately spot security issue with production server, and it is a simple tool to use.</description></item><item><title>Manipulation of configuration files for deploy</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/manipulation-of-configuration-files-for-deploy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/manipulation-of-configuration-files-for-deploy/</guid><description>In my experience, one of the most feared problem during the going in production phase of an asp.net site or a complex project is configurations. Usually everything works perfectly on developer machines, but when you move the project in production machines all sort of problems appear.
For Asp.Net, one day one of my colleagues called me asking a little help troubleshooting some performance problem of a site in production, the problem was so big that after a couple of hours the application goes into memory overflow exception.</description></item><item><title>Reshaper 45 beta</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/03/reshaper-45-beta/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/03/reshaper-45-beta/</guid><description>Today I decided to install the beta of the new version of Resharper. I must admit that I cannot work without reshaper :D now I&amp;rsquo;m so used to it that if I work with computers with no R# I spent some second Hitting shortcut and wondering why nothing happens :D. Here is my impression
Installer is quick, it seems me quickier than older version, in about 30 seconds it uninstalled previous version and integrates in both vs2005 and vs2008.</description></item><item><title>First Steps with Unity</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/first-steps-with-unity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2009 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/first-steps-with-unity/</guid><description>I use Castle.Windsor for IoC, and sometimes I used Spring; those two are really enough to cover all IoC problems I had in the past. I do no like very much Enterprise Library but in some situation customers does not like open source code, and ask you to use only MS product, so it is worth to give a look at unity that is shipped as part of the enterprise library, but also distributed in stand alone form.</description></item><item><title>Intellisense in Sql Server 2008 missing backward compatibility</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/intellisense-in-sql-server-2008-missing-backward-compatibility/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2009 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/intellisense-in-sql-server-2008-missing-backward-compatibility/</guid><description>I Know that Sql SErver 2008 have a lot of new feature in Database Engine, but one of the most loved feature is intellisense in Management Studio. Intellisense really helps you to improve productivity when you write T-Sql code, and it is great to have it included in base version of the MS. The disappointing stuff is that it does not work when you connect to a sql server 2005 instance.</description></item><item><title>Optimize aspnet web application</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/optimize-aspnet-web-application/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 12:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/optimize-aspnet-web-application/</guid><description>The first step to optimize an application is &amp;ldquo;measure measure measure&amp;rdquo;, you cannot optimize nothing without measuring, you need some number that tells you where the application is slow and suggests you where to apply modifications, then after your optimization is done, run test suite again and measure again to check if performance are improved.
In web applications one of the most annoying stuff is a slow home page, and asp.</description></item><item><title>Speed up your visual studio</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/speed-up-your-visual-studio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/speed-up-your-visual-studio/</guid><description>After a lot of years working with visual studio I realized that to speed up building process you need faster Disks. My actual configuration consists of Three disks, two of them are 10.000 RPM Western digital, with 16 MB cache configured in RAID 1 array with a dedicated adaptec RAID card. Then I have a secondary 7.200 Disk that I use to store temporary backup, download, and file of little importance.</description></item><item><title>Resharper and switch to a different solution</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/resharper-and-switch-to-a-different-solution/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/resharper-and-switch-to-a-different-solution/</guid><description>When I close a solution from visual studio quite often resharper does not release memory
To show this information you can simply go to Resharper-&amp;gt;options and in the General section under System check the &amp;ldquo;show managed memory usage in status bar&amp;rdquo;
As you can see I store caches in TEMP folder, this because I have two disks, so I prefer to keep caches in a disk different from the one used to store source code, in this way overall disk usage is better.</description></item><item><title>Performance of logging system</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/11/performance-of-logging-system/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/11/performance-of-logging-system/</guid><description>When you insert a logging system into your application you should do some preliminary test for performance issue. The most important thing is that logging infrastructure should not introduce too much overhead when the log is disabled. With log4net you have different way to handle the log, suppose you have a logger and the DEBUG level is disabled; you can use one of these three form
1 2 3 4 5 log1.</description></item><item><title>View the current exception in Visual Studio</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/view-the-current-exception-in-visual-studio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2008 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/view-the-current-exception-in-visual-studio/</guid><description>Sometimes you write pieces of code like this.
1 2 3 catch { LogException(.... This type of exception handler catch everything and log, despite the fact that is not so good practice to catch every exception that a piece of code could raise, one of the most frustrating thing is that if you place a breakpoint in the LogException line, since you have not specified in the catch clause no exception you have no way to see detail of the exception.</description></item><item><title>Resharper and plugins</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/resharper-and-plugin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/resharper-and-plugin/</guid><description>Version 4.0 of resharper offers the ability to create plugins. This is very important, because you can use the basic structure of resharper to offer additional features. One of the most interesting, in my opinion, is the NHibernate plugin, I suggest you to have a try of it, another good reason to use resharper ;).
alk.</description></item><item><title>Resharper 40 goes in RC almost finished</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/resharper-40-goes-in-rc-almost-finished/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/resharper-40-goes-in-rc-almost-finished/</guid><description>I must admit that resharper is really the most useful plugin for visual studio I use, I’m testing the nightly build but the Release Candidate is now avaliable, and this means that in a short time we can have final version, Stay tuned.
Alk.
Tags: Resharper</description></item><item><title>Argotic Rss Library for NET</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/argotic-rss-library-for-net/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/argotic-rss-library-for-net/</guid><description>I need to work with rss, so I wandered a little bit in the net and found Argotic library. At the first glance the library is really good, but a simple thing appears to be missing (or probably I did not find in the documentation)
I need to examine a large set of feed to grab all the link, but I do not know if the feed is rss or atom or whathever else, I decided to support atom and Rss, and I created this little piece of code that use GenericSyndicationFeed to load the feed from the uri, then check the format and create the correct feed component.</description></item><item><title>The heartbeat of a project</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/the-heartbeat-of-a-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2008 01:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/the-heartbeat-of-a-project/</guid><description>Continuous Integration is one of the most important part of a project, it gives the heartbeat of the code, when it is green the beat is ok, when it is red something wrong is occurred.
Setting up a good CI environment can be really challenging, but setting up a primitive CC.net is a relative simple task. I realized that even with basic functions, a CI can give you a valuable asset.</description></item><item><title>RSS toolkit for aspnet</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/05/rss-toolkit-for-aspnet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2007 01:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/05/rss-toolkit-for-aspnet/</guid><description>If you needs to manage some RSS content in your asp.net application maybeRSS Toolkit is the answer to all of your problems. In this post of Scott Guthrie there is also a good tutorial on the toolkit, it is worth to take a look.
Alk.</description></item></channel></rss>