<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Architecture Castle on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/architecture-castle/</link><description>Recent content in Architecture Castle on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2010 11:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/architecture-castle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cache layer</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/cache-layer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2010 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/cache-layer/</guid><description>Thanks to AOP concept, creating a cache layer that is transparent to the caller is not a big deal. I have a piece of code that in a loop calls this method
1 2 3 ClientCompetitor competitor = Repository.ClientCompetitor.GetByCriteria( Query.CreateEq(&amp;#34;AssociatedClient&amp;#34;, clieid)) .SingleOrDefault(); This is based on a standard implementation of repository and a Specification Pattern as a query model. With nhibernate profiler I see that during the execution of this task, a lot of identical query are issued, because it gets called around 1000 times always with the same clieid.</description></item><item><title>Value of architecture</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/value-of-architecture/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/value-of-architecture/</guid><description>If I have to tell what is the main property of a good architecture, I surely will answer that a good architecture centralize common operations and make simple to extend the application.
Here is a typical example. I have a WCF services called from external clients, but I use the same service inside my organization. I created a little WPF project that needs to use services functions, but since this program is run internally, I do not want it to pass in the WCF stack, but I simply want to use concrete services classes that access the database.</description></item></channel></rss>