<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Visual Studio ALM on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/visual-studio-alm/</link><description>Recent content in Visual Studio ALM on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 20:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/visual-studio-alm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Azure DevOps agent with Docker Compose</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/12/azure-devops-agent-with-docker-compose/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/12/azure-devops-agent-with-docker-compose/</guid><description>I’ve dealt in the past on using Docker for your Azure DevOps Linux Build Agent in a post called Configure a VSTS Linux agent with docker in minutes and also I’ve blogged on how you can use Docker inside a build definition to have some prerequisite for testing (like MongoDb and Sql Server), now it is time to move a little step further and leverage Docker compose.
Using Docker commands in pipeline definition is nice, but has some drawbacks: First of all this approach suffers in speed of execution, because the container must start each time you run a build (and should be stopped at the end of the build).</description></item><item><title>Analyze your GitHub project for free with Azure DevOps and SonarCloud</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/11/analyze-your-github-project-for-free-with-azure-devops-and-sonarcloud/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/11/analyze-your-github-project-for-free-with-azure-devops-and-sonarcloud/</guid><description>I’ve blogged some weeks ago on how to analyze OS code with SonarCloud, but it is time to update the post, because if you want to use SonarCloud you have a dedicated extension in the marketplace.
Figure 1: Official SonarCloud extension in the marketplace.
One of the great feature of Azure DevOps is its extendibility, that allows people external to Microsoft to create extensions to expand the possibility of the tool.</description></item><item><title>Welcome Azure DevOps</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/09/welcome-azure-devops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/09/welcome-azure-devops/</guid><description>Yesterday Microsoft announced a change in naming for VSTS, now branded as Azure DevOps. You can read most of the details in this blog post and if you are using VSTS right now you will not have a big impact in the future. Event is this is just a rebranding of the service, there are a couple of suggestion I’d like to give you to have a smoother transition.
Visual Studio Team Services was rebranded in Azure DevOps, this will not impact your existing VSTS projects, but it is wise to start planning for a smooth transition.</description></item><item><title>TFS 2018 is out time to upgrade</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/11/tfs-2018-is-out-time-to-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/11/tfs-2018-is-out-time-to-upgrade/</guid><description>Some days are passed, but it is good to remind you that TFS 2018 is finally out. Some people are surprised because after TFS 2015 we had TFS 2017 and we are still in 2017 and we already have version 2018, but this is the good part of the ALM tools in Microsoft, they are really shipping tons of new goodness each year :).
Release note page contains all the details about the new version, from that link you have a small 13 minute video that explain what is new in this version and as usual in the page you have a detailed list of all the news with detailed information about each of the new features.</description></item><item><title>Configure a VSTS Linux agent with docker in minutes</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/10/configure-a-vsts-linux-agent-with-docker-in-minutes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/10/configure-a-vsts-linux-agent-with-docker-in-minutes/</guid><description>It is really simple to create a build agent for VSTS that runs in Linux and is capable of building and packaging your DotNetCore project, I’ve explained everything in a previous post, but I want to remind you that, with docker, the whole process is really simple.
Anyone knows that setting up a build machine often takes time. VSTS makes it super simple to install the Agent , just download a zip, call a script to configure the agent and the game is done.</description></item><item><title>Pause build and clear long build queue</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/10/pause-build-and-clear-long-build-queue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/10/pause-build-and-clear-long-build-queue/</guid><description>In VSTS / TFS Build system, you can change the status of the build, between three states: Enabled, Paused and Disabled. The Paused state is really special, because all the build trigger are still active and builds are queued, but all these queued build does not starts.
Figure 1: Paused build
Paused state should be used with great care, because if you forget a build in this state, you can end up with lots of queued build, as you can see in Figure 2: Figure 2: Really high number of build queued, because the build definition is paused.</description></item><item><title>Running UAT and integration tests during a VSTS Build</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/08/running-uat-and-integration-tests-during-a-vsts-build/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/08/running-uat-and-integration-tests-during-a-vsts-build/</guid><description>There are a lots of small suggestions I’ve learned from experience when it is time to create a suite of integration / UAT test for your project. A UAT or integration test is a test that exercise the entire application, sometimes composed by several services that are collaborating to create the final result. The difference from UAT tests and Integration test, in my personal terminology, is that the UAT uses direct automation of User Interface, while an integration tests can skip the UI and exercise the system directly from public API (REST, MSMQ Commands, etc).</description></item><item><title>Dump all environment variables during a TFS VSTS Build</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/08/dump-all-environment-variables-during-a-tfs-vsts-build/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/08/dump-all-environment-variables-during-a-tfs-vsts-build/</guid><description>Environment variables are really important during a build, especially because all Build variables are stored as environment variables, and this imply that most of the build context is stored inside them. One of the feature I miss most, is the ability to easily visualize on the result of the build a nice list of all the values of Environment variables. We need also to be aware of the fact that tasks can change environment variables during the build, so we need to be able to decide the exact point of the build where we want variables to be dumped.</description></item><item><title>Writing a VSTS TFS task that uses 7zip</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/07/writing-a-vsts-tfs-task-that-uses-7zip/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/07/writing-a-vsts-tfs-task-that-uses-7zip/</guid><description>Writing a Build / Release task for VSTS / TFS is really simple, but when you need third party software you need to be aware of license issue. As an example I have a small task that uses 7zip under the hood to compress / extract with the fantastic 7zip format. 7zip is good because, even if it uses more processing power to compress files, the result is often really smaller than a standard zip, and this is especially good for build agent that are behind a standard ADSL (300 Kbs upload speed).</description></item><item><title>Microsoft support for non Windows developers</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/05/microsoft-support-for-non-windows-developers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/05/microsoft-support-for-non-windows-developers/</guid><description>During Build 2015 conference Microsoft announced** ** Visual Studio Code ** , a free IDE to develop web, cloud and modern application **. The nice aspect of VS Code is that it runs on every platform, here is a screenshot of Code running on a Linux Ubuntu box.
** Figure 1: **Visual Studio Code running on Linux box
I can now clone a git repository from my Visual Studio Online account and create a first Hello Node Js application.</description></item><item><title>Team Project Rename</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/04/team-project-rename/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/04/team-project-rename/</guid><description>Renaming of Team Projects is one of the most requested feature on Visual Studio User Voice:
Figure 1: Team Project rename suggestion on User Voice
Today, Brian Harry announced new Visual Studio Online Update and it contains this feature, even if it will not be available to everyone at the beginning. For those people that uses TFS on-premise you will have this feature in the upcoming new version: TFS 2015.</description></item><item><title>Professional Application Lifecycle Management With Visual Studio 2013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/05/professional-application-lifecycle-management-with-visual-studio-2013/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2014 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/05/professional-application-lifecycle-management-with-visual-studio-2013/</guid><description>If you use or plan to use Team Foundation Server or Visual Studio Online, this is the book for you.
Professional Application Lifecycle Management with Visual Studio 2013 covers all aspects and tools of Microsoft ALM Ecosystem , giving you all the details on how to implement effectively ALM for your team/s. This book is dedicated to all people involved in a Software Project, from managers who plan work with new Portfolio Management features, to developers that create the product, and finally to testers and end users that could monitor quality with Microsoft Test Manager and Feedback Tool.</description></item><item><title>Keep your Team Foundation Server upgraded to latest version</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/05/keep-your-team-foundation-server-upgraded-to-latest-version/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/05/keep-your-team-foundation-server-upgraded-to-latest-version/</guid><description>When it is time to maintain Team Foundation Server in small companies the major risk is “fear of upgrade”. In a small shops usually there is no dedicated resource to maintain TFS installation , usually you install the first time, schedule backup and everything is done. In small company maintenance is also simple, you usually have not big database and speed is not a problem with current hardware.
Some people also fear the upgrade, because they think it is a complicated process, they are not sure if they are able to restore the old version if the upgrade went wrong, and so on.</description></item><item><title>Programmatically use of Coded UI in Visual Studio</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/04/programmatically-use-of-coded-ui-in-visual-studio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/04/programmatically-use-of-coded-ui-in-visual-studio/</guid><description>Coded UI Tests are a specific type of UI testing introduced with Visual Studio 2010. You can create your first Coded UI test following simple instruction from MSDN documentation. Most of the introductory examples shows you how you can use the Recorder tools to record interaction with a software (Web, WinForm, Wpf. etc) to generate what is called a UiMap. An UiMap is nothing more than a big Xml files where the recorder records the interaction with the UI and a bunch of automatic generated classes to interact with the UI.</description></item><item><title>Versioning assembly during TFS 2013 build with Powershell Scripts</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/01/customize-tfs-2013-build-with-powershell-scripts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/01/customize-tfs-2013-build-with-powershell-scripts/</guid><description>One of the most important news in TFS Build 2010 is the introduction of Workflow Foundation that replaced standard MSBuild scripts used in TFS 2008. Workflow foundation can be really powerful, but indeed it is somewhat scaring and quite often customizing a build can be complex.
You can find some blog post of mine on the subject:
Writing a Custom Activity for TFS 2010 Builds Run Test With TypeMock isolator in TFS 2010 Build Wrap a MsBuild Custom task inside a custom Action Years are passed, but I still see people scared when it is time to customize the build , especially because the Workflow can be a little bit intimidating.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio Online Announcement</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/11/visual-studio-online-announcement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/11/visual-studio-online-announcement/</guid><description>During the official Launch of Visual Studio 2013 a lots of news were announced, but one of the most interesting is Visual Studio Online (Previously Known as TF Service). This is not only a simple rebrand of a product, the change of name indicates also that the service is not only a TFS hosted on Azure but it contains lots more functionality. You can find some quick introductory videos in Channel9.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links week 25</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-25/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-25/</guid><description>Tracking project costs and Budgets with Microsoft TFS XCentium Enhancement What’s new And exciting in.NET 4.5 and Visual Studio 2012 (RangerTalk) Writing.NET in PowerShell and creating TFS Teams Extending Visual Studio Team Explorer 2012 + MyHistory Extension P.S. This will be probably the last of my “Visual Studio ALM Links week xxx” series, because I usually use other channels to share links about Visual Studio ALM news and maintaining such a list is quite a duplication.</description></item><item><title>Associate Work Items to Git commit in TF Service with API Calls</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/associate-work-items-to-git-commit-in-tf-service-with-api-calls/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/associate-work-items-to-git-commit-in-tf-service-with-api-calls/</guid><description>I’ve already blogged how to associate Work Items with TFS Check-ins using tags in comment and a bunch of Api Calls. This feature is now available for any TF Service based on Git, but someone asked me how can you accomplish this task with API. A possible scenario would be supporting different type of comment syntax and in general to understand how this task can be accomplished though API.
The code is really similar to the one I’ve posted in the other article, the only differences is comments are taken from Git commit and not from changeset checkins.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links Week 24</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-24-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-24-2/</guid><description> Using TFS Kanban Column State in the warehouse TFS API – May 2013 Release Visual Studio 2012 Extension – List of software installed on TFS Service build Servers Microsoft Test Manager: Customization of test result fields an marking test results as N/A Testing improvements in Team foundation Service Update for Tech Ed 2013</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links Week 24</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-24/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-24/</guid><description>Visual Studio 2013 and TFS 2013 announced It is possible to run Coded UI Tests in a virtual machine instead that in my primary machine Test Scribe for Visual Studio 2012 Update 2 Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links Week 23</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-23/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-23/</guid><description>NEtAdvantage for LightSwitch 2012 Vol.2 Light (Free) now supports Visual Studio 2012 A Bug in TFS 2012 alerts System (Fixed in Update 3) Team Foundation Service Updates for TechEd 2013 Visual Studio 2013 Visual Studio Collaboration, Anywhere Introducing cloud-based Load Testing with Team Foundation Service Visual Studio 2013, ALM, and DevOps MSDN blogs detail Application Lifecycle workflow feature updates Enriched ALM In Visual Studio 2013 and Team Foundation Server 2013 Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>News for VS 2013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/news-for-vs-2013/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/news-for-vs-2013/</guid><description>With the new release cadence, Brian Harry announced at TechEd a lot of news on the upcoming version of Visual Studio and you can read everything directly on Brian Harry’s post Visual Studio 2013. The cool part is that some of these new features are already available on TF Service and we can start using right now.
You can read about those new features directly from the TF Service News blog, on Team Foundation Service Updates for Tech Ed 2013, and clearly you can start using immediately.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links Week 22</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-22/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-22/</guid><description>Hacking getKanban Version 2 Visual Studio 2012 Supported in Devart’s dbForge Fusion for MySQL 6.0 Restore TFS Backups from Sql Server Enterprise to sql Express Better Multi-User Support for Work Item Tracking in TFS 2012 Using TFS Kanban Column State to the warehouse Team Foundation Service Updates 5/28 – Team Foundation Service Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links Week 21</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/visual-studio-alm-links-week-21/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/visual-studio-alm-links-week-21/</guid><description>Visual Studio ALM Ranger Solutions Catalog TFS as perfect tool for Scrum – Sprint planning (Part 3) Enable Feedback support for users in Team Foundation Server 2012 ALM Readiness Treasure Map Continuous Deployment on Windows Azure with Database Projects Enable Seamless Integration with Team Foundation server Microsoft Test Professional and HP ALM With Opshub 5.3 What has Changed in the home of the ALM Rangers during FY13 Support on Team Foundation Service Team Foundation Task Board Enhancer: Version.</description></item><item><title>Continuous Deployment on Windows Azure with Database projects</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/continuous-deployment-on-windows-azure-with-database-projects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/continuous-deployment-on-windows-azure-with-database-projects/</guid><description>I’ve already blogged about Deploying on Azure Web Site with Database Project in the past, but in that article I showed how to accomplish it with customization of the Build Template. That technique is useful because quite often you need to run custom scripts or tools to do additional deploy related procedures to the site , but if your need is simply deploying schema change to an Azure Database with a Database Project you can accomplish it even without the need to touch the Build Workflow.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links Week 20</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/visual-studio-alm-links-week-20/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/visual-studio-alm-links-week-20/</guid><description>Microsoft TFS Goes Mobile With Perfecto MobileCloud Configure Test Plans for Web Access in TFS 2012.2 Getting Started with LibGit2Sharp Team Foundation Service Update – May 13 Agilethought ALM Experts Present Free Visual STudio Webinars Known Issue and Workaround for TFS 2012 Update 3 RC1 Quality Enablement with Visual Studio 2012 Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links Week 19</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/visual-studio-alm-links-week-19/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/visual-studio-alm-links-week-19/</guid><description>Better Multi User Support for Work Item Tracking in TFS 2012 Naked ALM: starting with why and getting naked Help Content for the Agile Planning Tools gets a makeover with TFS CU2 Visual Studio Update 2012.3 Update 3 “go-Live” CTP is now available Finding Event Subscriptions in TFS 2012 using Power Shell Testing Java and Cross Platform applications with Squish and Microsoft Test Professional Embracing SCRUM and CMMI in TFS 2012 Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links-Week 18 2013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/visual-studio-alm-linksweek-18-2013/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/visual-studio-alm-linksweek-18-2013/</guid><description>You are doing it wrong if you are not using test first Upgrading your process template from MSF For Agile 4 to Visual Studio Scrum 2.x Use code Maps to understand code relationship Team Explorer Everywhere 2012 Update 2 Connect to TFS 2012 from VS 2005 even from Windows XP Quality Enablement with Microsoft Visual Studio 2012 Deploy Visual Studio 2012 Update 2 through SCCM Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links - Week 17 2013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/04/visual-studio-alm-links-week-17-2013/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/04/visual-studio-alm-links-week-17-2013/</guid><description>New Un-Versioned repository in TFS 2012 ALM Rangers dogfooding journal of the Team Foundation Service Administering Visual Studio TFS 2012: Exam (70-496) Channel 9. Free Microsoft Exam jump start for: Delivering Continuous Value with Visual Studio 2012 ALM Study Guide – Administering Visual Studio Team Foundation Server 2012 Release Management with Team Foundation Server 2012 Sprint 45 Service issues MsBuild Extension Pack – April 2013 Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM links-Week 16 2013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/04/visual-studio-alm-linksweek-16-2013/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/04/visual-studio-alm-linksweek-16-2013/</guid><description>List of all Visual Studio ALM Virtual machines Adventures in Software Engineering Broken Shared steps link after Migration from TFS Integration Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links-Week 152013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/04/visual-studio-alm-linksweek-152013/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/04/visual-studio-alm-linksweek-152013/</guid><description>TFS Service – Configure Source and Symbol Server Settings Visual Studio Update 2 RTM Quarterly Visual Studio 2012 updates are awesome Configuring your build server after upgrading to TFS 2012 Update2 TFS 2012 Update 2: Version control Changes Gian Maria.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links-Week 142013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/04/visual-studio-alm-linksweek-142013/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/04/visual-studio-alm-linksweek-142013/</guid><description>Visual Studio Premium and Ultimate 2012: New testing tools for manual testers TFS Admin Reports delivered to your inbox Daily Team Foundation Task Board Enhancer: version 2.6.2 released TFS Branch Tool goes “community”. Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>How to configure diff and Merge tool in Visual Studio Git Tools</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/03/how-to-configure-diff-and-merge-tool-in-visual-studio-git-tools/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/03/how-to-configure-diff-and-merge-tool-in-visual-studio-git-tools/</guid><description>If you are using Visual Studio plugin for Git, but you have also configured Git with MSys git, probably you could be surprised by some Visual Studio behavior. The most obvious one is that commits are done using the wrong user.name and user.email configuration as I’ve described in Visual Studio Tools for Git, a primer, other one can be: tools used to do merge and diff during conflicts.
Suppose you are working with Visual Studio, you issue a pull and find that there is some conflicts in repository.</description></item><item><title>Continuous integration in Team Foundation Service for Git based Team Project</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/02/continuous-integration-in-team-foundation-service-for-git-based-team-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/02/continuous-integration-in-team-foundation-service-for-git-based-team-project/</guid><description>Some weeks are passed from the announcement of TF Service support to Git based Team Projects, and Git is becoming first class citizen in the Team Foundation Server environment. Last week the latest update to TF Service introduced the ability to create build for Git Based Repository.
If you compare to a standard build (based on standard TFS Source control), Git based build is slightly different, the most important one is that a single build can be used to build multiple branches.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links week 492012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/12/visual-studio-alm-links-week-492012/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/12/visual-studio-alm-links-week-492012/</guid><description>Meet the author: Ben Day on ALM with TFS 2012 fundamentals Batched Gated Check-ins Replacing the Team Foundation Server Cube with a Tabular Model Understanding The TFS Tabular Model Alk.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM links 392012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/visual-studio-alm-link-392012/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/visual-studio-alm-link-392012/</guid><description>Tfs 2012 Power Tools Are now available Team Foundation Task Board Enhancer: More features Team Foundation Service Updates 9/17 Virtual Labs in the modern application lifecycle Configuring TFS so your task are estimated in story points Testing in the modern application lifecycle Gian Maria.</description></item><item><title>Visual studio ALM links week 332012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/visual-studio-alm-links-week-332012/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/visual-studio-alm-links-week-332012/</guid><description>ALM Rangers Build Cusotmization Guide V2 has shipped Team foundation Service Updates 8/13 Compatibility between Team foundation Clients and Team Foundation Server Announcing Git Integration with TFS Team foundation Server 2012 and Project Server 2010 Integration Showing files with pending changes or files that are open in Visual Studio 2012 Solution Explorer Visual Studio 2012 and MSDN Licensing White Paper Alk.</description></item></channel></rss>