<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NET Core on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/net-core/</link><description>Recent content in NET Core on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 09:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/net-core/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NET core configuration array with Bind</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/03/net-core-configuration-array-with-bind/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/03/net-core-configuration-array-with-bind/</guid><description>New configuration system of.NET core is really nice, but it does not works very well with arrays, I have a configuration object that has an array of FirewallRules 1 public FirewallRule[] Rules { get; set; } This rule is simply composed by four simple properties.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 public class FirewallRule { internal FirewallRule() { } public FirewallRule(string name, int udpPort, int tcpPort, string secret) { Name = name; UdpPort = udpPort; TcpPort = tcpPort; Secret = secret; } public String Name { get; set; } public Int32 UdpPort { get; set; } public Int32 TcpPort { get; set; } public String Secret { get; set; } } Ok, nothing complex, now I’m expecting to being able to write this json configuration file to configure a single rule.</description></item><item><title>Error when NET461 full framework references NETStandard nuget packages</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/07/error-when-net461-full-framework-references-netstandard-nuget-packages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/07/error-when-net461-full-framework-references-netstandard-nuget-packages/</guid><description>After updating MongoDb driver in a C# big project I start having a problem in a Web Project where we have this error after a deploy in test server (but we have no error in local machine of developers) &amp;gt; An assembly with the same identity ‘System.Runtime, Version=4.1.2.0, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=b03f5f7f11d50a3a’ has already been imported. Try removing one of the duplicate references.
This happens because MongoDB driver &amp;gt; 2.8 reference in the chain System.</description></item><item><title>Error with dotnet restore corrupted header</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/08/error-with-dotnet-restore-corrupted-header/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/08/error-with-dotnet-restore-corrupted-header/</guid><description>I’m trying to compile with dotnetcore 2.0 a project on Linux, but I got this strange error when I run the dotnet restore command.
Figure 1: Error restoring packages
The exact error comes from NuGet.targets and tells me: a local file header is corrupt and points to my solution file. Clearly this project builds just fine on another computer.
Since I’m experiencing intermittent connection, I suspect that nuget cache can be somewhat corrupted, so I run this command to clear all caches.</description></item><item><title>NET core 20 errors installing on linux</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/08/net-core-2-0-errors-installing-on-linux/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/08/net-core-2-0-errors-installing-on-linux/</guid><description>.NET Core 2.0 is finally out, and I immediately try to install it on every machine and especially in my linux test machines. In one of my Ubuntu machine I got an installation problem, a generic error of apt-get and I was a little bit puzzled on why the installation fail.
Since in windows the most common cause of.NET Core installation error is the presence of an old package (especially the preview version), I decide to uninstall all previous installation of.</description></item></channel></rss>