<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tfs Power Tools on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/tfs-power-tools/</link><description>Recent content in Tfs Power Tools on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 11:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/tfs-power-tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Power Tools Shell Extension with VS2008</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/using-power-tools-shell-extension-with-vs2008/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/using-power-tools-shell-extension-with-vs2008/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a great fan of TFS power tools, and working as a consultant it is normal for me to use TFS2010 as well TFS2008 servers, because some of my customers still uses TFS2008. In my laptop I&amp;rsquo;ve installed VS2008, team explorer and the latest power tools (August 2011), then I mapped a workspace from VS2008, but when I right click on mapped folder, no Team Foundation Server menu appears in contextual menu.</description></item><item><title>Use credential manager to use TFS shell extension in a workgroup or outside a domain</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/03/use-credential-manager-to-use-tfs-shell-extension-in-a-workgroup-or-outside-a-domain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/03/use-credential-manager-to-use-tfs-shell-extension-in-a-workgroup-or-outside-a-domain/</guid><description>Yesterday I&amp;rsquo;ve blogged about TFS Power tools Shell Extension, and today my friend Michele told me that he has a problem, the extension always told him to Reconnect to server and he is not able to use them.
This is probably due to an authentication request, so you can try to open Team Explorer, and if it asks for credential on connecting to TFS this is the reason. Shell extension are not able to ask for different user, so if you are outside the TFS domain or if you are in workgroup the only solution is going to Control Panel and fire the Credential Manager.</description></item></channel></rss>