<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Debugging on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/debugging/</link><description>Recent content in Debugging on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 09:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/debugging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unable to debug dll source code with symbol server</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/06/unable-to-debug-dll-source-code-with-symbol-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/06/unable-to-debug-dll-source-code-with-symbol-server/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve blogged in the past about using a &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2013/07/04/manage-symbol-server-on-azure-or-on-premise-vm-and-tf-service/">Symbol server&lt;/a> and I &lt;strong>recommend to all people to use symbol servers whenever possible&lt;/strong> , to helping people troubleshooting problem on dependencies. Basically with a symbol server you can reference a dll in your project, but you can debug original source code as if you have the original project linked instead of having the dll.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes this process just don’t work. Recently I’have a customer that had problem with this scenario, and the real strange stuff is: I’m able to step in dll source code without problem from any machine, but noone of the customer’s developers are able to make it work. After I’ve sent them detailed instruction it worked, and we were able to track down the problem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Troubleshoot remote debugging of Managed Code</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/troubleshoot-remote-debugging-of-managed-code/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/troubleshoot-remote-debugging-of-managed-code/</guid><description>&lt;p>Setting up Remote Debugging is usually a simple task, you can read the &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bt727f1t.aspx">Set Up Remote Debugging&lt;/a> guide on MSDN and you are ready to go, but sometimes it does not work and you are not able to connect to the remote process; in this post I want to give you some suggestions to troubleshoot the most common problem that you can encounter.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>First:&lt;/strong> &lt;em>you need to be aware that &lt;strong>Remote Debugging Managed Code&lt;/strong> is only available when you use the authenticated mode, if you run the remote debugger without authentication you can &lt;strong>debug only Native Code&lt;/strong> , but the main problem is that usually &lt;em>the host and remote machine&lt;/em> * &lt;strong>are not&lt;/strong> in the same Domain&lt;/em>. To bypass this situation you need to create what is called “Shadow Account”, this means that you need to have in * &lt;strong>both machines the same user with the same password.&lt;/strong> *&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/image26.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/image_thumb26.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/image_thumb26.png" alt="How to setup authentication if you do not have a domain" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>