<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VSO on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/vso/</link><description>Recent content in VSO on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 16:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/vso/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Build vNext and continuous integration on GitHub</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/06/build-vnext-and-continuous-integration-on-github/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/06/build-vnext-and-continuous-integration-on-github/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the great &lt;strong>news of build vNext is the ability to create a build that targets source on GitHub project&lt;/strong> , not only on Git or TFVC repositories that are in current TFS or VSO instance. Given this, plus the fact that VSO has a 5 basic user license for Free, and you can use VSO as Continuous integration Engine for your GitHub projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To create a build that targets GitHub source code, you should simply login into your GitHub account, then navigate in your personal settings and finally choose “Personal Access tokens”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>VSO vNext build error You cannot run the vsoAgentexe interactively</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/05/vso-vnext-build-error-you-cannot-run-the-vsoagent-exe-interactively/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/05/vso-vnext-build-error-you-cannot-run-the-vsoagent-exe-interactively/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Error Symptom&lt;/strong> *: &lt;em>You installed and configured an Agent for the new Visual Studio Online Build System, and you decided not to run as a service, but interactively. When you double click the VsoAgent.exe executable you got this error.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You cannot run the vsoAgent.exe interactively from within the Agent folder. Try running it from the parent folder&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I’ve encountered this error on my main workstation machine, and I’m not sure why I got this error. Actually I’ve configured agent for TFS 2015 RC without this problem and &lt;strong>in the same machine I got three distinct agents, but only the one targeting my VSO primary account is having this problem&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Microsoft support for non Windows developers</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/05/microsoft-support-for-non-windows-developers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/05/microsoft-support-for-non-windows-developers/</guid><description>&lt;p>During Build 2015 conference Microsoft announced** &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/">** Visual Studio Code **&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> , a free IDE to develop web, cloud and modern application **. The nice aspect of VS Code is that it runs on every platform, here is a screenshot of Code running on a Linux Ubuntu box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/image4.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/image_thumb4.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/image_thumb4.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>** Figure 1: **&lt;em>Visual Studio Code running on Linux box&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can now clone a git repository from my Visual Studio Online account and create a first Hello Node Js application. VS Code is not just an editor, and I’m able to debug my node.js code with easy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rename Team Project in VSO</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/04/rename-team-project-in-vso/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/04/rename-team-project-in-vso/</guid><description>&lt;p>With yesterday update, one of the most requested feature for TFS/VSO was finally active, &lt;strong>you can now rename a Team Project.&lt;/strong> It can be done directly from collection administration page, in the same place where you can delete a Team Project&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/image6.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/image_thumb6.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/image_thumb6.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once selected you should only provide a new name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/image7.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/image_thumb7.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/image_thumb7.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now you will be warned with a long warning message that tells you exactly what kind of intervention you need to do after the rename.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some love to Kanban Board in Visual Studio online</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/04/some-love-to-kanban-board-in-visual-studio-online/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/04/some-love-to-kanban-board-in-visual-studio-online/</guid><description>&lt;p>In some of recent updates on Visual Studio Online the team &lt;strong>put some love into the Kanban Board&lt;/strong>. In January they enable &lt;a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/news/2015-jan-27-vso">editing tiles on the Board&lt;/a>. In february we can &lt;a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/news/2015-feb-18-vso">Adding and editing&lt;/a> some fields directly from the Board, as well as the ability to split column.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/image1.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/image_thumb1.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/image_thumb1.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Figure 1&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>: &lt;em>Split columns in Kanban Board.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I must admit that split column is a must and I’m very happy to have it now on my VSO account. In March the ability to reorder card on the board was introduced, as well as the possibility to &lt;a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/news/2015-mar-10-vso">specify Definition of Done&lt;/a> for each column. Finally, with April deployment, &lt;strong>we have now the ability to customize cards, as well as Markdown on Definition of Done&lt;/strong> , plus the ability to configure the Cumulative Flow Diagram.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Team Project Rename</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/04/team-project-rename/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/04/team-project-rename/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Renaming of Team Projects is one of the most requested feature&lt;/strong> on Visual Studio User Voice:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/image.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/image_thumb.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/image_thumb.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Figure 1&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>: &lt;em>Team Project rename suggestion on User Voice&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, Brian Harry announced &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/bharry/archive/2015/04/13/vs-online-update-april-10th.aspx">new Visual Studio Online Update&lt;/a> and it contains this feature, even if it will not be available to everyone at the beginning. &lt;strong>For those people that uses TFS on-premise you will have this feature in the upcoming new version: TFS 2015&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Linking VSO with third party tools</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/10/linking-vso-with-third-party-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/10/linking-vso-with-third-party-tools/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most interesting news of VSO in last months &lt;strong>are&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="http://www.visualstudio.com/integrating-with-service-hooks-vs">&lt;strong>service hooks&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> &lt;strong>and REST API to integrate VSO with&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="http://www.visualstudio.com/integrating-with-service-hooks-vs">&lt;strong>third party tools&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>. This capability is a key for success because ALM is really a complicated subject and rarely you can manage all of your applications with a single tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>VSO and TFS are no exception to this rule, they are more a set of suites and tools glued together under a single brand. TFS is composed by a Work Item Store plus Two options for source control (TFVC/Git) plus a Continuous Integration service (Build service) and a Release Management Tool for release, it integrates with SCOM to keep Ops and Devs in contact, plus much more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to connect existing VSO Account to new azure portal</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/07/how-to-connect-existing-vso-account-to-new-azure-portal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/07/how-to-connect-existing-vso-account-to-new-azure-portal/</guid><description>&lt;p>With the &lt;a href="http://www.visualstudio.com/news/2014-jul-21-vso">new deploy of Visual Studio Online&lt;/a> you can link your existing VSO accounts to your azure subscription so they will be available on new Azure portal &lt;a href="http://portal.azure.com">http://portal.azure.com&lt;/a>. You just need to &lt;strong>connect to standard management portal (&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="http://manage.windowsazure.com">&lt;strong>http://manage.windowsazure.com&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> &lt;strong>) and then add an existing VSO account to the list of available ones&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/image21.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/image_thumb21.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/image_thumb21.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Figure 1&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>: &lt;em>Use the New button in azure portal to add existing VSO account to new azure portal.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to subscribe to event in Visual Studio Online</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/05/how-to-subscribe-to-event-in-visual-studio-online/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/05/how-to-subscribe-to-event-in-visual-studio-online/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve dealt with BisSubscribe.exe in the past when I described how to do &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2010/08/10/moving-to-a-deploy-system-based-on-tfs-build/">automatic deploy of TFS Build when the quality changes&lt;/a>. Those article explain how you can &lt;strong>build a WebService that listens for notification from TFS and react accordingly. If you are curious if this technique works also for Visual Studio Online, the answer is obviously YES&lt;/strong> !.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can reuse the very same code for the previous example, because VSO uses the very same mechanism as TFS on-premise, so you can easily use the same service regardless you want to be notified from on-premise installation (using BisSubscribe.exe) or VSO. You should have your service installed with a public accessible endpoints, because VSO should be able to call it from Azure. For a simple demo I’ve installed the service on an Azure Virtual Machine but you can use also a Azure Web Site or on-premise IIS that is accessible from azure (have a public DNS).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Application Insights on Visual Studio Online</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/02/application-insights-on-visual-studio-online/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/02/application-insights-on-visual-studio-online/</guid><description>&lt;p>Continuous deploy on Test and PreProduction server was always an argument that fascinates me a lot. &lt;strong>The ability to have latest version of the code up and Running in a Test environment is a must for every developing team&lt;/strong>. I’ve wrote some articles in the past on how to obtain such result for Web Sites and TFS.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2013/07/05/deploying-on-azure-web-sites-from-on-premise-tfs/">Deploying on AzureWebSites from on-premise Team Foundation Server&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2013/08/01/deploy-asp-net-web-site-on-iis-from-tfs-build/">Deploy Asp Net web Sites on IIS from Team Foundation Server Build&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2013/08/05/manage-test-data-in-visual-studio-database-project/">Manage Test Data in Visual Studio Database Project&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2013/05/22/continuous-deployment-on-windows-azure-with-database-projects/">Continuous Deployment on Windows Azure Web Sites with Database Projects&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2013/08/16/build-deploy-web-performance-test-with-tfs-build/">Build, Deploy, Web Performance test with TFS Build&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Now that you are able to automatically deploy a Web Site you need a way to monitor your site to verify what is happening during testing and beta phase. Thanks to Visual Studio Online Application Insights, you can have a lot of information about your application with very little effort. This kind of information are most useful for production server, but they can be really useful even during testing phase.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>