<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>programming on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/programming/</link><description>Recent content in programming on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 09:40:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Problem with Castle Windsor resolution in ASP.NET Core</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/castle-resolution-in-asp-net-core/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 09:40:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/castle-resolution-in-asp-net-core/</guid><description>Castle Windsor is a beautiful library for implementing inversion of control, but sometimes problem arise when it is used in projects that start with Full Framework and must be converted to ASP.NET Core during their lifetime. To make this work, an interdependency library is typically used to allow ASP.NET Core infrastructure to resolve dependencies using Castle. This approach helps avoid issues when replacing Castle with other libraries, since Castle is both powerful and complex, allowing for many customizations in dependency resolution.</description></item><item><title>Tutorial: Programming Playstation 2</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/memories/playstation2-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/memories/playstation2-tutorial/</guid><description>Looking in old backup and old disk can be a dive in the past, you found old stuff like articles tutorial and yesterday I stumbled on my old tutorial on Playstation 2. There were a time when I was really interested in Computer Graphics, and I had a Playstation 2 Linux kit that a dear friend of mine gave me. The kit was really interesting because it allows you to play with a nice and pretty architecture for the time.</description></item><item><title>Symbol server made easy with Azure DevOps</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/programming/aspnet/working-with-symbols/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 08:13:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/programming/aspnet/working-with-symbols/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve blogged in the past about symbol server, to recap here is the scenario.
In your organization you have some sort of common .NET code that is shared between projects, but you have to face and resolve some problems.
How to compile dlls How to distribute dlls How to make debugging easier for the user of the dll. We have clearly some standard solution for all the parts.</description></item><item><title>Determine version with GitVersion for a Python project</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/github/giversion-python-general/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/github/giversion-python-general/</guid><description>Project used for this example can be found in GitHub.
In GitHub actions you can use .NET based tools, both in Windows and in Linux machines, to accomplish various tasks. I&amp;rsquo;m a great fan of GitVersion tool, used to determine a semantic versioning based on a Git repository that uses git-flow structure. Another nice aspect is that GitHub action machines based on Linux comes with PowerShell core preinstalled, so I can use actions that comes from PowerShell gallery without any problems &amp;hellip; errr.</description></item><item><title>Avoid IIS to bind to every IP Address port and other amenities</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/iis-bind-ip/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/iis-bind-ip/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s suppose you have a Microservices based solution, you have many different processes and each process communicates with standard WebAPI. The usual developer solution is using a different port for each different program, this lead to http://localhost:12345, http://localhost:12346 and so on. This is far from being optimal, because in production, probably, each service could potentially be exposed with a different hostname, something like https://auth.mysoftware.com, https://orders.mysoftware.com and so on. Another problem is that, in production, everything must be exposed with https and too many times developer are not testing with TLS enabled.</description></item><item><title>Multitarget NetStandard for Windows and Linux</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/10/multitarget-netstandard-for-windows-and-linux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/10/multitarget-netstandard-for-windows-and-linux/</guid><description>One of the most important features of DotNetStandard is the ability to run on Linux and Mac, but if you need to use a DotNetStandard compiled library in a project that uses full.NET framework, sometimes you can have little problems. Actually you can reference a dll compiled for DotNetCore from a project that uses full Framework, but in a couple of project we experienced some trouble with some assemblies.
Thanks to multitargeting you can simply instruct DotNet compiler to produce libraries compiled against different versions of frameworks, so you can simply tell the compiler that you want both DotNetStandard 2.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading SonarQube from 51 to 60</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/08/upgrading-sonarqube-from-5-1-to-6-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/08/upgrading-sonarqube-from-5-1-to-6-0/</guid><description>SonarQube is a really nice software, but for what I experienced it does not play well with Sql Server. Even if Sql Server is fully supported, there are always some little problem in setting everything up, and this is probably due to the fact that most of the people using SonarQube are using MySql as Database Engine.
Today I was upgrading a test instance from version 5.1 to 6.0 , I’ve installed the new version, launched database upgrade procedure, and after some minutes the upgrade procedure stopped with a bad error</description></item><item><title>Decide when CastleWindsor Startable Facility starts your components</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/05/decide-when-castle-windsor-startable-facility-starts-your-components/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/05/decide-when-castle-windsor-startable-facility-starts-your-components/</guid><description>Castle.Windsor Startable facility is a nice facility that automatically starts component that implements a specific interface (IStartable) or components registered with specific extensions method (ex StartUsingMethod).
This approach is really nice, and the Facility has different way to work, the old aggressive mode that try to start a component immediately after is registered, and another, more useful, that starts a component only when all its dependencies are registered. This feature is helpful, because it avoid you to worry about order of registration.</description></item><item><title>Nuget default configuration</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/04/nuget-default-configuration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/04/nuget-default-configuration/</guid><description>If you use MyGet as package source or some other Nuget Feed and your code fail to build in a buildserver because it cannot retrieve some package, probably you have some problem in NuGet configuration.
**If you issue a nuget.exe source listin command line, you should be able to see all package source configured. **Actually I had a problem in a TeamCity build server, after we added a new package source to a solution and pushed code to the server the build was broken.</description></item><item><title>ProtocolViolationException when writing on response NetworkStream in c</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/09/protocolviolationexception-when-writing-on-response-networkstream-in-c/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/09/protocolviolationexception-when-writing-on-response-networkstream-in-c/</guid><description>I have a piece of code that is returning data with an HttpListener, but I have intermittent error in logs
Bytes to be written to the stream exceed the Content-Length bytes size specified
I wonder where is the error, because the code is simply returning a string with proper encoding and the ContentLength64 property of the Response was set correctly.
1 2 3 4 5 byte[] buffer = Encoding.</description></item><item><title>Git showing file as modified even if it is unchanged</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/04/git-showing-file-as-modified-even-if-it-is-unchanged/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/04/git-showing-file-as-modified-even-if-it-is-unchanged/</guid><description>This is one annoying problem that happens sometimes to git users: the symptom is:* **git status** *command shows you some files as modified (you are sure that you had not modified that files), you revert all changes with a * **git checkout —.** *but the files stills are in modified state if you issue another * **git status** *.
This is a real annoying problem, suppose you want to switch branch with * git checkout branchname *, you will find that git does not allow you to switch because of uncommitted changes.</description></item><item><title>Take care when you use RegExp constructor in javascript</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/01/take-care-when-you-use-regexp-constructor-in-javascript/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 12:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/01/take-care-when-you-use-regexp-constructor-in-javascript/</guid><description>I’m not a javascript guru when it is time to write regular expressions, but this morning I have a bug on a piece of code, and the bug was related to a regex declared in this way.
1 var noMatchRegex = new RegExp(&amp;#34;[\r\n\s;,$]+&amp;#34;); This regex basically should match a carriage return or a space or ; char, etc, but it appears not working sometimes. After a quick test I confirmed that the problem happens when I have string that contains the character ‘s’.</description></item><item><title>The beautiful world of Git-XXX</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/10/the-beautiful-world-of-git-xxx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 21:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/10/the-beautiful-world-of-git-xxx/</guid><description>Git support in Visual Studio Having Git Support in Visual Studio is something I like for a lot of reasons; one of the most important one is the ability to use a local Git repository even if you work with Standard TFS Source Control or if you work with subversion. Usually Git includes a Git svn utility that permits you to clone a subversion locally, use git locally and then finally push commit back to subversion.</description></item><item><title>Create Charts in excel with Open Xml Sdk 25</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/08/create-charts-in-excel-with-open-xml-sdk-2-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/08/create-charts-in-excel-with-open-xml-sdk-2-5/</guid><description>OpenXml Sdk is absolutely a fantastic library to programmatically create Office documents , but when it is time to add Chart components in Excel I‘m starting to feel the pain. I’ve searched in MSDN to find resource on “how to create a chart in Excel with OpenXmlSdk 2.5” and the only resource I’ve found is this article: How to: Insert a chart into a Spreadhseet document.
The article is good, but you immediately realize that the code is not so simple and that is not easy to understand how to modify it to suite your need.</description></item><item><title>Is it possible to run Coded Ui Test in a Virtual Machine instead that in my primary machine</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/is-it-possible-to-run-coded-ui-test-in-a-virtual-machine-instead-that-in-my-primary-machine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/is-it-possible-to-run-coded-ui-test-in-a-virtual-machine-instead-that-in-my-primary-machine/</guid><description>Code UI Test are an effective way to test your UI through automation, they absolutely are not a substitution for Unit Testing, but they can be used effectively to verify the whole application behave as expected. The most annoying part of Coded UI Test is that while they are running you cannot do anything else on the computer, because mouse and UI are used to run the test. This lead to a very common question</description></item><item><title>Wcf error Keyset does not exist with security certificate</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/04/wcf-error-keyset-does-not-exist-with-security-certificate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2012 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/04/wcf-error-keyset-does-not-exist-with-security-certificate/</guid><description>I worked a lot with WCF secured services and whenever is time to use certificates it is not uncommon to encounter strange and not so much descriptive exceptions. One of the less intuitive one is “ keyset does not exists with security certificate” , that basically means that the worker process in IIS is not able to access the service.
I’ve dealt with this problem in an old post, when I used self issued certificates to manage secure client/server communication between windows forms client and a service hosted in IIS, but the very same error happened yesterday trying to configure a net.</description></item><item><title>Dealing with a lot of data usually lot of problems</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/04/dealing-with-a-lot-of-data-usually-lot-of-problems/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/04/dealing-with-a-lot-of-data-usually-lot-of-problems/</guid><description>I’ve just read a post of my friend Mauro, “Dealing with log of Data” and I really agree with his position, because projects that needs to manage big amount of data usually brings a lot of problems both on production server, but also on the everyday developer life.
We tend to think that since disk space is quite cheap in these days , it is not a big problem, but this is usually false.</description></item><item><title>Move blog post from subtext to WordPress with Metaweblog API</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/move-blog-post-from-subtext-to-wordpress-with-metaweblog-api/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/move-blog-post-from-subtext-to-wordpress-with-metaweblog-api/</guid><description>My desire is to move my Italian blog located in http://blogs.ugidotnet.org/rgm to a WordPress blog in our domain http://www.nablasoft.com, because I really feel nostalgic of my old domain, but I face a bad problem, because the export routine of the original blog, based on Subtext , seems not to work. I started thinking to a solution and I decided to try to write a simple program that download post from an original blog engine via Metaweblog API and repost to destination blog.</description></item><item><title>Using CUIT on Firefox 4X does not works</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/05/using-cuit-on-firefox-4-x-does-not-works-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2011 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/05/using-cuit-on-firefox-4-x-does-not-works-2/</guid><description>Suppose you have downloaded the Feature Pack 2 of Visual Studio 2010, enabled firefox support but when you run a CUIT on firefox you got this error.
Test method TestProject.CodedUITest1.NavigateNablasoftTest threw exception: Microsoft.VisualStudio.TestTools.UITest.Extension.TechnologyNotSupportedException: The * selected version of Mozilla Firefox is not supported *for playback. Go to http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=157214 for information on available add-in for possible support.
This happens because FF 4.x is still not supported, but you can download and install FF 3.</description></item><item><title>Change the icon of a folder</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/change-the-icon-of-a-folder/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2011 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/change-the-icon-of-a-folder/</guid><description>I need to change the default icon of Windows Explorer for some special folder inside a my application, I know that it could be done Through Desktop.Ini file, but after some frustrating tentative I did not succeed in using a custom.ico file stored as resource inside the assembly.
It was my fault, because the first resource you should check is MSDN, and when I read the whole page dedicate to this argument I found my error, I forgot to set the System Bit of the folder.</description></item><item><title>SQLite performance in production code</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/sqllite-performance-in-production-code/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/sqllite-performance-in-production-code/</guid><description>SQLite is a cool relational database engine that runs embedded in code, without the need to use a server. It is usually used for unit testing, but it could be used in production code if we need to maintain a small database and we do not need the full power of a SQL Server or similar RDBMS.
When you use SQLite in production, remember to enable caching of connection into the connection string, if you use the wrong connection string, you wull not use pooling, and performance will suffer.</description></item><item><title>Use a WebBrowser to login into a site that use HttpOnly cookie</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/use-a-webbrowser-to-login-into-a-site-that-use-httponly-cookie/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2011 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/use-a-webbrowser-to-login-into-a-site-that-use-httponly-cookie/</guid><description>Suppose you need to programmatically analyze some web pages that are protected by a login procedure and you have a valid login to the site. A simple solution is issuing a POST request to the login page with the correct credentials, then continue to use the same cookie container to issue subsequent downloads, but in some situation this is not enough. Suppose the site uses some strange login procedure that uses redirect</description></item><item><title>I love R because it reduce mouse usage</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/03/i-love-r-because-it-reduce-mouse-usage/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/03/i-love-r-because-it-reduce-mouse-usage/</guid><description>I have this piece of code
And doc2 is checked because it could be null, so I can ALT+RET and choose the right action, as example check if doc2 is null
And I got this
With a couple of click on the keyboard, if you to not like all of the code to be indented inside the if you can press ALT+RETURN on the declaration of the doc2 variable</description></item><item><title>GeckoFX for c strange behavior</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/01/geckofx-for-c-strange-behavior/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/01/geckofx-for-c-strange-behavior/</guid><description>Today I faced a very strange problem with GeckoBrowser, after navigating a page I simply need to grab all the HTML of the page to analyze it. I try to access the * GeckoBrowser.Document.TextContentv *property but it is always null.
I searched on the web and found this discussion but it does not work, because the DocumentElement.InnerHtml throws a nullreferenceexception, how sad. In that post a user suggest to download the text manually, but saving bandwidth is one of the requirements, so I really need to use the HTML already downloaded by Gecko Browser.</description></item><item><title>Resharper live template are the solution to many problems</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/01/resharper-live-template-are-the-solution-to-many-problems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/01/resharper-live-template-are-the-solution-to-many-problems/</guid><description>Surely when you write code you write a lot of similar snippets, as an example, defining properties in objects that should implements INotifyPropertyChanged is usually highly repetitive, I write my properties like this one.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 [DataMember] public Int32 Rank { get { return _rank; } set { this.Set(p =&amp;gt; p.Rank, value, ref _rank); } } private Int32 _rank; DataMember is needed for WCF, and the setter part is based on some base class and some helpers that raise INotifyPropertyChanged etc etc etc.</description></item><item><title>T4 toolbox RenderCore no suitable method to override</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/t4-toolbox-rendercore-no-suitable-method-to-override/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/t4-toolbox-rendercore-no-suitable-method-to-override/</guid><description>T4 toolbox a very good Visual Studio addin to efficiently manage T4 template. If you move to the new version you should be aware that there is a breaking change in the base Template class. In old version you render all text inside the method RenderCore()
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 protected override void RenderCore() { GenerateDto( AssemblyName, HostDirectory, TypeName, DtoName, NameSpaceName, DataContractNameSpace, InheritLevel, Properties, PropertyDataList, GenerateINotifiedPropertyChanging, GenerateINotifiedPropertyChanged, GenerateIEditableObject); } In the new version the function RenderCore is not accessible anymore from derived classes, and you should override the TransformText() function.</description></item><item><title>Brian Harry programming practices</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/brian-harry-programming-practices/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/brian-harry-programming-practices/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m exited on Brian Harry&amp;rsquo;s plan to do a series of posts regarding programming practices in his blog. The main reason is that Brian had really wrote tons of good code and it is really interesting knowing how he organize his projects. From this first post I strongly agree with a couple of concepts, the first is having a clean code at regular interval, no longer than few hours.
I made mistake in the past, and sometimes in the present, I begin coding a super new feature, with a lot of code, and after some hours I have nothing working because I&amp;rsquo;m still doing infrastructure code, etc etc.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio 2010 Intellisense does not show 'Parameter Info'</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/visual-studio-2010-intellisense-does-not-show-parameter-info/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2010 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/visual-studio-2010-intellisense-does-not-show-parameter-info/</guid><description>I installed on metal VS2010 RC, and when I tried to write the first line of code I see that intellisense failed to show parameter info.
This bring me back when I was young, and we have to remember all C stdlib functions because we used vi in linux to edit source file, but in 2010 I&amp;rsquo;m really bad without intellisense.
Ok, I remember very well that SqlConnection has 2 constructors, but for complex classes working without intellisense can be a pain.</description></item><item><title>Change base directory of a site in IIS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/change-base-directory-of-a-site-in-iis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/change-base-directory-of-a-site-in-iis/</guid><description>This technique works for IIS6 and IIS7 with the &amp;ldquo;IIS 6 WMI Compatibility* installed. The purpose is changing the directory of a web site in a remote server. The purpose of this action will be clear in a future post, for now only assume that you want to be able to create a piece of c# code that changes directory of a web site in windows server. Here is a test site.</description></item><item><title>Use AspNet Membership provider with a WCF svc service</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/09/use-aspnet-membership-provider-with-a-wcf-svc-service/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2009 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/09/use-aspnet-membership-provider-with-a-wcf-svc-service/</guid><description>Yesterday I literally lost 4 hours trying to do the following thing: Exposing a wcf service with wsHttpBinding, and using the same asp.net membership database used by the site. I encountered many problems, and I decided to write this post to explain the steps that makes everything work for me. First of all you need to know that fact: if you want to use asp.net membership in a wcf service exposed with wsHttpBinding you need to use certificates , and this causes most of the problems.</description></item><item><title>Manipulate Expression Tree in DtoGenerator</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/manipulate-expression-tree-in-dtogenerator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/manipulate-expression-tree-in-dtogenerator/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing a simple Dto generator, and today I found a challenging problem. I supported dto composition like this:
I have a CustomerDto3 that have only CustomerId and ContactName properties, then I want to autogenerate a OrderTestDto that have a Customers property of type CustomerDto3. The syntax on My T4 generator is this one.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 SyntaxCode syntax = new SyntaxCode( @&amp;#34;bin\Debug\DtoFactory.Exe&amp;#34;, Path.</description></item><item><title>Dto generator and repository integration</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/dto-generator-and-repository-integration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/dto-generator-and-repository-integration/</guid><description>I have a project where I use repository pattern, interface code access domain object through a service, and the service return Dto. One of the bad side of the dto is that they are boring to write and to maintain. The main risk is that developers does this error
Mmmm I had to show a combo with all the typologies of the current customer, let me seee, I have already a service that return Typlogy object given the customer Id, ok I&amp;rsquo;ll use it.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on software engineering</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/thoughts-on-software-engineering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2009 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/thoughts-on-software-engineering/</guid><description>I was reading this post of Jeff Atwood that link this interesting article. One of the key point in the article was to consider two different kind of projects
Project A will eventually cost about a million dollars and produce value of around $1.1 million. Project B will eventually cost about a million dollars and produce value of more than $50 million. And the conclusion is that *control is more important in project A and not in project B,*and another astonishing sentence in the article was</description></item><item><title>Manipulation of configuration files for deploy</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/manipulation-of-configuration-files-for-deploy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/manipulation-of-configuration-files-for-deploy/</guid><description>In my experience, one of the most feared problem during the going in production phase of an asp.net site or a complex project is configurations. Usually everything works perfectly on developer machines, but when you move the project in production machines all sort of problems appear.
For Asp.Net, one day one of my colleagues called me asking a little help troubleshooting some performance problem of a site in production, the problem was so big that after a couple of hours the application goes into memory overflow exception.</description></item><item><title>error MSB3321 Importing key file xxx was canceled</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/error-msb3321-importing-key-file-xxx-was-canceled/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 01:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/error-msb3321-importing-key-file-xxx-was-canceled/</guid><description>I start to got this error from my Continuous integration machine, after I setup a project for deploy with clickonce the build begins to fail. I&amp;rsquo;m using CC.net with msbuild scripts and in detailed error I see a message like
The &amp;ldquo;ResolveKeySource&amp;rdquo; task failed unexpectedly.
System.InvalidOperationException: Showing a modal dialog box or form when the application is not running in UserInteractive mode is not a valid operation. Specify the ServiceNotification or DefaultDesktopOnly style to display a notification from a service application.</description></item></channel></rss>