<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rest APIs on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/rest-apis/</link><description>Recent content in Rest APIs on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 09:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/rest-apis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Import a Git Project with REST API between VSTS Team Projects</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/10/import-a-git-project-with-rest-api-between-vsts-team-projects/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/10/import-a-git-project-with-rest-api-between-vsts-team-projects/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve got an interesting question about the possibility to import via REST API a Git Repository between Team Projects of VSTS. Actually the problem is: **you want to import a private git repository from a &lt;em>Source repository&lt;/em>(in this situation is another VSTS git repository but it could be hosted everywhere) to a VSTS &lt;em>Target  repository&lt;/em> using only REST API. **The operation is quite simple thanks to the new api described here (&lt;a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/en-us/docs/integrate/api/git/import-requests#create-a-request-to-import-a-repository" title="https://www.visualstudio.com/en-us/docs/integrate/api/git/import-requests#create-a-request-to-import-a-repository">https://www.visualstudio.com/en-us/docs/integrate/api/git/import-requests#create-a-request-to-import-a-repository&lt;/a>) and in this post I’ll give you all the details.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting Work Item data in powershell through REST API</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/01/getting-work-item-data-in-powershell-through-rest-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/01/getting-work-item-data-in-powershell-through-rest-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>VSTS and the latests versions of on-premise TFS has the ability to access data through&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/en-us/integrate/api/overview">&lt;strong>REST API&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> &lt;strong>.&lt;/strong> This way to access TFS data is really convenient expecially if used from PowerShell scripts, because you do not need any external dependency, except being able to issue REST requests with the &lt;a href="https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/hh849971.aspx">Invoke-RestRequest&lt;/a> cmdlet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To simplify accessing your VSTS account, you can &lt;strong>enable alternate credentials, needed to issue request with simple Basic Authentication&lt;/strong>. Here is a PowerShell snippet that retrieve a Work Item with a given ID.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Linking VSO with third party tools</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/10/linking-vso-with-third-party-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/10/linking-vso-with-third-party-tools/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most interesting news of VSO in last months &lt;strong>are&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="http://www.visualstudio.com/integrating-with-service-hooks-vs">&lt;strong>service hooks&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> &lt;strong>and REST API to integrate VSO with&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="http://www.visualstudio.com/integrating-with-service-hooks-vs">&lt;strong>third party tools&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>. This capability is a key for success because ALM is really a complicated subject and rarely you can manage all of your applications with a single tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>VSO and TFS are no exception to this rule, they are more a set of suites and tools glued together under a single brand. TFS is composed by a Work Item Store plus Two options for source control (TFVC/Git) plus a Continuous Integration service (Build service) and a Release Management Tool for release, it integrates with SCOM to keep Ops and Devs in contact, plus much more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TFS Rest Api and Asof operator</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/07/tfs-rest-api-and-asof-operator/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/07/tfs-rest-api-and-asof-operator/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>TFS&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="http://www.visualstudio.com/en-us/integrate/explore/explore-vso-vsi">&lt;strong>Rest Api&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> &lt;strong>are one of the most exiting new feature introduced in Visual Studio Online&lt;/strong>. One of the most important aspect of TFS is the ability to gather data about our team and having full access to that data for custom reporting is the primary need for most people. While you can query TFS Warehouse database for on-premise TFS to gather all the data you need, you have no access to databases for VSO In such scenario Rest APIs are the best way to interact to your account to quickly grab data to consume from your application.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>