<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ALM on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/alm/</link><description>Recent content in ALM on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 19:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/alm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Visual Studio ALM links week 362012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/visual-studio-alm-links-week-362012/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/visual-studio-alm-links-week-362012/</guid><description>Remote UAC with Standard Environment and Workgroup Machines Convert VB.NET to C# from Visual Studio 2012 Team Foundation TaskBoard: Auto Refresh ALM Rangers Demo Factory Team release their first demo nuggets!!!! Visual studio 2012 cookbook ALM Rangers – ALM Dogfooding and the ANGST Factor Alk.</description></item><item><title>Visual studio ALM links week 352012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/visual-studio-alm-links-week-352012/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/visual-studio-alm-links-week-352012/</guid><description>ALM Rangers Branching and Merging guide for Visual Studio 2012 is available Enable Remote Audio Capture to when Testing or Providing Feedback on Remote Machines Adding work item ids to Team Foundation Server Board Team Foundation Service Updates 8/27 Updated: Visual Studio 2012 RTM ALM Virtual Machine and Hands-on-Labs / Demo Scripts Tfs Shipping Cadence The one With Brian Keller, (new features of Visual studio 2012 release) Alk.</description></item><item><title>Visual studio ALM links week 332012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/visual-studio-alm-links-week-332012/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/visual-studio-alm-links-week-332012/</guid><description>ALM Rangers Build Cusotmization Guide V2 has shipped Team foundation Service Updates 8/13 Compatibility between Team foundation Clients and Team Foundation Server Announcing Git Integration with TFS Team foundation Server 2012 and Project Server 2010 Integration Showing files with pending changes or files that are open in Visual Studio 2012 Solution Explorer Visual Studio 2012 and MSDN Licensing White Paper Alk.</description></item><item><title>Manage disconnected team with TFS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/manage-disconnected-team-with-tfs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/manage-disconnected-team-with-tfs/</guid><description>Suppose you have this scenario, a team is working on company office to create some software that communicate with some complex hardware that will be deployed to a foreign country. When is time to set up everything in production the team goes physically to that foreign country and they will modify the software on the field doing final adjustments but usually they have no connection to the central office. How could you manage to keep your source code aligned when the team is on remote site not being able to access the central TFS?</description></item><item><title>A bunch of links for TFS ecosystem</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/a-bunch-of-links-for-tfs-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2011 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/a-bunch-of-links-for-tfs-ecosystem/</guid><description>TFS is not a tool, but a platform/ecosystem and if you miss to install / consider to use all of the free or commercial tools based on Tfs, you are actually missing the most part of it. Surely TFS comes with a very huge amount of features out of the box, but there are also an extremely high number of useful tools developed by third party developers.
Here is a surely incomplete list (I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep it updated) and in random order of a bunch of tools I know for TFS ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Customize Work Itemrsquos fields with Rules</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/customize-work-items-fields-with-rules/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2011 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/customize-work-items-fields-with-rules/</guid><description>1 – Customize Tfs Process Template
2 – Basic of TFS Process Template Customization
3 – Adding Field to a Work Item Definition
In the third part of this tutorial I showed how to add a field to a Work Item Definition, in this post I’ll show how you can customize field’s behavior with the addition of Rules.
If I select the new field I just created (called Note di revisione), I can press edit to modify its definition and in the “Field Definition” form I can manage all the Rulesapplied to the field.</description></item><item><title>Customization of TFS process template - adding field to a Work Item Definition</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/customization-of-tfs-process-template-adding-field-to-a-work-item-definition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/customization-of-tfs-process-template-adding-field-to-a-work-item-definition/</guid><description>1 – Customize Tfs Process Template
2 – Basic of TFS Process Template Customization
In this third part it is time to configure the definition of a Work Item. This is the most complex and more useful section of the process template that you can modify to adapt to your needs. We can modify a WI definition in two distinct way: on a local process template as explained in the previous articles and directly on a Team Process that exists on the server.</description></item><item><title>Basic of TFS Process Template customization</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/basic-of-tfs-process-template-customization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/basic-of-tfs-process-template-customization/</guid><description>1 – Customize Tfs Process Template
In the first post I showed how to download the definition of a process template into a local folder and how to open it with the Process Template Editor; in this post I&amp;rsquo;ll show you some of the very basic customizations that you can do with the PTE.
In the Methodology section you can simply change the name of the Process Template as well as including a textual description.</description></item><item><title>Customize TFS Process Template</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/customize-tfs-process-template/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/customize-tfs-process-template/</guid><description>One of the best aspect of TFS is that it is customizable: we can interact with API, customize builds, handle events and many other interaction, but one of the most important is the ability to customize the process template.
This capability is fundamental, because permit to adapt TFS to own process, the mantra is ** do not adapt your process to the tool, but adapt the tool to your process **.</description></item></channel></rss>