<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Actions on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/actions/</link><description>Recent content in Actions on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 08:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/actions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GitHub actions templates</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/github/github-actions-templates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/github/github-actions-templates/</guid><description>GitHub Actions are closing the gap with Azure DevOps pipelines day by day, one of the features introduces months ago was Action templates, the ability to re-use actions definitions between repositories. You can read all the detail in Official GitHub documentation.
Templates are really useful because usually, in one organization, you tend to use a restricted set of technologies with the very same set of actions to perform to build and release the code.</description></item><item><title>Analyze Python project with SonarCloud and GitHub</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/github/python-sonarcloud-actions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/github/python-sonarcloud-actions/</guid><description>SonarCloud is free for Open Source projects, and for languages like Python, that does not need compilation, it can directly analyze the repository without any intervention from the author. This feature is automatically enabled when you setup your Project in SonarCloud and it determines that you have not compiled language.
Figure 1: Analysis configuration shows that in this project we have CI analysis
If you look at Figure you can see that in my situation I have a Continuous Integration based analysis and my automatic analysis is disabled.</description></item></channel></rss>