<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 17:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using certificate for SSH in Azure Linux VM</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/10/using-certificate-for-ssh-in-azure-linux-vm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/10/using-certificate-for-ssh-in-azure-linux-vm/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you like &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2015/10/10/using-certificate-to-connect-via-ssh-to-your-linux-machine/">to use certificate to connect via SSH to your Linux machine&lt;/a> you will probably use that technique to access all of your VMs, even those one hosted on Azure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This operation is really simple, because &lt;strong>Azure Portal allow you to specify the public key during VM creation&lt;/strong> and everything else is managed by VM Creation Scripts. In the same blade where you specify username and password you can opt in to use a certificate instead of a password. You should open the file with.pub extension you’ve created previously (with ssh-keygen) and paste full content in appropriate textbox.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Certificate to connect via SSH to your Linux Machine</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/10/using-certificate-to-connect-via-ssh-to-your-linux-machine/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/10/using-certificate-to-connect-via-ssh-to-your-linux-machine/</guid><description>&lt;p>The world of computer is changing and &lt;strong>is it not possible anymore to live in an isolated silo where you use only one operating system or technology&lt;/strong> , and this is the reason why, even if my last 20 years of development and work were made exclusively on Windows technologies, in this last 2 years I had many occasion to use Linux machines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I used Linux at the very beginning, using Slackware distribution and I was the typical guy that use command line. At that time I used Windows Maker as UI but all the administration was done via console. &lt;strong>This is the reason why, when I need a Linux VM (docker, ElasticSearch, Solr, Mongo, etc) I always install without a GUI.&lt;/strong> I use local Hyper-V host or Azure, and usually connect to machine via SSH with standard username and password, but this is not the optimal situation because I have lots of VM. With many Vm you can use the same password for all machines, or use a password manager to keep track of all the passwords, but this is not so secure (even if all environment are test ones).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Grey screen RDP to Ubuntu server VM running on Azure</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/05/grey-screen-rdp-to-ubuntu-server-vm-running-on-azure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/05/grey-screen-rdp-to-ubuntu-server-vm-running-on-azure/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are a &lt;a href="http://blogs.technet.com/b/uktechnet/archive/2013/11/12/running-a-remote-desktop-on-a-windows-azure-linux-vm.aspx">lot of articles&lt;/a> that explains how to setup a Ubuntu machine on Azure and being able to use xrdp to access it with a standard Remote Desktop session. If you try now and &lt;strong>use Ubuntu 14 to create your virtual machine you will discover that you are able to RDP to the machine, but after inserting credential you will be prompted with a grey Screen&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is due to a change in Ubuntu 14, you can read details in &lt;a href="http://askubuntu.com/questions/449785/ubuntu-14-04-xrdp-grey">this blog post&lt;/a>. If you want to save time you can simply choose an older Ubuntu distribution for your Azure Machine, and in few minutes you will be able to RDP to Ubuntu from Windows machines.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>