<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SSIS on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/ssis/</link><description>Recent content in SSIS on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 12:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/ssis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Run SSIS package from another server in workspace</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/run-ssis-package-from-another-server-in-workspace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 12:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/run-ssis-package-from-another-server-in-workspace/</guid><description>Today I needed to move some SSIS packages that actually runs on the same server where the database resides, to another server dedicated to run SSIS packages. I do not have a domain and the second server is simply in the same network as the first server. I simply reconfigured a Job to run the Package from File system (as originally configured in the original server), but now I could not use Integrated Security because I&amp;rsquo;m running the SSIS package from another PC.</description></item><item><title>SSIS use parameter with ADO Net source in DataFlow</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/ssis-use-parameter-with-ado-net-source-in-dataflow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/ssis-use-parameter-with-ado-net-source-in-dataflow/</guid><description>I have a database where reports are done with stored procedure over the OLTP database, and we begin to suffer poor performance because we have a lot of data and sometimes reports are locked by transaction issued from components that does bulk data insertion.
A viable solution is moving all data in a DataWarehouse server where I can copy all denormalized data. This permits me to do a report query with only a simple select over a single table, then queries are issued against a database with no lock.</description></item></channel></rss>