<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WCF IIS7 on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/wcf-iis7/</link><description>Recent content in WCF IIS7 on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 11:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/wcf-iis7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to test SSL based WCF services</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/11/how-to-test-ssl-based-wcf-services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/11/how-to-test-ssl-based-wcf-services/</guid><description>&lt;p>I usually work with WCF service that needs to be secured with Certificates or simply using HTTPS. The usual question from other dev in the team is “how can I simulate HTTPS to work with WCF?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem arise that to test https sites, people usually work with IIS self issued certificates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/SNAGHTMLa82f3d.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/SNAGHTMLa82f3d_thumb.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/SNAGHTMLa82f3d_thumb.png" alt="SNAGHTMLa82f3d" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Figure 1&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>: &lt;em>Self-Signed certificate in IIS&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This works great for sites, you can use the auto signed certificate in your sites in https binding, then when you navigate to the site you usually got an error because the certificate is not issued for the right site. What I need is usually to modifiy the hosts file in windows, creating an alias of &lt;a href="http://www.mydomain.com">www.mydomain.com&lt;/a> to 127.0.0.1, so I can directly point to the right address with WCF client application and can simply manage to use the local or remote service simply modifying the hosts file.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Use AspNet Membership provider with a WCF svc service</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/09/use-aspnet-membership-provider-with-a-wcf-svc-service/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2009 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/09/use-aspnet-membership-provider-with-a-wcf-svc-service/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yesterday I literally lost 4 hours trying to do the following thing: Exposing a wcf service with wsHttpBinding, and using the same asp.net membership database used by the site. I encountered many problems, and I decided to write this post to explain the steps that makes everything work for me. First of all you need to know that fact: &lt;strong>if you want to use asp.net membership in a wcf service exposed with wsHttpBinding you need to use certificates&lt;/strong> , and this causes most of the problems.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>