<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Visual Studio ALM on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/visual-studio-alm/</link><description>Recent content in Visual Studio ALM on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 19:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/visual-studio-alm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TFS 2018 is out time to upgrade</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/11/tfs-2018-is-out-time-to-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/11/tfs-2018-is-out-time-to-upgrade/</guid><description>Some days are passed, but it is good to remind you that TFS 2018 is finally out. Some people are surprised because after TFS 2015 we had TFS 2017 and we are still in 2017 and we already have version 2018, but this is the good part of the ALM tools in Microsoft, they are really shipping tons of new goodness each year :).
Release note page contains all the details about the new version, from that link you have a small 13 minute video that explain what is new in this version and as usual in the page you have a detailed list of all the news with detailed information about each of the new features.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio Online Announcement</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/11/visual-studio-online-announcement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/11/visual-studio-online-announcement/</guid><description>During the official Launch of Visual Studio 2013 a lots of news were announced, but one of the most interesting is Visual Studio Online (Previously Known as TF Service). This is not only a simple rebrand of a product, the change of name indicates also that the service is not only a TFS hosted on Azure but it contains lots more functionality. You can find some quick introductory videos in Channel9.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links week 25</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-25/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-25/</guid><description>Tracking project costs and Budgets with Microsoft TFS XCentium Enhancement What’s new And exciting in.NET 4.5 and Visual Studio 2012 (RangerTalk) Writing.NET in PowerShell and creating TFS Teams Extending Visual Studio Team Explorer 2012 + MyHistory Extension P.S. This will be probably the last of my “Visual Studio ALM Links week xxx” series, because I usually use other channels to share links about Visual Studio ALM news and maintaining such a list is quite a duplication.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links Week 24</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-24-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-24-2/</guid><description> Using TFS Kanban Column State in the warehouse TFS API – May 2013 Release Visual Studio 2012 Extension – List of software installed on TFS Service build Servers Microsoft Test Manager: Customization of test result fields an marking test results as N/A Testing improvements in Team foundation Service Update for Tech Ed 2013</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links Week 24</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-24/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-24/</guid><description>Visual Studio 2013 and TFS 2013 announced It is possible to run Coded UI Tests in a virtual machine instead that in my primary machine Test Scribe for Visual Studio 2012 Update 2 Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links Week 23</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-23/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-23/</guid><description>NEtAdvantage for LightSwitch 2012 Vol.2 Light (Free) now supports Visual Studio 2012 A Bug in TFS 2012 alerts System (Fixed in Update 3) Team Foundation Service Updates for TechEd 2013 Visual Studio 2013 Visual Studio Collaboration, Anywhere Introducing cloud-based Load Testing with Team Foundation Service Visual Studio 2013, ALM, and DevOps MSDN blogs detail Application Lifecycle workflow feature updates Enriched ALM In Visual Studio 2013 and Team Foundation Server 2013 Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links Week 22</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-22/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/visual-studio-alm-links-week-22/</guid><description>Hacking getKanban Version 2 Visual Studio 2012 Supported in Devart’s dbForge Fusion for MySQL 6.0 Restore TFS Backups from Sql Server Enterprise to sql Express Better Multi-User Support for Work Item Tracking in TFS 2012 Using TFS Kanban Column State to the warehouse Team Foundation Service Updates 5/28 – Team Foundation Service Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links Week 21</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/visual-studio-alm-links-week-21/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/visual-studio-alm-links-week-21/</guid><description>Visual Studio ALM Ranger Solutions Catalog TFS as perfect tool for Scrum – Sprint planning (Part 3) Enable Feedback support for users in Team Foundation Server 2012 ALM Readiness Treasure Map Continuous Deployment on Windows Azure with Database Projects Enable Seamless Integration with Team Foundation server Microsoft Test Professional and HP ALM With Opshub 5.3 What has Changed in the home of the ALM Rangers during FY13 Support on Team Foundation Service Team Foundation Task Board Enhancer: Version.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links Week 20</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/visual-studio-alm-links-week-20/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/visual-studio-alm-links-week-20/</guid><description>Microsoft TFS Goes Mobile With Perfecto MobileCloud Configure Test Plans for Web Access in TFS 2012.2 Getting Started with LibGit2Sharp Team Foundation Service Update – May 13 Agilethought ALM Experts Present Free Visual STudio Webinars Known Issue and Workaround for TFS 2012 Update 3 RC1 Quality Enablement with Visual Studio 2012 Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links Week 19</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/visual-studio-alm-links-week-19/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/visual-studio-alm-links-week-19/</guid><description>Better Multi User Support for Work Item Tracking in TFS 2012 Naked ALM: starting with why and getting naked Help Content for the Agile Planning Tools gets a makeover with TFS CU2 Visual Studio Update 2012.3 Update 3 “go-Live” CTP is now available Finding Event Subscriptions in TFS 2012 using Power Shell Testing Java and Cross Platform applications with Squish and Microsoft Test Professional Embracing SCRUM and CMMI in TFS 2012 Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links-Week 18 2013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/visual-studio-alm-linksweek-18-2013/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/visual-studio-alm-linksweek-18-2013/</guid><description>You are doing it wrong if you are not using test first Upgrading your process template from MSF For Agile 4 to Visual Studio Scrum 2.x Use code Maps to understand code relationship Team Explorer Everywhere 2012 Update 2 Connect to TFS 2012 from VS 2005 even from Windows XP Quality Enablement with Microsoft Visual Studio 2012 Deploy Visual Studio 2012 Update 2 through SCCM Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links - Week 17 2013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/04/visual-studio-alm-links-week-17-2013/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/04/visual-studio-alm-links-week-17-2013/</guid><description>New Un-Versioned repository in TFS 2012 ALM Rangers dogfooding journal of the Team Foundation Service Administering Visual Studio TFS 2012: Exam (70-496) Channel 9. Free Microsoft Exam jump start for: Delivering Continuous Value with Visual Studio 2012 ALM Study Guide – Administering Visual Studio Team Foundation Server 2012 Release Management with Team Foundation Server 2012 Sprint 45 Service issues MsBuild Extension Pack – April 2013 Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM links-Week 16 2013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/04/visual-studio-alm-linksweek-16-2013/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/04/visual-studio-alm-linksweek-16-2013/</guid><description>List of all Visual Studio ALM Virtual machines Adventures in Software Engineering Broken Shared steps link after Migration from TFS Integration Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Migrating from TFS On Premise to TF Service With Integration Platform some advices</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/01/migrating-from-tfs-on-premise-to-tf-service-with-integration-platform-some-advices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/01/migrating-from-tfs-on-premise-to-tf-service-with-integration-platform-some-advices/</guid><description>When it is time to migrate from an On Premise version of TFS to TF Service ( http://tfs.visualstudio.com ) actually Integration Platform is the only viable solution. I just want to give you a couple of hint to avoid problem in the migration. The account you are using to perform the migration should be in the Team Project Collection Service account because it need special permissions. Suppose you are using the Brian Keller’s Virtual Machine, you decide to perform the migration with Adam Barr, you need to be sure that the user is part of the Team Project Collection Service account Unfortunately when is time to add a user in that group, you will find that the UI does not allow you to do this, so you need to add the group to the user, not the user to the group, here is the sequence of operations that accomplish this operation.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM links Week 22013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/01/visual-studio-alm-links-week-22013/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/01/visual-studio-alm-links-week-22013/</guid><description>Monitoring TFS 2012 using SCLM (System Center Operation Manager 2012) Changing The product Backlog In TFS 2012 Upgrade TFS 2010 to TFS 2012 with Migration to a New Hardware Putting the You in Visual Studio 2012’s Team Explorer Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links Week 12013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/01/visual-studio-alm-links-week-12013/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/01/visual-studio-alm-links-week-12013/</guid><description>Upgrading to Team Foundation Server 2012 Update 1 in production – DONE Content Index for Coded UI Test Free online training form MSDN subscriber Exporting TF Status to excel Extending Team Explorer in Visual Studio 2012 Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links wees 512012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/12/visual-studio-alm-links-wees-512012/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/12/visual-studio-alm-links-wees-512012/</guid><description>Visual Studio 2012 and Oracle Development environment Sidekicks available for TFS 2012 TFS 2012 Management Pack available Team Explorer Everywhere Update 1 Troubleshooting tips for Cross Browser testing in Coded UI Tests. Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links week 502012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/12/visual-studio-alm-links-week-502012/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/12/visual-studio-alm-links-week-502012/</guid><description>Tfs2012: Monitoring Management Pack Code Coverage in Microsoft Test Manager – Deep Dive Gian Maria.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links week 492012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/12/visual-studio-alm-links-week-492012/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/12/visual-studio-alm-links-week-492012/</guid><description>Meet the author: Ben Day on ALM with TFS 2012 fundamentals Batched Gated Check-ins Replacing the Team Foundation Server Cube with a Tabular Model Understanding The TFS Tabular Model Alk.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM links week 372012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/visual-studio-alm-links-week-372012/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/visual-studio-alm-links-week-372012/</guid><description>Requirement management in the modern application lifecycle. Rangers Flash – August 2012 Where is the Test Toolbar … couldn’t find it anywhere Sam and Neno’s VS 2012 Book available at Launch Visual Studio Express 2012 for Windows Desktop is here Customizable Process Guidance for VS ALM 2012 iOS, iPhone and iPad storyboarding Enjoy.
Alk.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM links week 362012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/visual-studio-alm-links-week-362012/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/visual-studio-alm-links-week-362012/</guid><description>Remote UAC with Standard Environment and Workgroup Machines Convert VB.NET to C# from Visual Studio 2012 Team Foundation TaskBoard: Auto Refresh ALM Rangers Demo Factory Team release their first demo nuggets!!!! Visual studio 2012 cookbook ALM Rangers – ALM Dogfooding and the ANGST Factor Alk.</description></item><item><title>Visual studio ALM links week 352012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/visual-studio-alm-links-week-352012/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/visual-studio-alm-links-week-352012/</guid><description>ALM Rangers Branching and Merging guide for Visual Studio 2012 is available Enable Remote Audio Capture to when Testing or Providing Feedback on Remote Machines Adding work item ids to Team Foundation Server Board Team Foundation Service Updates 8/27 Updated: Visual Studio 2012 RTM ALM Virtual Machine and Hands-on-Labs / Demo Scripts Tfs Shipping Cadence The one With Brian Keller, (new features of Visual studio 2012 release) Alk.</description></item><item><title>Visual studio ALM links week 332012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/visual-studio-alm-links-week-332012/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/visual-studio-alm-links-week-332012/</guid><description>ALM Rangers Build Cusotmization Guide V2 has shipped Team foundation Service Updates 8/13 Compatibility between Team foundation Clients and Team Foundation Server Announcing Git Integration with TFS Team foundation Server 2012 and Project Server 2010 Integration Showing files with pending changes or files that are open in Visual Studio 2012 Solution Explorer Visual Studio 2012 and MSDN Licensing White Paper Alk.</description></item></channel></rss>