<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Macro on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/macro/</link><description>Recent content in Macro on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 17:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/macro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Visual Studio macro to group files</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/visual-studio-macro-to-group-files/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/visual-studio-macro-to-group-files/</guid><description>&lt;p>Visual Studio has the concept of grouping files together a feature used mainly from code generation tools to groups generated files under the main file, but this feature can be used even for your class, as shown in &lt;strong>Figure1&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/image11.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/image_thumb11.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/image_thumb11.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Figure 1&lt;/strong> : &lt;em>Two code files nested inside program.cs&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a lot of reasons to group files togheter, you can use this technique for group partial classes definition or you can simply want to group logically related files, etc etc. The annoying stuff is that there is no menu in Visual Studio that permits you to obtain this result, but you can solve everything with a  macro. Just open the Visual Studio Macro IDE and insert the following macro.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Macro to attach to local IIS take 3</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/macro-to-attach-to-local-iis-take-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2011 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/macro-to-attach-to-local-iis-take-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the third post on the &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2011/08/10/visual-studio-macroattach-to-local-iis/">series&lt;/a> &lt;em>create a macro to &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2011/08/16/attach-to-local-iis-macro-evolution/">Attach to Local IIS&lt;/a>&lt;/em>. The last modification I want to implement is the ability to list all the w3wp.exe active processes, if more than one process is present, I want it to show a list of all IIS processes and let the user choose the list of processes to attach to. Clearly if I have no w3wp.exe active processes, or I have only one, there is no need to bother the user to choose the single available process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Attach to local IIS Macro evolution</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/attach-to-local-iis-macro-evolution/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/attach-to-local-iis-macro-evolution/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve already blogged about the creation of a macro that permits you to attach to IIS worker process pressing a key combination. This approach does not work if you have multiple w3wp.exe processes that are actually running into your machine, because the macro only attach to the very first of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A simple and stupid solution is to attach to every w3wp.exe processes that is actually running in the system :), it is somewhat a &lt;em>patch&lt;/em> solution, but it is really easy to implement, because it requires only a minor modification of the code generated by the Macro Recorder.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Visual studio Macro to the rescue</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/visual-studio-macro-to-the-rescue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/visual-studio-macro-to-the-rescue/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you heavily work with branches, one of the most frustrating error you can do is modify the wrong branch. I have a project composed by several solution each one containing different UI Projects, each one using WCF as back end but released as separate software. Whenever we do a release of a new version of one of the UI we create a branch, so we can support hotfix, SP, etc.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>