<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>T4 Generator on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/t4-generator/</link><description>Recent content in T4 Generator on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 11:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/t4-generator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>T4 toolbox RenderCore no suitable method to override</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/t4-toolbox-rendercore-no-suitable-method-to-override/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/t4-toolbox-rendercore-no-suitable-method-to-override/</guid><description>T4 toolbox a very good Visual Studio addin to efficiently manage T4 template. If you move to the new version you should be aware that there is a breaking change in the base Template class. In old version you render all text inside the method RenderCore()
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 protected override void RenderCore() { GenerateDto( AssemblyName, HostDirectory, TypeName, DtoName, NameSpaceName, DataContractNameSpace, InheritLevel, Properties, PropertyDataList, GenerateINotifiedPropertyChanging, GenerateINotifiedPropertyChanged, GenerateIEditableObject); } In the new version the function RenderCore is not accessible anymore from derived classes, and you should override the TransformText() function.</description></item><item><title>Manipulate Expression Tree in DtoGenerator</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/manipulate-expression-tree-in-dtogenerator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/manipulate-expression-tree-in-dtogenerator/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing a simple Dto generator, and today I found a challenging problem. I supported dto composition like this:
I have a CustomerDto3 that have only CustomerId and ContactName properties, then I want to autogenerate a OrderTestDto that have a Customers property of type CustomerDto3. The syntax on My T4 generator is this one.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 SyntaxCode syntax = new SyntaxCode( @&amp;#34;bin\Debug\DtoFactory.Exe&amp;#34;, Path.</description></item></channel></rss>