<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TFS11 on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/tfs11/</link><description>Recent content in TFS11 on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 08:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/tfs11/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Local workspaces in TFS11</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/local-workspaces-in-tfs11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/local-workspaces-in-tfs11/</guid><description>&lt;p>The concept of Workspace is a key point in Team Foundation Server, it represents the mapping between a local version and server version of source control of a Team Project. The Workspace model of TFS was somewhat criticized in the past, because it is logically &lt;em>Server Side&lt;/em>, because TFS Server, in each moment, knows the situation of each workspace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This choice has, (as any choice in real life :) ) good and bad point. The good point is that Get Latest operation are really quick, because the server knows the situation of your workspace and can simply send you all files that were modified since the previous Get operation. The bad part is that, if you delete a file from windows explorer, when you issue a Get Latest it is not downloaded again, because the server really believe that the file is in your workspace (you can solve such inconsistencies with* &lt;strong>tfpt scorch&lt;/strong> *command from &lt;a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/c255a1e4-04ba-4f68-8f4e-cd473d6b971f">power tools&lt;/a>). Another annoying problem is that all files are read-only on disk, because before starting a file modification you should contact the server to do a Check-Out operation. This does not mean that the file is locked, just that you need to make the server knows the fact that you started modifying that file.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>