<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sonarqube on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/sonarqube/</link><description>Recent content in Sonarqube on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 11:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/sonarqube/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sonar Analysis of Python with Azure DevOps pipeline</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/01/sonar-analysis-of-python-with-azure-devops-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/01/sonar-analysis-of-python-with-azure-devops-pipeline/</guid><description>Once you have test and Code Coverage for your build of Python code, last step for a good build is adding support for Code Analysis with Sonar/SonarCloud. SonarCloud is the best option if your code is open source, because it is free and you should not install anything except the free addin in Azure Devops Marketplace.
From original build you need only to add two steps: PrepareAnalysis onSonarCloud and Run SonarCloud analysis, in the same way you do analysis for a.</description></item><item><title>Run SonarCloud analysis in VSTS TFS Build</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/03/run-sonarcloud-analysis-in-vsts-tfs-build/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/03/run-sonarcloud-analysis-in-vsts-tfs-build/</guid><description>Running a SonarQube analysis for TFS or VSTS is really easy because we can use a pre-made build tasks that requires few parameters and the game is done. If you have open source project it made lot of sense to use a public account in SonarCloud , so you do not need to maintain a sonar server on-premise and you can also share your public account with the community.
For open source projects, SonarCloud is available for you with zero effort and thanks to VSTS and TFS you can automate the analysis with few steps.</description></item><item><title>Exclude Folders from SonarQube analysis</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/07/exclude-folders-from-sonarqube-analysis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/07/exclude-folders-from-sonarqube-analysis/</guid><description>Creating a build that is capable of perform a SonarQube analysis on a VSTS / TFS is a really simple task, thanks to the two tasks that are present out-of-the box.
Figure 1: Build that uses Sonarqube tasks to perform analysis
The problem in a project that was alive for more than a couple of years is that you usually have a really bad report when you do your first analysis.</description></item><item><title>SonarQube UTF-8 error after upgrading</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/12/sonarqube-utf-8-error-after-upgrading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 12:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/12/sonarqube-utf-8-error-after-upgrading/</guid><description>I’ve upgraded a SonarQube instance, and then, suddently I realyze that some builds start failing due to to a strange error in the SonarQube complete analysis task.
1 2 3 2016-12-09T11:41:00.8695497Z ##[error]WARN: Invalid character encountered in file C:\vso\_work\3\s\src\Jarvis.ConfigurationService.Client.CastleIntegration\Properties\AssemblyInfo.cs at line 25 for encoding UTF-8. Please fix file content or configure the encoding to be used using property &amp;#39;sonar.sourceEncoding&amp;#39;. Thiserror in turns made the entire task execution failing with a really strange error</description></item><item><title>Upgrading SonarQube from 51 to 60</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/08/upgrading-sonarqube-from-5-1-to-6-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/08/upgrading-sonarqube-from-5-1-to-6-0/</guid><description>SonarQube is a really nice software, but for what I experienced it does not play well with Sql Server. Even if Sql Server is fully supported, there are always some little problem in setting everything up, and this is probably due to the fact that most of the people using SonarQube are using MySql as Database Engine.
Today I was upgrading a test instance from version 5.1 to 6.0 , I’ve installed the new version, launched database upgrade procedure, and after some minutes the upgrade procedure stopped with a bad error</description></item><item><title>No agent could be found with the following capabilities</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/05/no-agent-could-be-found-with-the-following-capabilities/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/05/no-agent-could-be-found-with-the-following-capabilities/</guid><description>In TFS 2015 / VSTS new build system each task contains a series of requirements that needs to be matched by agents capabilities for the task to run. Usually you install Visual Studio in the machine with the build agent and you can schedule standard.NET builds without problem, but what happens when the build starts to evolve?
When you start creating more complex build, you can find that your agent does not meets requirements because it miss some of the required capabilities.</description></item><item><title>Sonar Upgrade from 51 to 53</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/02/sonar-upgrade-from-5-1-to-5-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/02/sonar-upgrade-from-5-1-to-5-3/</guid><description>I really like SonarQube, but I need to admit that upgrade procedures are not the best experience I’ve had. Upgrading from 5.1 to 5.3 should be a simple task, but I had a couple of problems. I’ve followed the official upgrade instruction: http://docs.sonarqube.org/display/SONAR/Upgrading but the first problem was my connection string to SQL Server, that needs to be changed. Original connection string was
sonar.jdbc.url=jdbc:jtds:sqlserver://localhost/Sonar;SelectMethod=Cursor;instance=sqlexpress
But it seems that with the new version of Solr it needs to be changed because jtds is not anymore used.</description></item><item><title>Analyze your project with SonarQube in TFS Build vNext</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/10/analyze-your-project-with-sonarqube-in-tfs-build-vnext/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/10/analyze-your-project-with-sonarqube-in-tfs-build-vnext/</guid><description>When you have your SonarQube server up and runinng it is time to put some data into it. You will be amazed to know how simple it is with build vNext and Visual Studio Online.
Installing the analyzer As a prerequisite, you need to install Java on the machine where the agent is running, then download the Msbuild.SonarQube.Runner, unblock the zip and unzip everything in a folder of your HD. Make sure that PATH contains that folder so you are able to launch the runner from any command prompt.</description></item></channel></rss>