<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hardware on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in Hardware on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 09:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Budget for Hardware</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/11/budget-for-hardware/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/11/budget-for-hardware/</guid><description>I’ve just read this blog post that deals about the benefit of having the right hardware to work for developers. Quite often having or not having an SSD is not the real problem, because developers works with machine with low ram and slow disks and this is especially true for people working with laptop, that often uses 5.400 standard RPM disks.
It is difficult to understand how much minutes or hours per day a developer can save moving from an average speed hardware to a top speed hardware and without these numbers it is difficult to justify the expense of buying top speed hardware.</description></item><item><title>Extract the maximum from your Hardware</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/extract-the-maximum-from-your-hardware/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/extract-the-maximum-from-your-hardware/</guid><description>I used to be a hardware enthusiast in the past, I start overclocking PC in the old day of 486, and I loved to tweak my system to squeeze out the most I can. After lots of years are passed, I have no time to follow overclocking forum, and I do not want to risk system stability to have a little increase in performance.
In the last post I show the benchmark for all of my disks units, and after the benchmark I got a suggestion of running the Intel Solid State Drive Toolbox to verify that my settings makes my ssd disk operates at maximum speed.</description></item><item><title>Benchmarking your disks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/benchmarking-your-disks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/benchmarking-your-disks/</guid><description>I love Fast Hard Disks and in the last month I bought an SSD and a replacement 2TB disk for my Virtual Machine disk that failed last week. Today I wanted to do a little benchmark on all the disks that are inside my machine to verify the differencies between the various units.
These are the results from my Intel-X25 M disk
These ones are for RAID-0 of two WD Velociraptor 10K RPM (150 GB each)</description></item><item><title>The good part of having a lot of RAM</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/the-good-part-of-having-a-lot-of-ram/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/the-good-part-of-having-a-lot-of-ram/</guid><description>I’ve learned in the past a precious rule about hardware: try to imagine how you will use your pc in at least one or two years period before thinking to buy some piece of hardware.
I remember a lot of years ago, when I bought a pc with a 1.6 GB Hard Disk, a size that was really big for these period, when standard pc had 512 MB Hard Disk or less.</description></item><item><title>My new Workstation is arrived</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/05/my-new-workstation-is-arrived/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/05/my-new-workstation-is-arrived/</guid><description>After a couple of years of upgrades, my old workstation reached a limit and another upgrade would not make me benefit so much, so I decided that is time to move to an entire new workstation. As usual I started to look around to decide what to buy to avoid spending big money, while having a good increase of performances.
Here is what I bought after some month of ranting against Intel, because bug in chipset of Sandy Bridge based processor motherboard had delayed my new system of 3 month.</description></item></channel></rss>