<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SSD on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/ssd/</link><description>Recent content in SSD on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 08:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/ssd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Samsung EVO 840 500GB VS OCZ Vertex 4 256GB</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/02/samsung-evo-840-500gb-vs-ocz-vertex-4-256gb/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/02/samsung-evo-840-500gb-vs-ocz-vertex-4-256gb/</guid><description>I’ve decided to move to a 500 GB SSD to have plenty of space to store my virtual machines. At the time of the decision, Samsung EVO was the better option. I’ve posted in the past benchmarks for my Vertex4 256 GB
And I was really curious about performance of Samsung EVO. Vertex 4 has a real impressive write speed, even if after one year of use if you test it again you can find a decrease in performance.</description></item><item><title>OCZ Vertex 3 Vs Vertex4</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/03/ocz-vertex-3-vs-vertex4/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/03/ocz-vertex-3-vs-vertex4/</guid><description>I own both a Vertex3 256GB and a Vertex 4 256, and people usually ask me if the vertex 4 is really faster than vertex 3, or difference in performance are really little. I think it is difficult to answer this question, I can only post you Cristal Diskmark test for both drive when they are completely empty.
This is the Vertex 3
And this is the Vertex 4</description></item><item><title>Vertex 4 vs vertex 3 OCZ Hard disks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/vertex-4-vs-vertex-3-ocz-hard-disks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/vertex-4-vs-vertex-3-ocz-hard-disks/</guid><description>My new Vertex4 SSD is just arrived, I bought essentially to upgrade my laptop that has an old OCZ vertex2 drive 120 GB. I was constantly striving to make room for my virtual machines, so I decided that it was time to upgrade it to a 240GB SSD disk. As soon as my vertex 4 is arrived I immediately upgraded the firmware and run some benchmark
Figure 1: Benchmark of Vertex4 empty drive with firmware 1.</description></item><item><title>The real price of hardware</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/02/the-real-price-of-hardware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/02/the-real-price-of-hardware/</guid><description>I bought a Vertex 3 240GB SSD drive for 270€ VAT included and some of my friend told that this is an expensive drive and they do not want to spend so much money for a Drive. The problem is how you use your hardware, in my life I work as a software consultant, and I spent most of the time in front of a computer compiling and programming and if spending 270€ can make my work more productive it worth the money I spent, because I can work faster.</description></item><item><title>Pay attention where you attach your SSD Driver</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/02/pay-attention-where-you-attach-your-ssd-driver/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/02/pay-attention-where-you-attach-your-ssd-driver/</guid><description>I blogged a couple of days ago about my new Vertex3 SSD Disk, and I gave a screenshot of the CrystalDiskmark result, that I report here for the sake of discussion.
Yesterday I decided to work on my laptop while I did a fresh windows 7 install on the new disk, then I installed everything and finally re-run Crystal Diskmark again…. and I got a really different result. I did not take a screenshot, but basically I got a 350MB/sec sequential read and and an awful 150 MB/Sec on write 4K QD32, that basically is one of the reason why I choose Vertex 3 disk.</description></item><item><title>Difference between various SSD</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/02/difference-between-various-ssd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/02/difference-between-various-ssd/</guid><description>Some time ago I posted some benchmark of my SSD, this is the result I got from my Intel X25-M
It is a really good result compared to a standard disk, expecially in the 4K and 4K QD32, now I bought a Vertex 3 SSD 240 GB and first of all I run again diskmark to see if it is really faster respect my old Intel X25-M, and result are awesome.</description></item><item><title>Time to upgrade my Disks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/10/time-to-upgrade-my-disks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/10/time-to-upgrade-my-disks/</guid><description>I always love to have fast computer and sadly enough, the slowest part is always the HD. In my desktop computer I reach a good compromise with three 10.000 RPM Raptor disk, but in the laptop, having a single 7.200 RPM&amp;hellip; it is simply a pain.
This morning I was reading an old post of Jeff, that reminds me of the existence of Hybrid HD drives :). Basically at very low price you can buy an HD that is surely not fast as an SSD, but is better than a simple 7.</description></item></channel></rss>