<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EverydayLife on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/everydaylife/</link><description>Recent content in EverydayLife on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 10:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/everydaylife/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unable to use Android Emulator error ADBVENDORKEY</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/09/unable-to-use-android-emulator-error-adb_vendor_key/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/09/unable-to-use-android-emulator-error-adb_vendor_key/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m working with Xamarin, but in my workstation, where my user has no administrative right, I’m not capable of running the emulator, even if I start everything with administrative user.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Device unauthorieze ADB_VENDOR_KEY is not set&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/image-23.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/image_thumb-23.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/image_thumb-23.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Figure 1&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>: &lt;em>Error running the emulator.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a really similar identical setup on another computer, where the user is admin of the machine and everythign work. I’ve found some solution on the internet, but nothing worked, until I found some clue on the fact that, this error is somewhat related to google store.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to security expose my test TFS on the internet</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/09/how-to-security-expose-my-test-tfs-on-the-internet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/09/how-to-security-expose-my-test-tfs-on-the-internet/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m not a security expert, but I have a basic knowledge on the argument, so when it is time to expose my test TFS on the outside world I took some precautions. First of all this is a test TFS instance that is running in my test network, it is not a production instance and I need to access it only sometimes when I’m outside my network.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of mapping 8080 port on my firewall I’ve deployed a Linux machine, enabled SSH and added google two factor authentication, then I expose port 22 on another external port. Thanks to this, the only port that is exposed on my router is a port that remap on port 22 on my linux instance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rename xmlrpcphp on your WordPress installation</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/12/rename-xmlrpc-php-on-your-wordpress-installation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/12/rename-xmlrpc-php-on-your-wordpress-installation/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last month my Live Writer stopped being able to publish on this blog. Using Fiddler I discovered that I got an error calling xmlrpc.php. I’ve opened a ticket on my blog hosting, and the support told me that &lt;strong>access to xmlrpc.php was blocked on that machine (my blog is on a shared host) because of spam attack&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem is, malicious script try continuously to send spam content to WordPress blogs using standard API and this usually causes a spike in CPU usage. For this reason many providers block access to xmlrpc.php file.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cleaning up your WSUS Server</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/08/cleaning-up-your-wsus-server/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/08/cleaning-up-your-wsus-server/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-situation">The situation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I’ve a WSUS server that is up and running for last 2 years, it runs on a HP Proliant Microserver where I have a domain controller for my test lab. The purpose of WSUS Server is reducing download time for updates when I install test VMs. I’ve lots of Test VM, and the time needed to download updates is really great, so I’ve decided to configure a WSUS server to mitigate that problem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Windows Server 2012 R2 switching to AHCI after installation</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/08/windows-server-2012-r2-switching-to-ahci-after-installation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/08/windows-server-2012-r2-switching-to-ahci-after-installation/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve installed some weeks ago a new server, and at the time of installation I did the really bad error of not fully checking BIOS settings. This week I moved a couple of SSD to that server, because it will be used for virtualization, and I did noticed that my Vertex 4 is performing really slower respect the original system, so I immediately checked and verified that &lt;strong>I forgot to enable AHCI in the BIOS&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Samsung EVO 840 500GB VS OCZ Vertex 4 256GB</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/02/samsung-evo-840-500gb-vs-ocz-vertex-4-256gb/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/02/samsung-evo-840-500gb-vs-ocz-vertex-4-256gb/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve decided to move to a 500 GB SSD to have plenty of space to store my virtual machines. At the time of the decision, Samsung EVO was the better option. I’ve posted in the past benchmarks for my Vertex4 256 GB&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/SNAGHTMLa0b84_thumb.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/SNAGHTMLa0b84_thumb.png" alt="External Image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I was really curious about performance of Samsung EVO. Vertex 4 has a real impressive write speed, even if after one year of use if you test it again you can find a decrease in performance. Running test on the Evo gave me these results.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Upgrade HP Proliant Microserver N54L Gen7 to Windows Server 2012 troubleshoot</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/11/upgrade-hp-proliant-microserver-n54l-gen7-to-windows-server-2012-troubleshoot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/11/upgrade-hp-proliant-microserver-n54l-gen7-to-windows-server-2012-troubleshoot/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sadly enough if you try to upgrade your Proliant Microserver N54L (or N40L) to Windows Server 2012 R2 &lt;strong>you probably got stuck after the third reboot at 84% when it is time to install computer devices&lt;/strong>. The problem is caused by the NIC firmare that is not compatible with Server 2012 R2. Luckly enough, HP just released a patch of the firmware to address this problem, you can find more info in &lt;a href="http://h30499.www3.hp.com/t5/ProLiant-Servers-Netservers/Windows-Server-2012-R2-on-HP-Microserver-N36L-N40L-N54L/td-p/6237457#.UpWhUHl3taR">the last post of this thread&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Really impressed by AspNix web hosting</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/08/really-impressed-by-aspnix-web-hosting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/08/really-impressed-by-aspnix-web-hosting/</guid><description>&lt;p>I needed to move my blog on another hosting quickly, and I was puzzled on what hosting to choose. Since I had no much time to evaluate a series of alternative, I asked to some friends for an &lt;strong>hosting that have monthly billing and they directed me towards&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://aspnix.com/">&lt;strong>aspnix&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>. Since I had no time to evaluate alternatives my plan was to move the blog on a cheap monthly plan then evaluate alternatives. I choose  the &lt;a href="https://aspnix.com/web-hosting/windows-starter-hosting/">Windows Starter Web Hosting&lt;/a>, it costs $3.00 at each month but I had also a discount coupon so I paid $2.20 for each month.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Running Three monitors with single video card</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/04/running-three-monitors-with-single-video-card/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/04/running-three-monitors-with-single-video-card/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m a great fan of Three Monitors configuration and I usually have two video cards with a Motherboard that support two PCI Express 16x. This configuration is not the top, unless you really need to have super high video performance using the two Video Card in Crossfire configuration. I’ve also the following problems&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My Motherboard has two Pci Express physically 16x, but the second one is only 4x electrically, and when I use software like snagit, the overall experience is not so smooty.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Old windows update window in Windows 8</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/03/old-windows-update-window-in-windows-8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/03/old-windows-update-window-in-windows-8/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve moved all of my computers to &lt;em>Windows 8&lt;/em> (I’ve used it in my laptop since the beta but the workstation was still in windows 7) and I’m really satisfied with this choice. The only drawback is that you need to find &lt;strong>how to do some old stuff in the old way if you do not like the new way :)&lt;/strong>. I usually do not enable automatic update in Windows, I want only to be notified when updates are available then I proceed to install manually and I’m really used to&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OCZ Vertex 3 Vs Vertex4</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/03/ocz-vertex-3-vs-vertex4/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/03/ocz-vertex-3-vs-vertex4/</guid><description>&lt;p>I own both a Vertex3 256GB and a Vertex 4 256, and people usually ask me if the vertex 4 is really faster than vertex 3, or difference in performance are really little. I think it is difficult to answer this question, I can only post you Cristal Diskmark test for both drive when they are completely empty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the Vertex 3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/SNAGHTML69aa9.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/SNAGHTML69aa9.png" alt="External Image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And this is the Vertex 4&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google probably does not like cloudflare</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/google-probably-does-not-like-cloudflare/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/google-probably-does-not-like-cloudflare/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve signed up months ago for a &lt;a href="http://www.cloudflare.com/">Cloudflare&lt;/a> during a refactoring of my web site, at the same time I changed the theme of the blog, cleaned up a little bit the HTML of the page and optimized few stuffs. I was very satisfied of the gain of performance I got with Cloudflare, but after a month stats of blog started to went down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The trend was continuous, each week traffic is slightly less than previous week and all traffic loss is mostly from Google organic&lt;/em>. I started thinking that &lt;strong>the change to HTML structure I’ve done during refactoring is the root cause of this&lt;/strong> , after a month I realized that wordpress version is old and since this information is visible even in Google Webmaster tools I suspected that Google is penalizing me for having an old version of wordpress (maybe it has some security bug) so I upgraded, but nothing changed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Manipulating Html with HtmlAgilityToolkit does not modify DocumentNodeOuterHtml</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/manipulating-html-with-htmlagilitytoolkit-does-not-modify-documentnode-outerhtml/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/manipulating-html-with-htmlagilitytoolkit-does-not-modify-documentnode-outerhtml/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://htmlagilitypack.codeplex.com/">&lt;strong>Html Agility Pack&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> &lt;strong>is a real good library to manipulate Html with.NET code&lt;/strong> , I used it for years and it is really good. To modify HTML you have a real convenient API where you can choose nodes with XPath and then manipulate with Remove() AddChild() etc etc. One of the caveat of manipulating the Document is that usually a lot of people goes through this path.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Load the document (from disk or in memory string)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Manipulate nodes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Get updated content from DocumentNode.OuterHtml property&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>This seems to be the correct path, because DocumentNode.OuterHtml is the property that contain the full html content of the page, but if you go through this path you will probably be surprised that &lt;strong>modifying internal nodes, does not affect the OuterHtml property of the DocumentNode element&lt;/strong>. The problem arise from the fact that &lt;em>latest version of Html Agility Pack does heavy caching on that property and it gets updated only on specific conditions&lt;/em>. This can lead to unexpected behavior, &lt;strong>sometimes the OuterHtml property reflects the modification, in other situation it does not&lt;/strong>. The annoying stuff is that if you play the code inside the debugger with a lot of variables in Wacth, probably you will find that the property is updated, but when you run the program outside the debugger the behavior is different.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vertex 4 vs vertex 3 OCZ Hard disks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/vertex-4-vs-vertex-3-ocz-hard-disks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/vertex-4-vs-vertex-3-ocz-hard-disks/</guid><description>&lt;p>My new Vertex4 SSD is just arrived, I bought essentially to upgrade my laptop that has an old OCZ vertex2 drive 120 GB. I was constantly striving to make room for my virtual machines, so I decided that it was time to upgrade it to a 240GB SSD disk. As soon as my vertex 4 is arrived I immediately upgraded the firmware and run some benchmark&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/SNAGHTML6a43a.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/SNAGHTML6a43a_thumb.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/SNAGHTML6a43a_thumb.png" alt="SNAGHTML6a43a" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Figure 1&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>: &lt;em>Benchmark of Vertex4 empty drive with firmware 1.5.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>