<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Windows on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/windows/</link><description>Recent content in Windows on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 06:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Elasticsearch and weird unicode char</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/elasticsearch-and-weird-unicode-char/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 06:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/elasticsearch-and-weird-unicode-char/</guid><description>&lt;p>Scenario: you have a software where you have a standard search made in UI for data in a board, then you need to move the search server side (due to the increasing number of object in the board), so &lt;strong>you switch to ElasticSearch to have nice full text functionalities&lt;/strong>. Then you have an exact request: Does ElasticSearch supports searching with Unicode chars? The answer is yes, but then you find that users complains about not being able to search with Unicode chars.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to create a list of non upgradable software for winget</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/winget-update-selective/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/winget-update-selective/</guid><description>&lt;p>Edit: I&amp;rsquo;ve stored &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/alkampfergit/2f662c07df0ca379c8e8e65e588c687b">gist of the script here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Winget is finally &lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/winget-intro/">here&lt;/a> and we can, at least, using a package manager on windows &lt;strong>to simplify application management&lt;/strong>. Everything is good, except that some packages are not ready to be upgraded. &lt;strong>As an example in my system I have python 2.7 and 3.x, winget always try to upgrade 3.x version at each run and messed up my installation&lt;/strong>. At the end of the Nth upgrade of python my Visual Studio code was not able anymore to debug and run python.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Winget is finally a thing</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/winget-intro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/winget-intro/</guid><description>&lt;p>After a really loooooong time, finally Windows has its own &lt;a href="https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/windows-package-manager-1-0/">Package Manager&lt;/a> called Windows Package Manager 1.0. It was firstly announced last year at build, but &lt;strong>with 2021 build conference it was announced that it is now in version 1.0&lt;/strong>. I do not want to do a full coverage of all the features, but simply share why this is a thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Linux users had package managers from almost the beginning, this imply that &lt;strong>to install all of your favorite tools, you can simply use command line to install everything&lt;/strong>. Windows was an Operating System that was not born with Command Line in mind and this reflects negatively on the experience of &amp;ldquo;new machine configuration&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speedup WSUS in your AD (Part 2)</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/speed-up-wsus-part2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/speed-up-wsus-part2/</guid><description>&lt;p>After I did some maintenance on my WSUS &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/speed-up-wsus/">with some tricks&lt;/a> I still had problem, after hours of cleanup, PowerShell script stopped working and constantly gave me a timeout.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a target="_blank" href="../images/wsusl-unable-to-clean.png"> &lt;img src="../images/wsusl-unable-to-clean.png" alt="WSUS was unable to perform cleanup" />&lt;/a>
&lt;em>&lt;strong>Figure 1:&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> &lt;em>WSUS was unable to perform cleanup&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did not had time to investigate the issue, but I got saved in my disk a small notes I&amp;rsquo;ve found somewhere that suggested how to &lt;strong>cleanup manually directly with SQL&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speedup WSUS in your AD</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/speed-up-wsus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/speed-up-wsus/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have a very old HP Proliant Microserver, it has 16 GB of RAM and an SSD, but it is really old, it is powered by a really old Turion CPU and WSUS is starting to becoming unresponsive. That machine act &lt;strong>as a test domain controller for a bunch of test virtual machines&lt;/strong>, WSUS always was a little bit slow, but it worked, until few days ago, when it constantly fails to load data.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>