<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>windows on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/windows/</link><description>Recent content in windows on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 08:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to create a list of non upgradable software for winget</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/winget-update-selective/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/winget-update-selective/</guid><description>Winget is finally here and we can, at least, using a package manager on windows to simplify application management. Everything is good, except that some packages are not ready to be upgraded. As an example in my system I have python 2.7 and 3.x, winget always try to upgrade 3.x version at each run and messed up my installation. At the end of the Nth upgrade of python my Visual Studio code was not able anymore to debug and run python.</description></item><item><title>Winget is finally a thing</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/winget-intro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/winget-intro/</guid><description>After a really loooooong time, finally Windows has its own Package Manager called Windows Package Manager 1.0. It was firstly announced last year at build, but with 2021 build conference it was announced that it is now in version 1.0. I do not want to do a full coverage of all the features, but simply share why this is a thing.
Linux users had package managers from almost the beginning, this imply that to install all of your favorite tools, you can simply use command line to install everything.</description></item><item><title>Speedup WSUS in your AD (Part 2)</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/speed-up-wsus-part2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/speed-up-wsus-part2/</guid><description>After I did some maintenance on my WSUS with some tricks I still had problem, after hours of cleanup, PowerShell script stopped working and constantly gave me a timeout.
Figure 1: WSUS was unable to perform cleanup
I did not had time to investigate the issue, but I got saved in my disk a small notes I&amp;rsquo;ve found somewhere that suggested how to cleanup manually directly with SQL.
1 2 EXEC spGetObsoleteUpdatesToCleanup EXEC spDeleteUpdate @localUpdateID=&amp;lt;LocalUpdateID&amp;gt; In such situation my temptation to wipe out everything and start a new WSUS is really high, but I always resort on spending a little time trying to do some manual tentative.</description></item><item><title>Speedup WSUS in your AD</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/speed-up-wsus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/speed-up-wsus/</guid><description>I have a very old HP Proliant Microserver, it has 16 GB of RAM and an SSD, but it is really old, it is powered by a really old Turion CPU and WSUS is starting to becoming unresponsive. That machine act as a test domain controller for a bunch of test virtual machines, WSUS always was a little bit slow, but it worked, until few days ago, when it constantly fails to load data.</description></item></channel></rss>