<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Automation on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/automation/</link><description>Recent content in Automation on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 08:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pill: Include files in your publish profile for C# projects</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/azdo/pills/msbuild-copy-file/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/azdo/pills/msbuild-copy-file/</guid><description>When publishing an ASP.NET core web project, it&amp;rsquo;s often necessary to include certain files external to the Visual Studio solution but that are logical part of the project. A typical example is frontend build from angular projects. For web projects, it&amp;rsquo;s also common to include some static resources that might be outside of the web project, like images or files.
At this point, we want the Azure DevOps pipeline to correctly include all these external files in the final artifacts.</description></item><item><title>Pill: Enhancing DevOps with Automated Pull Requests</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/azdo/pills/automatic-pull-request-close/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 08:10:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/azdo/pills/automatic-pull-request-close/</guid><description>Pull requests are a cornerstone of collaborative software development, particularly with distributed version control systems like Git and platforms such as GitHub or Azure DevOps. However, managing pull requests can become cumbersome, particularly for branches undergoing extensive modifications and receiving frequent feedback. This complexity is evident when preparing a pull request only to find it needs additional changes due to peer review, necessitating a complete retest of the code.
Such workflows highlight the challenges in finalizing a branch.</description></item></channel></rss>