<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Uncategorized on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/uncategorized/</link><description>Recent content in Uncategorized on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 10:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Slow tests with nunit 24 and nhibernate</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/slow-nunit-24-test-with-nhibernate-maybe-it-is-log-problem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/slow-nunit-24-test-with-nhibernate-maybe-it-is-log-problem/</guid><description>I noticed that when I used nunit 2.4 test runner it is really slower than 2.2. The reason is that in 2.4 the nunit test runner will use log4net as default logger, and if you do not disable logging, you will see in log tab an enormous amount of text.
The reason is that nunit used default log level of “DEBUG”, and this in turn means that nhibernate will run with full logging enabled, and this is a really waste of time because nhibernate really log everything with DEBUG level.</description></item><item><title>Favor small and frequent checkin over big ones</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/favor-small-and-frequent-checkin-over-big-ones/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/favor-small-and-frequent-checkin-over-big-ones/</guid><description>This is a rule that I try to adopt since long time in the past, and few days ago Jeff Atwood enforces this concept in his blog. I completely agree with him, code should be checked in often, especially when you have continuous integration server. Checking in often reduce the risk of conflicts, makes tests run often (you should have setup your continuous server to run all tests for each checkin) and makes integration simplier.</description></item><item><title>Adobe Acrobat new is better or worse</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/adobe-acrobat-new-is-better-or-worse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/adobe-acrobat-new-is-better-or-worse/</guid><description>I’m working with OpenXml format of office 2007, so I keep the reference document open because I constantly need to search information into the document. The reference document is a 5200 huge 37 mb pdf, when I open it in Adobe reader 8 the acrobat process uses 60MB of ram, when I start a search of a text the search is incredibly slow, acrobat begin to use more memory. To make a comparison I try to search the text youcannotfoundThis and after 30 seconds acrobat is still at page 500, and the memory consumption is 125 mb.</description></item><item><title>Really strange error in production server a tale of named pipes</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/really-strange-error-in-production-server-a-tale-of-named-pipes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2008 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/really-strange-error-in-production-server-a-tale-of-named-pipes/</guid><description>I have a production server with an asp.net application, it run for months without errors. 10 days ago the elmah page begins to shows an error that occurred in a lot of pages.
The application uses a standard ado.net Data access Layer, but a module uses nhibernate, and it turns out that all the errors happened when a page use some function in this module. I tried to access some pages in the site that uses nhibernate, and every page raises an error of type.</description></item><item><title>Remove comment moderation</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/remove-comment-moderation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2008 04:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/remove-comment-moderation/</guid><description>I decided to remove comment moderation for the blog. I used it mainly to be sure that no spam pass the filter, but after some months of testing I verify that Akismet really does a good work, intercepting all the spam comments.
Moreover I setup the WP-reCAPTCHA plugin to add a CAPTCHA in the end of the post, making life harder for spammers. I really like to have moderation removed, primarily because I have to check it often to be sure that no comment gets lost, moreover I like that readers can immediately see comments in the post.</description></item><item><title>WordPress and permalink make your url case sensitive</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/wordpress-and-permalink-case-sensitive/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2008 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/wordpress-and-permalink-case-sensitive/</guid><description>This morning I browse some stats that google made on my blog, and saw that there are some 404 (Not Found) page. After some inspection I see that all the 404 have the form
http://www.nablasoft.com/Alkampfer/xxx
They have capital A for Alkampfer, if I changed the Alkampfer in alkampfer everything work……the strange thing is that I perfectly remember that it does work when I first setup the blog. After some inspection I found that the problem is due to the permalink, when you activate permalink in wordpress the url became case sensitive.</description></item><item><title>Overriding the Equals Method for object used as a key in hashtable</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/overriding-the-equalsmethod/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/overriding-the-equalsmethod/</guid><description>Overriding the Equals method is not a stuff for the fainted-hearts; it could seems absolutely a simple thing to do, but there are a lot of subtleties that had to be keep in mind.
Here is a typical implementation of Equals for a Customer entity made by Resharper (R# permits you to define equals with a single click)
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 public class Customer : IEquatable&amp;lt;Customer&amp;gt; { public String Name { get; set; } public String Surname { get; set; } public bool Equals(Customer obj) { if (ReferenceEquals(null, obj)) return false; if (ReferenceEquals(this, obj)) return true; return Equals(obj.</description></item><item><title>Lambda recursion pay attention to performances</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/lambda-recursion-pay-attention-to-performances/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2008 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/lambda-recursion-pay-attention-to-performances/</guid><description>This morning I stumble across this old post, that shows how to create a recursive function with lambda. The article is very interesting and has a second part that deal with memoization. These two articles are really great ones, but I want to point out that you need really pay attention to performance each time you speak about recursion. This piece of code shows an interesting thing
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 class Program { private static Stopwatch sw = new Stopwatch(); static void TestSpeed(Func&amp;lt;int, int&amp;gt; f, int i, string msg) { sw.</description></item><item><title>We love our hardware really true</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/we-love-our-hardware-really-true/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2008 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/we-love-our-hardware-really-true/</guid><description>As Jeff Atwood says “we love computers”, yes, we are developer, but in the end we choose this profession because is the one that make us possible to work with the object of our love…computer.
I’m one of those person that build his development machine, I want to choose every pieces of hardware, and this is mainly because I worked as a technician during my university period, so I used to work with a lot of different hardware, and I cannot think to own a computer that is “packaged by someone else”, each part of my pc is there because I want it to be there.</description></item><item><title>WCF services and silverlight</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/wcf-services-and-silverlight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2008 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/wcf-services-and-silverlight/</guid><description>I’m doing the first steps with silverlight, and today I incurred in a very strange behavior. First of all I see that in my web project I can add WCF service or Silverlight-enabled WCF services. My first thought was…”why a wcf service should be different for silverlight”?
The only difference is that with a silverlight enabled wcf you will get a service already configured in a very specific way. First of all it does not use the separation of the interface, so you have only the service class like an old asmx service, moreover it configures web.</description></item><item><title>Current directory in a library that should work for aspnet and windows app</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/current-directory-in-a-library-that-should-work-for-aspnet-and-windows-app/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2008 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/current-directory-in-a-library-that-should-work-for-aspnet-and-windows-app/</guid><description>Suppose you created a library that needs to scan the “current directory” looking for some files, first solution that came in my mind was to use Enviroment.CurrentDirectory, but this is not correct. In a web.application or windows service you will find that CurrentDirectory is c:\windows\system32.
I need a generic way to find a file that is located in the same path of the executables in a windows app, and in base directory for a web.</description></item><item><title>Generate RTF library in NET</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/generate-rtf-library-in-net/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2008 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/generate-rtf-library-in-net/</guid><description>This rtf generator is one of my first projects in.net, it started in Visual studio 2002 :D, then it was converted to visual studio 2003 and.net 1.1. Some time ago one of the developer of my team ask me if I know a quick way to generate an rtf file from asp.net, so I simply say
“Hey, I have this really old library of mine…..you can try at your own risk :D”</description></item><item><title>error MSB3323 Unable to find manifest signing certificate in the certificate store and CCNEt</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/error-msb3323-unable-to-find-manifest-signing-certificate-in-the-certificate-store-and-ccnet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2008 04:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/error-msb3323-unable-to-find-manifest-signing-certificate-in-the-certificate-store-and-ccnet/</guid><description>This morning I did some modification to a project that is deployed with click once, I checked in and the build was broken. I go to CC.NET dashboard and I see that the error is
error MSB3323 Unable to find manifest signing certificate in the certificate store
I tried to do various experiments, but after half hour I came to the solution, simply go to the Project Properties, Signing tab, then I deselect “Sign the ClickOnce manifest” and check it again, all works well again.</description></item><item><title>Find value of ASPNET ObjectDataSource or SqlDataSource at runtime</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/find-value-of-aspnet-objectdatasource-or-sqldatasource-at-runtime/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/find-value-of-aspnet-objectdatasource-or-sqldatasource-at-runtime/</guid><description>I must admit that I do not like very much the XXXDataSource control of ASP.NET 2.0 library, but the ObjectDataSource is sometimes a quick solution to interface the UI with own LogicLayer.
In a recent project I have a complex page that set up some complex filter for data in a Sql Server engine, the logic of filtering is exposed by an object queried by an ObjectDataSource. this DataSource has QueryString Parameters, Control Parameter, and some other custom parameter to take parameter value from other sources.</description></item><item><title>Using a single ModalPopupExtender to show Dynamic Complex Data</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/using-a-single-modalpopupextender-to-show-dynamic-complex-data/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/using-a-single-modalpopupextender-to-show-dynamic-complex-data/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m not a javascript fan, but sometimes I have the need to write some client script code, to make the application more responsive.
In a project I was working on, we have the main page with a gridview that shows 15 components at time, each component has really a lot of information to show to the user, so the first version uses the ModalPopupExtender from AjaxControlToolkit to move in a popup the extended informations.</description></item><item><title>Simple skinnable and Theme management in WPF user interface</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/simple-skinnable-and-theme-management-in-wpf-user-interface/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2008 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/simple-skinnable-and-theme-management-in-wpf-user-interface/</guid><description>A skinnable interface is the gotha of the user interface, the developer use standard control and set the behaviour, the designer skin it with some tool and creates a beautiful user interface. In WPF this is possible thanks to XAML and styles, but it is possible to simple include in an application a series of skin and load at runtime??. The answer is Yes, it is possible.
Let’s Start with a simple page with a combo and a textblock</description></item><item><title>Delegates and Rhino Mocks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/delegates-and-rhino-mocks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/delegates-and-rhino-mocks/</guid><description>I love delegates, with c# 2.0 anonymous delegates and with C# 3.0 lambda, working with delegates is simply wonderful. Anonymous delegates makes possible to create closure, and I like to use delegate in a lot of places. When you have to test objects that accepts external delegates Rhino Mock is simply exceptional, here is a test I write this afternoon
1 2 3 4 5 6 MultiRange sut1 = CreateMultiRange(50, &amp;#34;pippo&amp;#34;, 100, &amp;#34;pluto&amp;#34;); MultiRange sut2 = CreateMultiRange(60, &amp;#34;ted&amp;#34;); MultiRange.</description></item><item><title>XmlDocument XmlResolver and cache the schema of XHTML</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/xmldocument-xmlresolver-and-cache-the-schema-of-xhtml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/xmldocument-xmlresolver-and-cache-the-schema-of-xhtml/</guid><description>I’m working with a class created by my colleague, this class has a function that accept a uri, a string (that represent the content of a page) and tells me if in that string there are some links to an RssFeed. I have a full page content store in files, so I simply load files one by one and then pass to this function.
It seems to me that the execution is quite slow and looking into fiddler I found that almost each file I pass to the function the function download some files related to xml schema.</description></item><item><title>Loading dictionary of resources runtime in WPF</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/loading-dictionary-of-resources-runtime-in-wpf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/loading-dictionary-of-resources-runtime-in-wpf/</guid><description>This morning I had a little task, I’going to a Customer to install a simple WPF application in a touch screen. The problem is: I do not know how the customer want to format the form: font, color and so on. The problem is that I do not want to setup a procedural code to change these setting runtime, I only want to change the first time, then all goes on forever with that settings.</description></item><item><title>XamlReader quotMissing XmlNamespace Assembly or ClrNamespace in Mapping instructionquot</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/xamlreader-missing-xmlnamespace-assembly-or-clrnamespace-in-mapping-instruction/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/xamlreader-missing-xmlnamespace-assembly-or-clrnamespace-in-mapping-instruction/</guid><description>This post is a clarification of the preceding post.
If you try to load XAML file at runtime with the XamlReader it is important that you specify the full assembly if the file contain reference to local defined object. As an example, if I use a custom IValueConverter defined in my assembly, the cyder designer can generate such a XAML file for a resource
1 2 3 &amp;lt;ResourceDictionary xmlns=&amp;#34;http://schemas.microsoft.com/winfx/2006/xaml/presentation&amp;#34; xmlns:x=&amp;#34;http://schemas.</description></item><item><title>A simple try for the KickIt plugin</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/a-simple-try-for-the-kickit-plugin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2008 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/a-simple-try-for-the-kickit-plugin/</guid><description>The DotNetKicks community is really new for me, But I decided to try to contribute, and I found a really interesting plugin for Windows Live Writer here. I’ve installed also the WordPress related plugin, so let’s see if all works.
Tags: DotNetKicks
Alk.</description></item><item><title>FeedBurner stats</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/feedburner-stats/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2008 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/feedburner-stats/</guid><description>This morning I had a great surprise, I saw in feedburner 103 readers of my blog, it is really great for me to reach three digit count :D, it means that my blog interests some people. 103 is not such a great number, but thinking that in the world 100 person are interested in what I’m saying is really exiting. Hope to raise this stat in the future, thanks to everyone, have a great day.</description></item><item><title>Technorati tags</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/technorati-tags/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2008 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/technorati-tags/</guid><description>I realized that technorati tags does not work well in my blog, if I click in tags cloud technorati tells me that are no post with that tag. I’ll investigate the problem
alk.
Tags: Technorati
Tags</description></item><item><title>Blog upgrade</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/blog-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2008 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/blog-upgrade/</guid><description>I must admit that wordpress is really exceptional, in few minutes I upgraded my blog to the new version. Now I hope that everything is ok! :D
Alk.
Tags: WordPress</description></item><item><title>LINQ to XML 8211 really interesting</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/linq-to-xml-really-interesting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/linq-to-xml-really-interesting/</guid><description>A lot of people tend to consider linq2sql the most important provider for linq, this is not true for me. First of all I tend to prefer NHibernate over Entity Framework and LINQ2SQL, and moreover I think that Linq 2 XML really rocks.
If you worked like me with XML you probably are frustrated of the many api you have to deal with: you have to know XPATH 1.0 and 2.</description></item><item><title>Entity Framework span and eager fetch</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/entity-framework-spam-and-eager-fetch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/entity-framework-spam-and-eager-fetch/</guid><description>Some minutes ago I posted about the Entity Framework and fetching strategy. After a little search in the documentation, I finally found how to prefetch using a concept called * span *. Here is a LINQ query that load a department eagerly fetching the courses collection
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 var query = from d in conn.Department.Include(&amp;#34;Course&amp;#34;) where d.Name == &amp;#34;Economics&amp;#34; select d; foreach (Department dep in query) { Console.</description></item><item><title>error MSB3464</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/error-msb3464/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2008 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/error-msb3464/</guid><description>Today I was creating some nant build to automate the deploy of a webproject, I use the wdproj extension for visual studio 2005 to create a web deployment project, then I add a task to the nant script to simply build the wdproj with msbuild.exe.
The script give me error MSB3464, it turns out that I call msbuild with the parameter /p:Platform=&amp;quot;Any CPU&amp;rdquo; and this was the cause of the problem.</description></item><item><title>Technorati tags does not work</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/technorati-tags-does-not-work/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2008 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/technorati-tags-does-not-work/</guid><description>This is a test to technorati Tags, It seems that technorati tags does not work anymore.
Technorati Tags: Technorati
Tags: Technorati</description></item><item><title>CCNEt and error in file ccnetconfig</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/ccnet-and-error-in-file-ccnetconfig/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2008 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/ccnet-and-error-in-file-ccnetconfig/</guid><description>Sometimes it happens that editing xml file ccnet.config you can made some mistake, if for example the xml is not well formed, the cc.net server simply ignore the change.
As a rule of thumb, when I make modification in ccnet.config file I stopped the server, modify the file and then launch ccnet.exe from commandline, in this way I can easily find any error in the config. When the config is ok I start the service again.</description></item><item><title>Test post</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/03/test-post/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2008 01:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/03/test-post/</guid><description>I have moved to a new computer this is a test post.
Alk.</description></item><item><title>IQueryable</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/03/iqueryable/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 01:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/03/iqueryable/</guid><description>Implementing IQueryable is not a joke, here there is an excellent tutorial. I’m actually playing on Linq2Nhibernate by ayende and I realize that traversing an Expression Tree is not so painful, but surely complicated.
Alk.</description></item><item><title>Linq to Sqlworking with detached object 82308230</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/03/linq-to-sqlworking-with-detatched-object/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2008 01:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/03/linq-to-sqlworking-with-detatched-object/</guid><description>Linq to Sql is beautiful, but for people using NHibernate sometimes there are surprises. Suppose you load an entity, then you keep a reference in memory, dispose the original DataContext, and after some time you want to propagate to the database the value of the modified entity.
In NHibernate this is simple as calling SaveOrUpdate() method, in Linq2SQL you can call Attach() on the table you want to attach the object.</description></item><item><title>C 30 Expression Trees</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/02/c-30-expression-trees/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2008 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/02/c-30-expression-trees/</guid><description>One of the most impressing features of C# 3.0 are Lamba expression, because they are *not only syntactic sugar.*If you are not convinced try to run the following two pieces of codes in LINQ to SQL
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 FirstTestDataContext context = new FirstTestDataContext(); context.Log = Console.Out; IEnumerable&amp;lt;Customer&amp;gt; custs = context.Customers .Where(C =&amp;gt; C.CustomerID.StartsWith(&amp;#34;A&amp;#34;)); Console.WriteLine(&amp;#34;Recuperati {0} oggetti Customer&amp;#34;, custs.Count()); custs = context.Customers .Where(delegate(Customer C) { return C.</description></item><item><title>Nant and The specified solution configuration Debugmcd is invalid</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/02/nant-and-the-specified-solution-configuration-debugmcd-is-invalid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2008 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/02/nant-and-the-specified-solution-configuration-debugmcd-is-invalid/</guid><description>Today a friend of mine tell me that in his new windows vista computer one nant scritp stopped working giving the error The specified solution configuration “Debug|MCD” is invalid during the msbuild part of the script. After a brief search it turns out that the msbuild command line is not correct because it miss the /p:Platform instruction, my command line now is
1 2 3 &amp;lt;exec program=&amp;#34;${MSBuild}&amp;#34; commandline=&amp;#39; ${ProjectDir}\${BuildSolutionName} /verbosity:quiet /T:rebuild /p:Configuration=Debug /p:Platform=&amp;#34;Any CPU&amp;#34;&amp;#39; basedir=&amp;#34;.</description></item><item><title>sgenexe and strongly named assemblies</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/02/sgenexe-and-strongly-named-assemblies/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2008 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/02/sgenexe-and-strongly-named-assemblies/</guid><description>Today I was facing a strange exception with a XmlSerializer, it gives to me FileNotFoundException NHibernate.XmlSerializers, it turns out that the debug settings are set to “break to all exceptions” and so the visual studio Ide warn me even for handled exception.
After some search I found that the xxxx.XmlSerializers assembly is a pregenerated assembly that the xmlserializers looks for before attempting to generate one at runtime, so if you want to have better performance you can pregenerate such an assembly.</description></item><item><title>Parse a date in NET</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/parse-a-date-in-net/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2007 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/parse-a-date-in-net/</guid><description>Today I had a little bug in an application of mine, I have a routine that accepts a series of parameter through a comma separated string of values, this kind of interface to a function is not a good thing to do, expecially when DateTime variables are transmitted, but this is an old routine and worked well for a while, so I did not refactor.
The problem is arising now when the application build another function on top of this routine.</description></item><item><title>Padding is invalid and cannot be removed</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/padding-is-invalid-and-cannot-be-removed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2007 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/padding-is-invalid-and-cannot-be-removed/</guid><description>After another release of our project in production machine sometimes I see in the log this strange error
System.Security.Cryptography.CryptographicException: Padding is invalid and cannot be removed.
System.Security.Cryptography.CryptographicException: Padding is invalid and cannot be removed.
at System.Security.Cryptography.RijndaelManagedTransform.DecryptData(Byte[] inputBuffer, Int32 inputOffset, Int32 inputCount, Byte[]&amp;amp; outputBuffer, Int32 outputOffset, PaddingMode paddingMode, Boolean fLast)
at System.Security.Cryptography.RijndaelManagedTransform.TransformFinalBlock(Byte[] inputBuffer, Int32 inputOffset, Int32 inputCount)
at System.Security.Cryptography.CryptoStream.FlushFinalBlock()
at System.Web.Configuration.MachineKeySection.EncryptOrDecryptData(Boolean fEncrypt, Byte[] buf, Byte[] modifier, Int32 start, Int32 length, Boolean useValidationSymAlgo)</description></item><item><title>WatiN looking for content in GridView</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/watin-looking-for-content-in-gridview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2007 04:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/watin-looking-for-content-in-gridview/</guid><description>Quite often I need to automate test page and check that the contents of a GridView contains exactly some strings. First of all I have an helper class that helps me to cope with the name that asp.net give to controls contained in another controls, then I write some helper methods to assert that the content of a grid is what I expected to be.
publicstaticvoid TableContentEqAssertion(IE ie, String tableName, Int32 row, Int32 col, String expectedvalue) {</description></item><item><title>How to format code blogging with word 2007</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/05/how-to-format-code-blogging-with-word-2007/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2007 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/05/how-to-format-code-blogging-with-word-2007/</guid><description>Today I was trying to blog with word 2007 and I found some difficulties with code. First of all I suggest you to install a Visual Studio Plugin that enable a “copy source as HTML” option that permits you to copy the code as HTML and this makes the life easier. The problem is that simply pasting the code into word will produce some strange results
3”’ &amp;lt;summary&amp;gt;
4”’ classe base per la definizione di proprietÃ comuni</description></item><item><title>Test of blog publishing with Microsoft word 2007</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/04/test-of-blog-publishing-with-microsoft-word-2007/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2007 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/04/test-of-blog-publishing-with-microsoft-word-2007/</guid><description>This post is created using Microsoft word 2007. Let’s see if this makes blogging simpler. First of all some formatting bold italic.
This is indented with tab.
Some ordered item Another ordered item A bullet list Another element of the bullet list Some weird code in VB.NET
1 &amp;lt;AspNetHostingPermission(SecurityAction.LinkDemand, Level:=AspNetHostingPermissionLevel.Minimal), _
2 AspNetHostingPermission(SecurityAction.InheritanceDemand, Level:=AspNetHostingPermissionLevel.Minimal), _
3 ToolboxData(“&amp;lt;{0}:MultipleFieldsValidator runat=server&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/{0}:MultipleFieldsValidator&amp;gt;”)&amp;gt; _
4PublicClass MultipleControlsValidator
5Inherits BaseValidator
6
7 &amp;lt;Browsable(False), _</description></item><item><title>Hello world</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/04/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2007 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/04/hello-world/</guid><description>Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start blogging!</description></item></channel></rss>