<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Virtual Machine on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/virtual-machine/</link><description>Recent content in Virtual Machine on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 17:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/virtual-machine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using vmWare machine when you have Hyper-V</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/10/using-vmware-machine-when-you-have-hyper-v/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/10/using-vmware-machine-when-you-have-hyper-v/</guid><description>There are lots of VM containing Demo, Labs etc around the internet and surely Hyper-V is not the primary target as virtualization system. This because it is present on desktop OS only from Windows 8, it is not free (present in windows professional) and bound to windows. If you have to create a VM to share in internet, 99% of the time you want to target vmWare or Virtual Box and a linux guest system (no license needed).</description></item><item><title>Esxi Hyper-V and Linux</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/12/esxi-hyper-v-and-linux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/12/esxi-hyper-v-and-linux/</guid><description>I mainly use Hyper-V to virtualize my test environments and I’m really happy with it, the only problem is virtualizing Linux Desktop environments, especially if you have monitors with higher resolution than Full-HD (since in Hyper-V I’ve not found a way to run with a greater resolution than Full HD).
To overcome this limitation, I’ve converted my old workstation in a virtualization host running VMWare ESXi and I’m really satisfied. Here is a couple of tricks that I’ve learned (I’m a completely new to latest version of ESXi).</description></item><item><title>Avoid expiring of Brian Keller VS2010 virtual machine</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/11/avoid-expiring-of-brian-keller-vs2010-virtual-machine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/11/avoid-expiring-of-brian-keller-vs2010-virtual-machine/</guid><description>Brian Keller always does a great work releasing a Demo Machine with all the goodness of VS2010 and TFS2010, really useful for making demo and courses. The only drawback is that this machine expires after 6 months, and if you did some customization on it, or prepared some customized hands-on-lab, you usually need to do everything again with the new machine. (Brian release a new machine updated with the latest tool some days before the expiration of the old machine).</description></item><item><title>Multi monitor remote desktop on a Windows 7 virtual machine</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/multi-monitor-remote-desktop-on-a-windows-7-virtual-machine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/multi-monitor-remote-desktop-on-a-windows-7-virtual-machine/</guid><description>To test dev 11 preview I’ve setup several virtual machines, just to be sure not to ruin my main installation box, since dev 11 is a developer previewand is not a good idea installing pre-beta release on production machine (even if dev 11 preview is really stable).
One of the annoying stuff in running inside a virtual machine is losing the ability to use all of your monitors… or not? If the virtualized and host operating system are Windows7 or Windows Server 2008, you can connect to the virtual machine using Remote Desktop (remember to enable it on windows7 because is not enabled by default), because it has full support for multiple monitors.</description></item><item><title>Convert Brian Keller dev11 Virtual Machine to vmWare</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/convert-brian-keller-dev11-virtual-machine-to-vmware/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2011 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/convert-brian-keller-dev11-virtual-machine-to-vmware/</guid><description>The Brian Keller’s Virtual Machine with all the goodness of dev11 developer preview is an Hyper-V one, so if you have a windows 7 environment (like me) you cannot use it. A possible solution is using a Virtual Disk converter like the Starwind one (http://www.starwindsoftware.com/download-starwind-converter) that permits you to convert a.VHD hyper-v virtual disk to a standard VmWare disk, then you can create a new VmWare virtual machine, use the converted disk and everything should be ok.</description></item></channel></rss>