<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sonarcloud on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/sonarcloud/</link><description>Recent content in sonarcloud on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 08:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/sonarcloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Analyze Python project with SonarCloud and GitHub</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/github/python-sonarcloud-actions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/github/python-sonarcloud-actions/</guid><description>SonarCloud is free for Open Source projects, and for languages like Python, that does not need compilation, it can directly analyze the repository without any intervention from the author. This feature is automatically enabled when you setup your Project in SonarCloud and it determines that you have not compiled language.
Figure 1: Analysis configuration shows that in this project we have CI analysis
If you look at Figure you can see that in my situation I have a Continuous Integration based analysis and my automatic analysis is disabled.</description></item><item><title>Sonar Cloud analysis in GitHub</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/github/github-sonar-cloud/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/github/github-sonar-cloud/</guid><description>Well, you know me, I like to have my code analyzed by SonarCloud when possible, and since it is free for open source, I always use Azure DevOps pipeline to automatically analyze code on each push. Now that GitHub actions are available, a good solution is to simply use GitHub actions to analyze code, without disturbing Azure DevOps.
Azure DevOps pipelines are, in my opinion, more mature than GitHub actions, but for small tasks, it is simpler to go with Actions.</description></item></channel></rss>