<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ApplicationInsights on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/applicationinsights/</link><description>Recent content in ApplicationInsights on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 16:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/applicationinsights/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Application insight Snapshot debugger and strange production problem</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/07/application-insight-snapshot-debugger-and-strange-production-problem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/07/application-insight-snapshot-debugger-and-strange-production-problem/</guid><description>I want to share with you an history of a problem we had in production last week, because after lots of internet search no article lead us to find the solution, so I hope that this article can help you if you experience the very same problem.
Situation: we deployed new version of a web application based on ASP.NET Web API, it was a small increment (we deploy frequently), but suddenly the customer starts experiencing slowness of the application and intermittent errors.</description></item><item><title>Application insight real life avoid sending garbage to AI instance</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/03/application-insight-real-life-avoid-sending-garbage-to-ai-instance/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/03/application-insight-real-life-avoid-sending-garbage-to-ai-instance/</guid><description>Application Insight is a real nice azure service that allows you to instrument your application to have a complete set of telemetries and problem diagnostics. Usually when you start using Application Insight, you also have some log in place (log4net, serilog) and you want to integrate logs with AI so some kind of logs (Ex errors) will be automatically send to AI.
All these log libraries allows you to write a sink / appender to send logs to your chosen destination, thus, sending all your serilog / log4net logs to application insight is usually a matter of minutes.</description></item><item><title>Application insights installation</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/03/application-insights-installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 12:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/03/application-insights-installation/</guid><description>I’ve already covered installation of Monitoring Agent for Visual Studio Online Application Insights. Actually the service is in preview and the setup experience is changed from the first one. At date of Today, during installation phase, setup asks you the type of agent you need, but it does not asks you if you want to automatically monitor all of your web application. After the installation you can configure Microsoft Monitoring Agent from Control Panel</description></item><item><title>Application Insights on Visual Studio Online</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/02/application-insights-on-visual-studio-online/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/02/application-insights-on-visual-studio-online/</guid><description>Continuous deploy on Test and PreProduction server was always an argument that fascinates me a lot. The ability to have latest version of the code up and Running in a Test environment is a must for every developing team. I’ve wrote some articles in the past on how to obtain such result for Web Sites and TFS.
Deploying on AzureWebSites from on-premise Team Foundation Server Deploy Asp Net web Sites on IIS from Team Foundation Server Build Manage Test Data in Visual Studio Database Project Continuous Deployment on Windows Azure Web Sites with Database Projects Build, Deploy, Web Performance test with TFS Build Now that you are able to automatically deploy a Web Site you need a way to monitor your site to verify what is happening during testing and beta phase.</description></item></channel></rss>