<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lab Management on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/lab-management/</link><description>Recent content in Lab Management on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 18:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/lab-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Error in AsyncProcessMessage during deploy phase of a TFS Lab Management Build</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/02/error-in-asyncprocessmessage-during-deploy-phase-of-a-tfs-lab-management-build/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/02/error-in-asyncprocessmessage-during-deploy-phase-of-a-tfs-lab-management-build/</guid><description>I have a customer that experiences this error during a build with Lab Management:
Exception Message: Team Foundation Server could not complete the deployment task for machine xxx ….Server stack trace: at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.Lab.Workflow.Activities.RunDeploymentTask.ExecuteDeploymentTask.RunCommand(AsyncState state) at System.Runtime.Remoting.Messaging.StackBuilderSink._PrivateProcessMessage(IntPtr md, Object[] args, Object server, Object[]&amp;amp; outArgs) at System.Runtime.Remoting.Messaging.StackBuilderSink.AsyncProcessMessage(IMessage msg, IMessageSink replySink)Exception rethrown at [0]: at System.Runtime.Remoting.Proxies.RealProxy.EndInvokeHelper(Message reqMsg, Boolean bProxyCase) at System.Runtime.Remoting.Proxies.RemotingProxy.Invoke(Object NotUsed, MessageData&amp;amp; msgData) at System.Action`1.EndInvoke(IAsyncResult result) at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.Lab.Workflow.Activities.RunDeploymentTask.ExecuteDeploymentTask.EndExecute(AsyncCodeActivityContext context, IAsyncResult result) at System.</description></item><item><title>Lab management release date</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/08/lab-management-release-date/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/08/lab-management-release-date/</guid><description>Lab Management is surely one of the most exiting new feature for TFS 2010 and now we finally have a Release Date.
Since Lab Management is really a complex set of tools, even if it is in the iso images of TFS 2010 is still considered to be in release candidate version. Now we can announce two big news
RTM Bits will be released at the end of August Lab managements will be avaliable even in MSDN Ultimate or TestProfessional with MSDN The second news is very well welcomed, because it widen the number of people that could benefit from Lab Management.</description></item><item><title>Deploy a solution and a database in a Lab Management Virtual Environment</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/deploy-a-solution-and-a-database-in-a-lab-management-virtual-environment/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/deploy-a-solution-and-a-database-in-a-lab-management-virtual-environment/</guid><description>One of the coolest feature of Tfs2010 is Lab Management, an infrastructure tool that permits you to manage Virtual Environment to test your applications. Once you have defined some template machine in SCVMM you can import them into your Lab to be used in defining Virtual Environment.
When you imported all the templates you need from SCVMM, to create a new environment you simply need to go to Environment tab, and create new virtual environment, then you can choose VM template to compose a test environment, like in the following picture where I choose three machine, a web server, a db server and a client machine.</description></item><item><title>Lab management TF267042 and dns configuration</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/lab-management-tf267042-and-dns-configuration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/lab-management-tf267042-and-dns-configuration/</guid><description>Today I configured an environment in lab management, when it finishes the deploy phase I see that the machine has testing capabilities Error and the details of the error is
The real error is the TF267055
he machine is not ready to run tests because of the following error: Unable to connect to the controller on labrtmhost.tfslab.nablasoft.com:6901′. Reason: A connection attempt failed because the connected party did not properly respond after a period of time&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip; host has failed to respond 10.</description></item><item><title>Configuring Lab Management on a single machine</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/error-when-configuring-lab-management-on-a-single-machine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2010 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/error-when-configuring-lab-management-on-a-single-machine/</guid><description>When you configure TFS Lab Management in a single box, and you follow the instruction that you find on MSDN, probably you will encounter this error when you configure the host tab.
The following host is unusable for Lab Management: xxxx in host group: &amp;ldquo;All Hosts&amp;rdquo;. To make it usable, connect at least one of its physical network adapters to a valid network. Then, verify the host group again to ensure that the problem has been resolved.</description></item><item><title>Preparing template machine for Lab Management</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/preparing-template-machine-for-lab-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/preparing-template-machine-for-lab-management/</guid><description>Quite often, customers ask for web application to be fully compatible with IE6 IE7 and IE8, so you need to always have some virtual machine with all version of IE running somewhere. In such a scenario, having right template machine in Lab Management can be a good option, so I decided to try it out and create some template machine to use in this scenario.
First of all I created a simple virtual machine in hyper-v, install WindowsXP SP3, and did all the update, except Internet explorer, so my system is fully updated with latest patch but with IE6.</description></item><item><title>Scvmm could not reset local administrator password during template creation</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/scvmm-could-not-reset-local-administrator-password-during-template-creation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/scvmm-could-not-reset-local-administrator-password-during-template-creation/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m creating some template in SCVMM to be used with lab management, I&amp;rsquo;ve created a windows XP client machine, joined to the domain, installed and configured Test Agent and finally I used SCVMM to convert the machine to a template.
The process finish with an error
Could not reset local Administrator password on WinXPIE8 to empty string before starting Sysprep.
(The password does not meet the password policy requirements. Check the minimum password length, etc etc</description></item></channel></rss>