<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VS11 on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/vs11/</link><description>Recent content in VS11 on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 16:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/vs11/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Shim and InstanceBehavior fallthrough to isolate part of the SUT</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/05/shim-and-instancebehavior-fallthrough-to-isolate-part-of-the-sut/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/05/shim-and-instancebehavior-fallthrough-to-isolate-part-of-the-sut/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve dealt in a previous post with the new &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2012/04/27/using-shims-in-visual-studio-11-to-test-untestable-code/">Shim library in Vs11&lt;/a> that permits you to test “difficult to test code” and &lt;strong>I showed a really simple example on how to use Shim to isolate the call to DateTime.Now&lt;/strong> to simulate passing time in a Unit Test. Now I want to change a little bit the perspective of the test, in the test showed in previous post I simply exercise the sut calling Execute() a couple of time, simulating the time that pass between the two calls. Here is the test&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Shims in Visual Studio 11 to test untestable code</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/04/using-shims-in-visual-studio-11-to-test-untestable-code/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/04/using-shims-in-visual-studio-11-to-test-untestable-code/</guid><description>&lt;p>I always strive myself to write testable code, but it is not always easy, especially if you do not follow TDD red-green-refactor mantra. &lt;strong>Code written without Unit Testing in mind is usually not so easy to test&lt;/strong> and when is time to modify code written by other, if you want to create a safety net of Unit Tests to avoid breaking code it is usually an hard task. The main problem is &lt;strong>hardcode dependency from static functions&lt;/strong> because you cannot test a single function or method in isolation, forcing you to use pattern like &lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://xunitpatterns.com/Back%20Door%20Manipulation.html">Back door manipulation&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> that makes test difficult to read, write and maintain. Lets take this code as example&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>VS11 gives you a fantastic XAML Editor</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/vs11-gives-you-a-fantastic-xaml-editor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2012 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/vs11-gives-you-a-fantastic-xaml-editor/</guid><description>&lt;p>XAML editing in Visual Studio 2010 is not one of the most exiting experience you can have, it works, but compared to Blend it is really poor. One of the thing I really do not like is the lack of information on design time data. Since I really develop every XAML application with MVVM or MVVM like approach, I always have design time data and I’d like Visual Studio to be able to use it during binding operation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Visual Studio 11 beta is out</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/02/visual-studio-11-beta-is-out/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/02/visual-studio-11-beta-is-out/</guid><description>&lt;p>Finally the beta version of Visual Studio 11 is out, toghter with TFS 11 and windows 8 consumer preview. You can find informations and links to download &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/visualstudio/11/en-us/products/visualstudio">here&lt;/a>, you can also find standalone installer for various components of Visual Studio ALM at &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/visualstudio/11/en-us/downloads#standalone">this address&lt;/a>. All download can be found at the home page of the &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/visualstudio/11/en-us/downloads#groups">Visual Studio 11 Beta downloads&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For those ones that wants to read information about this new version there is a nice PDF full of information at this address ( &lt;a href="http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=243994">http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=243994&lt;/a> ). You can find some nice video from Nortwest Cadence&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>