<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>kali on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/kali/</link><description>Recent content in kali on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 10:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/kali/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kali Linux in Hyper-V system</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/kali-linux-in-hyper-v/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/kali-linux-in-hyper-v/</guid><description>Kali Linux on Windows Most of the time a Kali Linux instance running in WSL is more than enough to have some fun in a Windows box. Using WSL is really simple but I have a couple of annoying problems that make my experience uncomfortable.
UI experience is sluggish, and annoying I have very little control over networking. Point 2 is the major pain point in my situation, I usually buy some inexpensive Intel i350 T2 cards on Ebay, to allow me to have at least three Network Card on my workstation.</description></item><item><title>Use Kali linux in Windows Subsystem for Linux</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/kali-linux-in-wsl2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/kali-linux-in-wsl2/</guid><description>Kali Linux on Windows Thanks to the new Windows Subsystem for Linux version 2, shortly called WSL2, we have now a real Linux kernel running in a real VM as the core of WSL. This allows finally to use Kali Linux in WSL environment; if you tried in WSL you probably encountered some errors with network tools like NMap. With WSL2 everything seems to run just fine giving you a quick way to have a Kali Linux running in your Windows system while having full integration between file systems.</description></item></channel></rss>