<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tfs Service on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/tfs-service/</link><description>Recent content in Tfs Service on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 17:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/tfs-service/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Troubleshoot logout from TFS Service when using multiple live Id</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/05/troubleshoot-logout-from-tfs-service-when-using-multiple-live-id/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/05/troubleshoot-logout-from-tfs-service-when-using-multiple-live-id/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are using * &lt;strong>multiple live id to connect to the same instance of&lt;/strong> &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://www.tfspreview.com/">* &lt;strong>TFS Preview&lt;/strong> *&lt;/a>&lt;/em> &lt;strong>(I’m, using a couple of different ID to demo authentication feature), you can find difficulties to logout from inside Visual Studio&lt;/strong> *. In &lt;strong>Figure 1&lt;/strong> you can visualize the standard Connect to Team Project page, and in the bottom left corner you find information about the user currently logged to TFS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Installing on-premise component against TFS Service TFS On Azure</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/04/installing-on-premise-component-against-tfs-service-tfs-on-azure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/04/installing-on-premise-component-against-tfs-service-tfs-on-azure/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://tfspreview.com/">Tfs on azure&lt;/a> is a a perfectly valid solution to have your &lt;strong>TFS hosted by Microsoft&lt;/strong> , no worries about upgrading, maintaining, backup and most important, &lt;em>it is available from every computer that has an internet connection&lt;/em>. This last factor can be really interesting for companies where people sometimes works from home, or from an hotel during transfers because the only solution with an On-Premise server is exposing the server as Https, or using a VPN, but with TFS on Azure all that you need is a simple internet connection.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>