<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Team Foundation Server on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/team-foundation-server/</link><description>Recent content in Team Foundation Server on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 15:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/team-foundation-server/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TFVC shell extension now published as standalone tool</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/03/6959/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/03/6959/</guid><description>&lt;p>Finally TFVC shell extension was published as a standalone tool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can read details in msdn blog&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/devops/2018/03/21/tfvc-windows-shell-extension-for-vsts-and-tfs-2018/">TFVC Windows Shell Extension for VSTS and TFS 2018&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" style="position: absolute; clip: rect(1px, 1px, 1px, 1px);" src="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/devops/2018/03/21/tfvc-windows-shell-extension-for-vsts-and-tfs-2018/embed/#?secret=5ipUdSDj4t" data-secret="5ipUdSDj4t" width="600" height="338" title="&amp;#8220;TFVC Windows Shell Extension for VSTS and TFS 2018&amp;#8221; &amp;#8212; Microsoft DevOps Blog" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>Gian Maria.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Troubleshoot 'service unavailable' in TFS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/02/troubleshoot-service-unavailable-in-tfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/02/troubleshoot-service-unavailable-in-tfs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yesterday I’ve started an old virtual machine with an old version of TFS and when I try to access the instance I got a “Service Unavailable” error.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image-6.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image_thumb-6.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/image_thumb-6.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Figure 1&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>: &lt;em>General Service Unavailable error for TFS Web interface&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This error happens most of the time if you have wrong user credentials in the worker process used by IIS to run the TFS Application. To verify this assumption, you can simply &lt;strong>open IIS Manager console and verify the status of the worker process&lt;/strong> that is used to run IIS ( &lt;strong>Figure 2&lt;/strong> )&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TFS 2018 is out time to upgrade</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/11/tfs-2018-is-out-time-to-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/11/tfs-2018-is-out-time-to-upgrade/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some days are passed, but it is good to remind you that &lt;strong>TFS 2018 is finally out.&lt;/strong> Some people are surprised because after TFS 2015 we had TFS 2017 and we are still in 2017 and we already have version 2018, but this is the good part of the ALM tools in Microsoft, &lt;strong>they are really shipping tons of new goodness each year&lt;/strong> :).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.visualstudio.com/en-us/news/releasenotes/tfs2018-relnotes">Release note page&lt;/a> contains all the details about the new version, from that link you have a small 13 minute video that explain what is new in this version and as usual in the page you have a detailed list of all the news with detailed information about each of the new features.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Visual Studio 2010 error connecting to TFS 2017</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/05/visual-studio-2010-error-connecting-to-tfs-2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/05/visual-studio-2010-error-connecting-to-tfs-2017/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the reason why I always suggest of keeping TFS upgraded is the compatibility matrix. &lt;strong>Microsoft ensure that old tools (like VS 2010) always can connect to latest version of TFS, but the opposite is not true.&lt;/strong> This means that new version of Visual Studio could have problem connecting to older instances of TFS.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Keeping your TFS updated will guarantee that you can use TFS with newer and older tooling (yes, even Visual Basic 6 can work with TFS 2017)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Create a Team Project from Web UI in TFS 2015 Update 2</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/04/create-a-team-project-from-web-ui-in-tfs-2015-update-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/04/create-a-team-project-from-web-ui-in-tfs-2015-update-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Creation of a new Team Project is a feature that traditionally was available only from Visual Studio in TFS on-premises. You do not need to have a full Visual Studio installation, you can only install the Team Explorer component, &lt;strong>but in 2015, unfortunately, the stand alone installer for Team Explorer is Gone&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It turns out that, after upgrade to 2015 &lt;strong>you should install Visual Studio Express or Visual Studio Community to create a Team Project&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tfx error Failed to find api location for area</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/11/tfx-error-failed-to-find-api-location-for-area/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 21:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/11/tfx-error-failed-to-find-api-location-for-area/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/Microsoft/tfs-cli">Tfx-cli&lt;/a> is a &lt;strong>cross platform command line for TFS / VSTS&lt;/strong> that can be used to accomplish various tasks. To connect to your favorite instance all you have to do is generate a Personal Access Token and use the command&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">
&lt;table style="border-spacing:0;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">&lt;tr>&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">1
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;;width:100%">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>tfx login&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>You will be prompted for the URL of the server and your Personal Access Token to access the server. In &lt;strong>Figure 1&lt;/strong> I connected to my VSTS account.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TFS Integration Platform copy from Agile 2010 to CMMI 2013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/08/tfs-integration-platform-copy-from-agile-2010-to-cmmi-2013/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/08/tfs-integration-platform-copy-from-agile-2010-to-cmmi-2013/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I needed to move a bunch of Work Items from a TFS 2010  to TFS 2013, but I needed also to move from a TP based on Agile Template on a Project based on CMMI Template.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Number of Work Items is small, but lots of them have attachments, &lt;strong>so I decided to use Integration Platform to migrate the history and attachments&lt;/strong>. It turns out that we accomplished an acceptable result with little time. An alternative, if you do not care about attachments and history, is using Excel.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Running NUnit Tests in a TFS 2015 Build vNext</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/03/running-nunit-tests-in-a-tfs-2015-build-vnext/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/03/running-nunit-tests-in-a-tfs-2015-build-vnext/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="scenario">Scenario&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In TFS2015 CTP you can have a preview of the new build system that will be available with the next version of Team Foundation Server. If you start &lt;strong>scheduling a new build that has NUnit test you probably will notice that your unit tests are not executed during the build&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To execute NUnit test in a vNext build you should ensure that appropriate tests adapters are available to agents that will run the build&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using a different unit of measure in task planning in TFS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/02/using-a-different-unit-of-measure-in-task-planning-in-tfs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/02/using-a-different-unit-of-measure-in-task-planning-in-tfs/</guid><description>&lt;p>With TFS 2012 you can do work planning with the new agile board, where work is decomposed from PBI to task and &lt;strong>task are usually estimated in hours&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/image10.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/image_thumb10.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/image_thumb10.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Figure 1&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>: &lt;em>Task estimation is made in hours.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using hours is only a matter of convenience, but many agile team does not like hourly estimates and prefer using some other empirical values such as Effort, Story Points, or Cup Of Coffee, where the latter is the number of Cup Of Coffee you need to finish that task :) (dev are caffeine addicted). Avoiding using hours, gave the idea that we are not estimating precisely, especially because we are interested in team Velocity and not knowing how many hours do we need for a certain task. &lt;strong>For this example suppose our team is used estimating in coc = Cup Of Coffee, and we want the board to reflect this fact&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Change email address in TFSPReview</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/10/change-email-address-in-tfspreview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 21:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/10/change-email-address-in-tfspreview/</guid><description>&lt;p>Actually TFSservice only accepts live id as a login mechanism, but if you start to use it in your company probably you want it to use another email address for E-Mail communication (alert, Feedback, etc), this is possible through the My Profile link&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/image1.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/image_thumb1.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/image_thumb1.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Figure 1&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>: &lt;em>My profile link to change your TFS Service profile&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you got to configuration page, &lt;strong>you can simply change your preferred email address to whatever mail you want&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/image2.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/image_thumb2.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/image_thumb2.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Team foundation service new login page and more</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/04/team-foundation-service-new-login-page-and-more/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/04/team-foundation-service-new-login-page-and-more/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are using the TfsPreview (Tfs on azure), you can notice that the login page is drastically changed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/image5.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/image_thumb4.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/image_thumb4.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even if this seems only a simple and stupid change, it shows one of the advantage of using TfsService over having it on-premise: the automatic update process made periodically by Microsoft. The change in the login page is only a fancy change of an update that was deployed last week on TFS Service, this actually means two distinct advantage:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Install Sharepoint Foundation on Workstation error the user does not exists or is not unique</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/04/install-sharepoint-foundation-on-workstation-error-the-user-does-not-exists-or-is-not-unique/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2012 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/04/install-sharepoint-foundation-on-workstation-error-the-user-does-not-exists-or-is-not-unique/</guid><description>&lt;p>I wish to install &lt;strong>Sharepoint Foundation 2010 on a Single Workstation machine&lt;/strong> (Windows Server 2008 R2) to use with TFS11 Beta and I followed the &lt;a href="http://www.dev4side.com/community/blog/2010/5/2/how-to-install-sharepoint-2010-with-a-local-account.aspx">really good guide&lt;/a> of my friend &lt;a href="http://www.peppedotnet.it/">Giuseppe Marchi&lt;/a> to accomplish this task, but I got a really strange error when I tried to configure the database with powershell&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>the user does not exists or is not unique&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is a real annoying stuff, because I’m not a Sharepoint Expert, so I started looking around to understand the cause. First of all you need to be sure to have latest Identity Foundation installed (&lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/download/en/details.aspx?displaylang=en&amp;amp;amp;id=17331">you can find installer here&lt;/a>). Then you need to create an account different from Administration, in my example I created a user named WssService and &lt;em>give a complex password so it met the password complexity rule of the System&lt;/em>. Make this user an administrator of the machine and be sure that it is also an administrator of the SQL Server instance, because he should be able to create databases, be sure also to download &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/download/en/details.aspx?id=26640">Sharepoint 2010 foundation Service Pack 1&lt;/a>, because it will maximize the success rate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TFS Express a TFS for team up to 5 user for FREE</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/02/tfs-express-a-tfs-for-team-up-to-5-user-for-free/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/02/tfs-express-a-tfs-for-team-up-to-5-user-for-free/</guid><description>&lt;p>As you can read &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/bharry/archive/2012/02/23/coming-soon-tfs-express.aspx">from Brian Harry’s blog post&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In TFS 11, we are introducing a new download of TFS, called Team Foundation Server Express, that includes core developer features:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Source Code Control&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Work Item Tracking&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Build Automation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Agile Taskboard&lt;/li>
&lt;li>and more…&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The best news is that it’s &lt;strong>FREE&lt;/strong> for individuals and teams of up to 5 users.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is really a BIG NEWS expecially for the really super-easy installing and configuring, because we can read in Brian’s post&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>X01 Team Foundation Server List</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/12/x01-team-foundation-server-list/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2011 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/12/x01-team-foundation-server-list/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve not a 101 Team Foundation Server link lists :), but quite often I got question from people on TFS, and I clearly remember that I read the answer in some blog post, but I could not remember exactly where. Since there are a lot of blogs and sites that deal with TFS, I decided to keep a list of all links that I found useful during time in a blog post, so, whenever I need to look for a link that was useful in the past, I can simply scan this list hoping to find what I’m searching :).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Team Foundation Service december update</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/12/team-foundation-service-december-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2011 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/12/team-foundation-service-december-update/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the great advantage of using Tfs on Azure, called Team Foundation Service, is that you never should worry for update of the server, because everything is managed by the TFS team. If you already have an account, you probably noticed that the UI is radically changed, as described in &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/bharry/archive/2011/12/08/december-refresh-of-the-team-foundation-service.aspx">Brian Harry’s post&lt;/a>, new features were added, a new UI is available and everything was done without any need for you intervention.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TFS Pills merging conflicts during unshelve</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/12/tfs-pills-merging-conflicts-during-unshelve/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2011 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/12/tfs-pills-merging-conflicts-during-unshelve/</guid><description>&lt;p>Shelvesets are a really useful concept in TFS, and you should be aware that thanks to Power Tools you can even do a Merge during an Unshelve in case of conflicts. As an example suppose this simple and stupid scenario, you have this code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/image8.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/image_thumb8.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/image_thumb8.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Figure 1&lt;/strong> * &lt;strong>:&lt;/strong> Original Code*&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now lets generate a conflict with Shelveset; simply typing some text.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/image9.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/image_thumb9.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/11/image_thumb9.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Figure 2&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>: &lt;em>Modified code, insertion of a simple comment.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Helps in installing TFS vNext</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/helps-in-installing-tfs-vnext/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/helps-in-installing-tfs-vnext/</guid><description>&lt;p>For those one that needs help on how to install the TFS vNext preview from the BUILD conference in Anaheim here is three link that will explain you how to install Basic, Standard and advanced configuration.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/visualstudioalm/archive/2011/09/14/installing-the-basic-configuration-of-tfs-vnext-from-the-build-conference-in-los-angeles.aspx">Tfs vNext – Basic&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/visualstudioalm/archive/2011/09/14/installing-the-standard-configuration-of-tfs-vnext-from-the-build-conference-in-los-angeles.aspx">Tfs vNext – Standard&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/visualstudioalm/archive/2011/09/15/installing-the-advanced-configuration-of-tfs-vnext-from-the-build-conference-in-anaheim.aspx">Tfs vNext – Advanced&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Enjoy TFS vNext.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gian Maria.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Manage disconnected team with TFS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/manage-disconnected-team-with-tfs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/manage-disconnected-team-with-tfs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Suppose you have this scenario, a team is working on company office to create some software that communicate with some complex hardware that will be deployed to a foreign country. When is time to set up everything in production the team goes physically to that foreign country and they will modify the software on the field doing final adjustments but usually they have no connection to the central office. How could you manage to keep your source code aligned when the team is on remote site not being able to access the central TFS?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>News for TFS 11 VCS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/news-for-tfs-11-vcs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/news-for-tfs-11-vcs/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/bharry/archive/2011/08/02/version-control-model-enhancements-in-tfs-11.aspx">this post of Mr. Brian Harry&lt;/a> some of the news regarding TFS 11 VCS are unveiled. While there is still no DVCS, there are a lot of improvements with the introduction of &lt;em>local workspaces&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Actually TFS Workspaces status is kept on the server, so whenever you issue a GetLatest, the server check the status of the Workspace and send you only new data. This causes sometimes behavior that surprise most developer coming from other VCS like subversion. One of this surprising behavior is &lt;em>delete a file from the file system, then issue a Get Latest, the file is not downloaded again&lt;/em>. This happens because the server does not know that you deleted the file, he still thinks that the file is there so you need to do a Get Specific version, or issue a &lt;a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/c255a1e4-04ba-4f68-8f4e-cd473d6b971f">tfpt scorch&lt;/a> command. Another aspect developers do not like is having Read-only file that needs to be checked out before starting to work with.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Duplicate queries in tfs between iterations</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/03/duplicate-queries-in-tfs-between-iterations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/03/duplicate-queries-in-tfs-between-iterations/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most common operation when you move to another iteration is moving queries to the new one. Here is a sample, this is the Iteration 1 of the TailSpin Toys of the Demo Tfs machine.&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/image.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/image_thumb.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/image_thumb.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Figure 1&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>: &lt;em>Team project queries of the Iteration 1&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you can see you have a lot of queries under the Iteration 1 path, and if you open one of them, you can see that in definition it got a filter to grab only Iteration 1 bugs:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Team Explorer everywhere SP1 Beta 1 in action</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/12/team-explorer-everywhere-sp1-beta-1-in-action/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/12/team-explorer-everywhere-sp1-beta-1-in-action/</guid><description>&lt;p>You can download &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/bharry/archive/2010/11/03/team-explorer-everywhere-2010-sp1-beta-is-available-for-download.aspx">Team Explorer Everywhere SP1 Beta&lt;/a> to integrate all TFS functionality in your &lt;em>non Visual Studio&lt;/em> environment, like eclipse. One of the most interesting addition made in SP1 is the support for gated Check In in Eclipse environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First of all you need to setup a build with ant or maven, and you need to install &lt;a href="http://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/2d7c8577-54b8-47ce-82a5-8649f579dcb6">Team Foundation Server Build Extensions Power Tool&lt;/a> on the build server in order to be able to run a build based on Ant. Carefully read all requisite in the download page (Java SDK, some environment variables, etc) and now you are able to create a build from eclipse.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>December update Of TFS and VS 2010</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/12/december-update-of-tfs-and-vs-2010/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/12/december-update-of-tfs-and-vs-2010/</guid><description>&lt;p>Microsoft releases a Virtual Machine with TFS and VS 2010 with some test data and hands on labs, that are really useful for demo or just to try out the new functionalities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The machine have a 6 month expiration, and the old version expired today. If you still want to use them you can download the update version &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/briankel/archive/2010/06/25/now-available-visual-studio-2010-rtm-virtual-machine-with-sample-data-and-hands-on-labs.aspx">here&lt;/a>. This new version has already the Feature pack 2 installed and other updates that are listed in the link above, but if you are curious here is all the updates from the older version.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Portfolio management-integrate TFS with Project Server</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/12/portfolio-managementintegrate-tfs-with-project-server/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/12/portfolio-managementintegrate-tfs-with-project-server/</guid><description>&lt;p>Finally the beta of integration between project server and TFS is out, and you can try it. All the detail can be found in the post in &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/bharry/archive/2010/12/07/portfolio-management-tfs-lt-gt-project-server-integration-in-beta.aspx">Brian Harry&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a>. Basically is a tool that manage synchronization between a TFS instance and project server, that permits to managers to work on project server for resource management, while developers still use TFS for agile process management.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have project server and tfs in your organization, this is a tool you should not miss.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Insert name of the user in assembly file number</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/11/insert-name-of-the-user-in-assembly-file-number/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/11/insert-name-of-the-user-in-assembly-file-number/</guid><description>&lt;p>Assembly file numbering during a Continuous integration build is one of the most interesting feature in a project, but sometimes we need also to generate numbers even for local build, especially if the user can launch some script to do a local compile and use it to deploy somewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Major and Minor number in an assembly file info are usually updated manually when a new version or milestone is reached, so we are left with two 16 bit number to store useful information. Clearly a number is suitable to store changesetId, or some other integer, but how can you include the name of the user who did the build into the assembly file info number?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to get TFS server address from a local folder mapped to a workspace</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/09/how-to-get-tfs-server-address-from-a-local-folder-mapped-to-a-workspace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/09/how-to-get-tfs-server-address-from-a-local-folder-mapped-to-a-workspace/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes you need to operate to a Tfs Version Control System with API starting from a local folder. There are a lot of API to work with workspaces, but the main problem is that you need to pass through a &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb171724%28v=VS.100%29.aspx">VersionControlServer&lt;/a> object, and to obtain such an object you need to know the address of the Tfs server the workspace is mapped to?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The exercise is the following one :) – Write a snippet of code, based on TFS API that, given a local path, retrieve ChangesetId that is currently mapped on the workspace.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Team Explorer Everywhere-first impression</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/team-explorer-everywherefirst-impression/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/team-explorer-everywherefirst-impression/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the coolest news of TFS 2010 is the presence of Team Explorer Everywhere, a plugin for eclipse and a command line cross platform tool to access TFS. I do not work with Java, but I want to have a look at it, just to understand the level of integration with TFs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First impression is really good, because the look and feel of the IDE is really similar to those of Visual Studio, as you can spot from &lt;strong>Figure 1&lt;/strong> , where I show the connection windows to a local tfs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Executing Test in a test agent during a build</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/executing-test-in-a-test-agent-during-a-build/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2010 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/executing-test-in-a-test-agent-during-a-build/</guid><description>&lt;p>With Tfs Build you have a great flexibility on how to execute your unit tests. First of all you can decide to execute only tests of a certain category, or with a certain priority, but one of the most interesting feature is the ability to execute them in another machine with the helps of a test Agent. First of all you need to install a test controller and configure it in one of the machine:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Edit properties of a Work Item with API</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/edit-properties-of-a-work-item-with-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/edit-properties-of-a-work-item-with-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you look at the &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2010/05/10/create-a-work-item-by-code-in-tfs-returns-tf237124-work-item-is-not-ready-to-save/">previous post,&lt;/a> I answered a little problem that can occur when saving a Work Item in TFS with API. A common question that arise from people when they begin to work with the WIT api is &lt;em>how can I make possible for users of my application to edit a WIT?&lt;/em> A Work Item has a lot of fields and building an UI to permit editing capabilities to the user would be really difficult, but clearly Microsoft has made the standard one available to use within your program.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Create a Work Item By code in TFS returns TF237124 Work Item is not ready to save</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/create-a-work-item-by-code-in-tfs-returns-tf237124-work-item-is-not-ready-to-save/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/create-a-work-item-by-code-in-tfs-returns-tf237124-work-item-is-not-ready-to-save/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today my dear friend &lt;a href="http://blogs.ugidotnet.org/j3r/Default.aspx">Matteo&lt;/a> asked me some help with a snippet of code to insert a WIT into a TFS. The snippet was the following one.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">
&lt;table style="border-spacing:0;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">&lt;tr>&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 1
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 2
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 3
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 4
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 5
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 6
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 7
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 8
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 9
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">10
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">11
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">12
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;;width:100%">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Dim tfs As New TeamFoundationServer(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;http://tfs2010test:8080/tfs/defaultcollection&amp;#34;&lt;/span>,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>New NetworkCredential(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Administrator&amp;#34;&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;xxxxxxxx&amp;#34;&lt;/span>))
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Dim wis As WorkItemStore = DirectCast(tfs.GetService(GetType(WorkItemStore)), WorkItemStore)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Dim teamProject As Project = wis.Projects(&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">0&lt;/span>)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Dim witype As WorkItemType = teamProject.WorkItemTypes(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Task&amp;#34;&lt;/span>)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>If witype IsNot Nothing Then
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Console.WriteLine(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Adding new task to Team Project {0}&amp;#34;&lt;/span>, teamProject.Name)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Dim wi As New WorkItem(witype)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>wi.Title = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;You have a Task! [Ding]&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>wi.State = &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Active&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>wi.Save()
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Console.WriteLine(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Added Work Item # {0} created by {1}&amp;#34;&lt;/span>, wi.Id, wi.CreatedBy)&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>He is having problem because the Save throws exception.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TFS Integration platform finished sync from codeplex</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/tfs-integration-platform-finished-sync-from-codeplex/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/tfs-integration-platform-finished-sync-from-codeplex/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2010/03/19/tfs-integration-platform-to-synchronize-from-codeplex-to-tfs2010/">days ago&lt;/a> I tried &lt;a href="http://tfsintegration.codeplex.com/">TFS Integration Platform&lt;/a> to sync a project (&lt;a href="http://dexterblogengine.codeplex.com/">Dexter&lt;/a>) from codeplex to a local test TFS with Lab Management capabilities enabled. At that time the sync process did not work very well, the server take a long time before raising an exception and I did not have time to investigate further.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yesterday I downloaded the latest version, dated 24 April, and try again the sync process. The most interesting stuff is that I was able to open the old project, and start again from the point it was stopped last time, cool. After an hour here is the result.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tfs power tools</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/tfs-power-tools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/tfs-power-tools/</guid><description>&lt;p>I think that &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/bharry/archive/2010/04/26/tfs-2010-power-tools-have-released.aspx">Power Tools&lt;/a> are indeed a must-have for every person that works with TFS. The new April 2010 version has a couple of commands that are really interesting. They are called AddProjectPortal and AddProjectReports and are used to create project portal and reports for Team Project that currently does not have one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This commands are useful for those one that starts with Tfs basic, then move to a Full version and for many other scenario.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Creating TFS2010 Team Project fails with TF30275</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/creating-tfs2010-team-project-fails-with-tf30275/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2010 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/creating-tfs2010-team-project-fails-with-tf30275/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have a strange issue that happens not only to me, but also to another guy that like me runs NOD32 antivirus. You can find &lt;a href="http://social.msdn.microsoft.com/Forums/en-US/tfsadmin/thread/97c28590-d9cd-467c-a6f8-664d3ea051fd?prof=required">more detail here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem is that at the very end of the MSF Agile team project creation, from a remote machine running NOD32 and if you ask to create sharepoint portal the process hang for a while, then failed and you can find this error in the log. (the error code is TF30275).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moving renaming and handling projects collection in tfs2010</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/moving-renaming-and-handling-projects-collection-in-tfs2010/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/moving-renaming-and-handling-projects-collection-in-tfs2010/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve installed a little test tfs with full MOSS 2007 integration in a virtual machine, now I want to move and rename a project collection from another test tfs (RC) to this new one (RTM), and recreate the project portal on MOSS for one of the team project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This operation can seem complex, but it is instead really simple. First of all log to the source TFS (it was an RC), uninstall everything related to TFS RC, then install TFS RTM and choose upgrade. &lt;em>Everything is automatic :)&lt;/em>. Then I simply detatched the DefaultCollection, backup the database of the collection, restore it to the destination server, and reattach Project Collection with a new name, like &lt;em>RcUpgradedDefaultCollection&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Preparing template machine for Lab Management</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/preparing-template-machine-for-lab-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/preparing-template-machine-for-lab-management/</guid><description>&lt;p>Quite often, customers ask for web application to be fully compatible with IE6 IE7 and IE8, so you need to always have some virtual machine with all version of IE running somewhere. In such a scenario, having right template machine in Lab Management can be a good option, so I decided to try it out and create some template machine to use in this scenario.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First of all I created a simple virtual machine in hyper-v, install WindowsXP SP3, and did all the update, except Internet explorer, so my system is fully updated with latest patch but with IE6.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Grab the highest changeset number in a workspace during a build</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/grab-the-highest-changeset-number-in-a-workspace-during-a-build/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2010 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/grab-the-highest-changeset-number-in-a-workspace-during-a-build/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2009/09/07/again-on-assembly-numbering-during-tfs-build/">very old post&lt;/a> I explained how to grab (with API) the latest changeset number during a build to use for assembly numbering, but I need to do a correction, after a comment on the post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ChangesetId is an unique number for all the source control system, so I have two distinct problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>while the build is running, developers do check-in, so when I retrieve the GetLatestChangesetId at a certain point during the buil, I do not get the real changesetId that I&amp;rsquo;m building, but an incorrect one. The problem is that a user can lookup the assembly number, see a changesetid and then verify that the changesetId is not related to that project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Virtual machine for VS2010</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/virtual-machine-for-vs2010/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/virtual-machine-for-vs2010/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you want to try VS2010 RC and TFS2010 with a virtual machine that has already everything preconfigured, and also have some nice hands on lab covering ALM:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;u>Software quality:&lt;/u>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Authoring and Running Manual Tests using Microsoft Test Manager 2010&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Introduction to Test Case Management with Microsoft Test Manager 2010&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Introduction to Coded UI Tests with Visual Studio 2010 Ultimate&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Debugging with IntelliTrace using Visual Studio 2010 Ultimate&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;u>Software architecture:&lt;/u>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Connecting to TFS2010 with API</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/connecting-to-tfs2010-with-api/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2010 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/connecting-to-tfs2010-with-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you know TFS 2008 API and try to connect to a tfs 2010 you could probably start with this snippet, but you will get a 404 exception, telling you that the tfs is not available.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">
&lt;table style="border-spacing:0;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">&lt;tr>&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">1
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">2
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">3
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;;width:100%">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>TeamFoundationServer tfs = &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">new&lt;/span> TeamFoundationServer(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;http://vs2010beta2:8080/tfs&amp;#34;&lt;/span>,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">new&lt;/span> NetworkCredential(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;dorikr&amp;#34;&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;P2ssw0rd&amp;#34;&lt;/span>));
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>tfs.EnsureAuthenticated();&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The problem is originated by the new &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/bharry/archive/2009/04/19/team-foundation-server-2010-key-concepts.aspx">architecture&lt;/a> of tfs2010, and the presence of &lt;em>Project collections&lt;/em>. Project collections are containers for Team Project, and they are the analogue of a TFS2008 server. The above code cannot work, because you are trying to connect with a TeamFoundationServer object to a tfs that contains a certain number of project collection. To make it work you need to change the server string passed to the constructor in this way&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tfs integration platform to synchronize from codeplex to TFS2010</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/tfs-integration-platform-to-synchronize-from-codeplex-to-tfs2010/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/tfs-integration-platform-to-synchronize-from-codeplex-to-tfs2010/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most exiting stuff of TFS is the ability to use API to access it, that gave possibilities to people outside MSFT to create tools. One tool to keep at look at is the &lt;a href="http://tfsintegration.codeplex.com/">TFS integration platform&lt;/a>, still in very alpha version, but that promises a lot of exiting stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I decided to have a look at it for a very specific task, I want to be able to periodically synchronize a project from Codeplex to TFS2010. This is an interesting scenario for me, because I can have a local version of the project in TFS2010 and I can setup a lab management environment on it, to test lab management on a real project. First of all now we have a clean gui to use integration services, simply go to TFS to TFS connector and fire the TFSMigrationShell.exe&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scvmm could not reset local administrator password during template creation</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/scvmm-could-not-reset-local-administrator-password-during-template-creation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/scvmm-could-not-reset-local-administrator-password-during-template-creation/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m creating some template in SCVMM to be used with lab management, I&amp;rsquo;ve created a windows XP client machine, joined to the domain, installed and configured Test Agent and finally I used SCVMM to convert the machine to a template.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The process finish with an error&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;font style="background-color: #ffffff">Could not reset local Administrator password on WinXPIE8 to empty string before starting Sysprep.&lt;/font>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;font style="background-color: #ffffff">(The password does not meet the password policy requirements. Check the minimum password length, etc etc&lt;/font>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lab Management VDH Up and running</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/02/lab-management-vdh-up-and-running/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2010 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/02/lab-management-vdh-up-and-running/</guid><description>&lt;p>With VS2010 RC MS had released a &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyID=592e874d-8fcd-4665-8e55-7da0d44b0dee&amp;amp;amp;displaylang=en">vhd to evaluate Lab Management&lt;/a>. This is a very good news, and since I already have a Beta2 Lab Management Up and running I want to try the VHD to see what is improved on RC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lab Management is and environment, so there is not a way you can simply launch the vhd and play with it, you absolutely need to setup an environment and follow &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/lab_management/archive/2010/02/12/one-box-lab-management-walkthrough.aspx">this detailed tutorial&lt;/a>. The first problem is, &lt;em>How I can evaluate lab management without disturbing my main system?&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Writing a custom Activity for TFS 2010 Build workflow</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/02/writing-a-custom-activity-for-tfs-2010-build-workflow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2010 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/02/writing-a-custom-activity-for-tfs-2010-build-workflow/</guid><description>&lt;p>A good option to customize TFS2010 build workflow is creating a Custom Activity, an operation that is quite different from creating a Custom &lt;strong>Code&lt;/strong> Activity. A custom activity does not contain any code at all and it is only composed by sub activities. This kind of customization is really useful to create pieces of workflow that will be inserted in main build workflow. As an example I created a simple custom activity to deploy a database project on a custom Database Server.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Use Msbuild Custom Action in TFS2010 build with a custom project</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/use-msbuild-custom-action-in-tfs2010-build-with-a-custom-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/use-msbuild-custom-action-in-tfs2010-build-with-a-custom-project/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since TFS Build 2010 is ruled by workflow foundation, what happens if you want to use a custom msbuild task that you already have used in the past? I agree with the fact that the right approach to use, is writing a custom activity, but you need to write more code, and if you already have a tested MsBuild custom task, probably the best approach is to reuse it in the build workflow.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TFSBuild 2010 some news</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/tfsbuild-2010-some-news/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/tfsbuild-2010-some-news/</guid><description>&lt;p>When you create a new build in tfs2010, you can immediately notice some changes during the definition. In the basic configuration there are more options devoted to testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/11/image.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/11/image_thumb.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/11/image_thumb.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you can see it is possible to specify now if a test failure must fail the entire build, it is possible to specify command line aguments, priority etc etc. Another set of new options is contained in Advanced section.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TF255352 and TF255331 warning during tfs 2010 beta2 install</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/tf255352-and-tf255331-warning-during-tfs-2010-beta2-install/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2009 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/tf255352-and-tf255331-warning-during-tfs-2010-beta2-install/</guid><description>&lt;p>This can happen when you change machine name after you installed and configured sql server. I&amp;rsquo;m trying various type of installation of tfs2010 just to verify the various options, my virtual machine had the default name, so I changed after I installed sql server 2008. I already know that this could cause problems, so I started a fresh installation of TFS just to verify if I guess correctly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is the two warnings I got during installation&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tfs Build in Tfs basic</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/tfs-build-in-tfs-basic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/tfs-build-in-tfs-basic/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2009/10/24/installing-tfs2010-beta2-first-try/">this post&lt;/a> I dealt with the easy of installation of tfs basic. But tfs basic is much more than simply source control, if you open the TFS Administration Console, you can configure Team Build (Suppose you have installed it as I showed in previous post).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/10/image20.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/10/image-thumb20.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/10/image-thumb20.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even in this wizard you can immediately see some warning&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/10/image21.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/10/image-thumb21.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/10/image-thumb21.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The wizard is telling you that you should not install TFS Build on the same machine of Team Foundation Server, this because building projects can impact performances. Another reason for not installing TFS build is on machine with very important and sensitive data, since the tfs build can execute arbitrary code (Custom msbuild action as example). The only configuration we need to specify is the Team project collection that the build machine must build,&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>An interesting post</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/an-interesting-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2009 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/an-interesting-post/</guid><description>&lt;p>As you can read in &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/bharry/archive/2009/10/01/tfs-2010-for-sourcesafe-users.aspx">this post&lt;/a>, there are a lot of new stuff around TFS 2010. The good news is that Standard TFS is a TFS so you can have not only version control, as Source safe does, but the Issue tracker and most important the build automation (how can you lived without :) ).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This sounds so good, it promises to bring TFS power to a really amount of teams. Even if the licensing price is not already announced, in that post you can read that * it will be at least as easy and cost effective to get as SourceSafe has been*. This is a really good news for all those people that are interested in moving towards TFS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speedup Tfs builds with parallel compilation and incremental get</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/speedup-tfs-builds-with-parallel-compilation-and-incremental-get/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/speedup-tfs-builds-with-parallel-compilation-and-incremental-get/</guid><description>&lt;p>For large projects, the time needed to run a build can grow considerably large, until it eventually pass the famous barrier of &lt;a href="http://www.think-box.co.uk/blog/2006/02/ten-minute-build-continuous.html">10 minutes&lt;/a>. To speedup build time you can try to use some features of TFS,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Parallel Builds:&lt;/strong> Msbuild can run faster in multicore environment with the use of &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb383805.aspx">parallel builds&lt;/a>, to enable this feature you can simply go to the machine where the tfs build agent is installed and you need to modify the file &lt;em>tfsbuildservice.exe.config&lt;/em> located in *C:\Program Files\Microsoft Visual Studio 9.0\Common7\IDE\PrivateAssemblies,*and change the value for the MaxProcesses key property&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Integrate Nunit test into a Tfs build</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/integrate-nunit-test-into-a-tfs-build/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2009 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/integrate-nunit-test-into-a-tfs-build/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since a lot of people use NUnit testing framework, it is of high importance knowing how to fully integrate nunit test runner inside a tfs build. The overall problem is that you can create a custom task, or using an &lt;a href="http://msbuildtasks.tigris.org/">existing one&lt;/a> to run nunit tests, but the main problem is &lt;em>integrating nunit output with standard tfs output&lt;/em>. The problem and a possible solution is described &lt;a href="http://richardsbraindump.blogspot.com/2008/06/merging-nunit-build-results-into-tfs.html">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This means that someone had already solved this problem for us :), and created an &lt;em>xslt that transforms a nunit-style output into a mstest-style output (.trx file)&lt;/em>, you can find the xslt and an example proj in the &lt;a href="http://nunit4teambuild.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?title=sample%20script">nunit4teambuild&lt;/a> codeplex project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Execute custom code during Tfs build</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/execute-custom-code-during-tfs-build/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/execute-custom-code-during-tfs-build/</guid><description>&lt;p>At this point I explained how to setup a build, and how to fully customize it editing the msbuild file to execute some tasks, like open an issue when one or more test fail.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another interesting stuff to explain is how to execute custom code during the build, to demonstrate this concept I&amp;rsquo;ll show how to tweet a warning message when test phase fails. To execute custom code you simply need to create a custom msbuild task that does everything you want, then you simply need to call this custom task in the build script. The first step is creating the task.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open an issue when a test fails during a TFS build</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/open-an-issue-when-a-test-fails-during-a-tfs-build/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2009 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/open-an-issue-when-a-test-fails-during-a-tfs-build/</guid><description>&lt;p>In last post I show how to configure test run in a team foundation build, simply editing the msbuild file. The aim of the post was showing how to make the entire build fail when a single test fails. To achieve this result I simply override a target and set some properties values.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll show how to automatically open an issue in TFS when a test fails. This is a standard requirement, because in such a way you are immediately aware when some test are failing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Installation of Tfs Beta 1</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/installation-of-tfs-beta-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/installation-of-tfs-beta-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I installed Tfs 2010 beta to look at new features; installation process of Tfs can be a complex operation but I must admit that in the 2010 version, the installer is more friendly. I installed sharepoint and sql server 2008 then I fired the installation of tfs. The main difference from the 2008 version is that it does not ask you anything, it just install, postponing the configuration after the installation is ok. When you access the Team Foundation Administration console, it presents you a configuration wizard.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Customize test running in a Tfs Team Build</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/customize-test-running-in-a-tfs-team-build/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/customize-test-running-in-a-tfs-team-build/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2009/06/26/running-tests-during-a-build-in-tfs/">previous post&lt;/a> I showed how to setup a build in tfs that not only builds the solution, but also runs all the tests. The next step is to configure how tests are run and reacting to test result. The first thing I want is the ability to make the entire build fail if one of the test fails. As you see in the previous post, the default behavior of the build, is to partially fail if one or more tests fail.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Running tests during a build in TFS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/running-tests-during-a-build-in-tfs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2009 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/running-tests-during-a-build-in-tfs/</guid><description>&lt;p>The term &lt;em>Build&lt;/em> is a complex one that does not only means &lt;em>compile source files into final assemblies&lt;/em>, but it comprehends many other operations that are vital for the project. One of these operation is running unit tests during Tfs build. The reason to have unit tests run at each build is to continuously keep track of the quality of the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Specifying test to run in a Tfs build is really simple, since you have a specific step of the wizard dedicated to this operation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Team foundation Build - Share Builds among multiple servers</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/team-foundation-build-share-builds-among-multiple-servers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 12:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/team-foundation-build-share-builds-among-multiple-servers/</guid><description>&lt;p>When you begin to use Team Foundation Server, you will create different builds for all of your company&amp;rsquo;s projects. Since building complex products can be resource intensive, it is likely that your Team Foundation Server machine starts to perform slowly. This is a typical issue of Continuous integration servers, since they compile projects at each check-in you will end with a lot of builds and a lot of work to do.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Creating a build with Tfs</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/creating-a-build-with-tfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2009 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/creating-a-build-with-tfs/</guid><description>&lt;p>I worked for long time with NANT + CC.net as continuous integration tools. I used subversion as Source Control System and use Mantis or Redmine for issue tracking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main disadvantage of using such a configuration is the need to make each tool communicate with others, the good part is that these tools are open source. Team Foundation Server on the other side is a Commercial tool, so you have to pay it, but it gives you a lot of features in a single unified tool, and this is Great. Let&amp;rsquo;s see as an example how to set up a continuous integration server for a simple project.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>