<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Visual Studio on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/visual-studio/</link><description>Recent content in Visual Studio on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 08:12:42 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/visual-studio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pills: Visual Studio lost access to authenticated Nuget feed</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/azdo/pills/vs-lose-authentication-to-nuget-feed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 08:12:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/azdo/pills/vs-lose-authentication-to-nuget-feed/</guid><description>The symptom is simple, you have a solution that uses some authenticated Nuget feed, like those hosted on Azure DevOps, suddenly Visual Studio stops authenticating and get a 401 error, or simply does not show any version of packages.
This is a problem that happens to some person recently and today was my turn. I have a build that published another version of a package to a private Azure DevOps feed and after publishing a new version, I start searching for that new version Visual Studio &amp;ldquo;manage nuget packages&amp;rdquo; but have no result.</description></item><item><title>Unable to execute NET core unit test in VS after uninstalling older sdk</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/11/unable-to-execute-net-core-unit-test-in-vs-after-uninstalling-older-sdk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/11/unable-to-execute-net-core-unit-test-in-vs-after-uninstalling-older-sdk/</guid><description>It is not uncommon to have installed many versions of.NET core framework, especially after many Visual Studio updates. Each installation consumes disk space so I’ve decided to cleanup everything leaving only major version of the framework installed in the system. Everything worked fine, except Visual Studio Test Explorer that, upon test run request, generates this error in Tests output window
[21/11/2019 6:08:03.911] ========== Discovery aborted: 0 tests found (0:00:05,5002292) ==========[21/11/2019 6:08:03.</description></item><item><title>Converting a big project to NET Standard without big bang</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/08/converting-a-big-project-to-net-standard-without-big-bang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/08/converting-a-big-project-to-net-standard-without-big-bang/</guid><description>When you have a big project in.NET full framework and you want to convert to.NET standard / core, usually MultiTargeting can be a viable solution to avoid a Big Bang conversion. You starts with the very first assembly in the chain of dependency, the one that does not depends on any other assembly in the project, and you start checking compatibility with.NET standard for all referenced NuGet Packages. Once the first project is done you proceed with the remaining.</description></item><item><title>Converting a big project to new VS2017 csproj format</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/10/converting-a-big-project-to-new-vs2017-csproj-format/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/10/converting-a-big-project-to-new-vs2017-csproj-format/</guid><description>Visual Studio 2017 introduced a new.csproj file format for C# project that is the key to move to.NET Standard but it is useful also for project with Full Framework, because is more human manageable.
The main drawback of this approach is that you end compatibility with older version of VS , if you open the.csproj with VS2015 you are not able to compile the project anymore. For this reason, switching to new format should be a decision that is well discussed in the team.</description></item><item><title>Test Explorer in VS 156</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/03/test-explorer-in-vs-15-6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/03/test-explorer-in-vs-15-6/</guid><description>The latest version of VS introduces some new cool feature, and it is quite big (almost 1 GB of download). If I should give you a single reason to upgrade to this new version, is the new Test Runner that now has the ability to show tests hierarchically Figure 1: Hierarchical view in action in Test Explorer.
Since I’m a great NUnit fan, I always like the ability to see my tests following the namespace structure of my test projects, this is surely much more better than a flat list.</description></item><item><title>Nuget packages for TFS VSO Client Object Model</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/08/nuget-packages-for-tfs-vso-client-object-model/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/08/nuget-packages-for-tfs-vso-client-object-model/</guid><description>Finally the Client Object Model for TFS / VSO is finally distributed with Nuget Packages, as you can read here. This is a great news especially because the Dll are finally redistributable, and your tool does not need to require a previous installation of Visual Studio or Team Explorer, or Client Object Model Package.
Another interesting fact, is that REST API are now supported for TFS 2015 / VSO (previous version of TFS does not support REST API).</description></item><item><title>Unable to debug dll source code with symbol server</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/06/unable-to-debug-dll-source-code-with-symbol-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/06/unable-to-debug-dll-source-code-with-symbol-server/</guid><description>I’ve blogged in the past about using a Symbol server and I recommend to all people to use symbol servers whenever possible , to helping people troubleshooting problem on dependencies. Basically with a symbol server you can reference a dll in your project, but you can debug original source code as if you have the original project linked instead of having the dll.
Sometimes this process just don’t work. Recently I’have a customer that had problem with this scenario, and the real strange stuff is: I’m able to step in dll source code without problem from any machine, but noone of the customer’s developers are able to make it work.</description></item><item><title>Team Project Rename</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/04/team-project-rename/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/04/team-project-rename/</guid><description>Renaming of Team Projects is one of the most requested feature on Visual Studio User Voice:
Figure 1: Team Project rename suggestion on User Voice
Today, Brian Harry announced new Visual Studio Online Update and it contains this feature, even if it will not be available to everyone at the beginning. For those people that uses TFS on-premise you will have this feature in the upcoming new version: TFS 2015.</description></item><item><title>Missing Developer Command prompt for Visual Studio 2013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/01/missing-developer-command-prompt-for-visual-studio-2013/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/01/missing-developer-command-prompt-for-visual-studio-2013/</guid><description>If you installed Visual Studio 2013 but you are not able to find the “developer command prompt” in your Windows 8 environment, the solution is simple. Just go to the folder
“C:\Program Files (x86)\Microsoft Visual Studio 12.0\Common7\Tools\Shortcuts”
Now right click on Developer Command Prompt for VS2013 and choose “pin to start” and the game is done.
Gian Maria.</description></item><item><title>Removing Network Emulation of Visual Studio Test Runner</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/11/removing-network-emulation-of-visual-studio-test-runner/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/11/removing-network-emulation-of-visual-studio-test-runner/</guid><description>Visual Studio has the ability to simulate network speeds during test executio n. This feature is nice especially for Load Test, because it permits to really simulate users that have different configuration speed. This ability is granted from a network component that gots installed in your TCP/IP stack and one of the question that usually arise is
I’ve enabled it in my machine, but now I want to remove because I’ve installed only to try to run a load test.</description></item><item><title>Manage Test Data in Visual Studio Database project</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/08/manage-test-data-in-visual-studio-database-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/08/manage-test-data-in-visual-studio-database-project/</guid><description>One of the greatest missing of Visual Studio Database Projects, is the ability to manage data in a Database Project. One widely used technique to overcome this limitation is using PostDeployment scripts and script data inserting. This technique is used also to insert test data inside the database. When used in this way, you need some way to avoid inserting test data in Production Database, so you need to find a technique that permits you to run the inserting test data only when needed.</description></item><item><title>Converting a Visual Studio plugin from 2012 to 2013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/07/converting-a-visual-studio-plugin-from-2012-to-2013/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/07/converting-a-visual-studio-plugin-from-2012-to-2013/</guid><description>I’ve some little utilities for Visual Studio, born as a Macro and then converted to Plugin. Now that VS 2013 preview is out, I want to convert that addin to support the new version of Visual Studio , so I can use my utilities even in VS 2013.
The whole conversion process is really straightforward, first of all I create a branch of the original VS2012 version of the plugin, just to be able to compile again with VS 2012.</description></item><item><title>Your configuration specifies to merge with the ref 8216master8217 from the remote but no such ref was fetched</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/your-configuration-specifies-to-merge-with-the-ref-master-from-the-remote-but-no-such-ref-was-fetched/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/your-configuration-specifies-to-merge-with-the-ref-master-from-the-remote-but-no-such-ref-was-fetched/</guid><description>A couple of times I encounter this error when I issue a command line pull of a Git repository hosted on TF Service:
Your configuration specifies to merge with the ref ‘master’
from the remote, but no such ref was fetched.
If you go to the.git folder and open the git configfile, I noticed the option tagopt set to –tags
I do not know if that option was setup from the initial Visual Studio clone option (VS Tools for git are still in beta) but removing it should fix the problem and you should be able to do a standard command line pull again</description></item><item><title>Unit Test class that makes use of HttpWebRequest thanks to Visual Studio fakes library</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/unit-test-class-that-makes-use-of-httpwebrequest-thanks-to-visual-studio-fakes-library/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/unit-test-class-that-makes-use-of-httpwebrequest-thanks-to-visual-studio-fakes-library/</guid><description>Thanks to Visual Studio Fakes is it possible to isolate your unit test and testing difficult to test code. Today I need to test a class that issues some Web Request around the internet and I’m concerned about testing the SUT when the web response contains some specific code like 404 (Not Found) or something.
If you simply right-click the reference to system assembly in your project and Add a fakes assembly, you probably will be annoyed by the fact that when you try to create a ShimHttpWebRequest you are not able to do it.</description></item><item><title>New Unit Test functionality in VS2012 Update 2 Test Playlist</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/03/new-unit-test-functionality-in-vs2012-update-2-test-playlist/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/03/new-unit-test-functionality-in-vs2012-update-2-test-playlist/</guid><description>In VS2012 we have support for basically any Unit Test Framework, because the new test runner is plugin based, and everyone can write plugin to make it compatible with the framework of choice. From the original version that was released with Visual Studio 2012 RTM, in Update 1 and Update 2 the test runner gained a lot of new feature, really useful for everyday work.
Update 2 introduced the concept of “Test Playlist” : basically a simple tool to create a subset of Unit Tests that are meant to be managed together.</description></item><item><title>Unable to build on TFS with a project managed with Nuget and automatic restore</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/03/unable-to-build-on-tfs-with-a-project-managed-with-nuget-and-automatic-restore/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/03/unable-to-build-on-tfs-with-a-project-managed-with-nuget-and-automatic-restore/</guid><description>To reduce the size of the repository and to easy dependencies management, nuget is a good solution, and when is time to create a build in TFS you can simply Enable Nuget Package Restore and let the build machine download the dependency for you. This works perfectly even on TF Service (tfs.visualstudio.com) because the Elastic Build is configured to restore packages during build. This is really cool, until your build start to fail for missing references.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio Plugin stop build at first error</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/visual-studio-plugin-stop-build-at-first-error/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/visual-studio-plugin-stop-build-at-first-error/</guid><description>When it is time to work with big solutions composed by many projects, it is useful to have the ability to stop the build at the very first build error. There are several reason to do this, first of all probably many of the subsequent error can be caused by the fact that a base project does not compile, or simply the build process takes a long time that it is not useful to continue the build when a project does not build , (quite often we are interested only in build the whole solution, so there is no point in waiting for all the other project to compile, because at the end everything we want to do is fixing the project that does not compile and try again to rebuild).</description></item><item><title>Converting Visual Studio Macro to Visual Studio plugin</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/converting-visual-studio-macro-to-visual-studio-plugin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/converting-visual-studio-macro-to-visual-studio-plugin/</guid><description>Visual Studio 2012 is really faster than 2010, this is due to an excellent work of the team to maximize performance and because in this release some of the older and less used part of the IDE were removed. One of this part is the Macro editor that is not anymore available in Visual Studio. This is one of the feature I missed most because I’ve used it in the past to automate some basic task, like attach to IIS automatically with a keyboard shortcut.</description></item><item><title>Location of your vsix files in experimental hive during plugin development</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/location-of-your-vsix-files-in-experimental-hive-during-plugin-development/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/location-of-your-vsix-files-in-experimental-hive-during-plugin-development/</guid><description>When you are developing Visual Studio plugin, your project is usually configured to launch a special instance of Visual Studio under the Visual Studio debugger (excellent example of dogfooding), this special instance is called experimental HIVE.
Figure 1: Configuration of a standard VSIX project to test your addin
As you can see the project is configured to start Visual Studio as external program to be debugged and it is started with the option /rootsuffix Exp to start in Experimental Hive.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio 2012 and TFS 2012 RC is finally out</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/06/visual-studio-2012-and-tfs-2012-rc-is-finally-out/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/06/visual-studio-2012-and-tfs-2012-rc-is-finally-out/</guid><description>Yesterday the Release Candidate of TFS2012 and Visual Studio 2012 were released by the Visual Studio team , you can download directly from Microsoft, and yes, the name is now officially Visual Studio 2012 and TFS 2012 :)
Visual Studio 2012 RC : http://www.microsoft.com/visualstudio/11/en-us
Team Foundation Server 2012 RC : http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=29918
If you are interested in the changes from the Beta you can check this MSDN Page, you can find also a lot of information from the Visual Studio ALM Rangers, that released the Readiness RC Wave full of important information.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshoot remote debugging of Managed Code</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/troubleshoot-remote-debugging-of-managed-code/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/troubleshoot-remote-debugging-of-managed-code/</guid><description>Setting up Remote Debugging is usually a simple task, you can read the Set Up Remote Debugging guide on MSDN and you are ready to go, but sometimes it does not work and you are not able to connect to the remote process; in this post I want to give you some suggestions to troubleshoot the most common problem that you can encounter.
First: you need to be aware that Remote Debugging Managed Code is only available when you use the authenticated mode, if you run the remote debugger without authentication you can debug only Native Code , but the main problem is that usually the host and remote machine * are not in the same Domain.</description></item><item><title>VS11 gives you a fantastic XAML Editor</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/vs11-gives-you-a-fantastic-xaml-editor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2012 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/vs11-gives-you-a-fantastic-xaml-editor/</guid><description>XAML editing in Visual Studio 2010 is not one of the most exiting experience you can have, it works, but compared to Blend it is really poor. One of the thing I really do not like is the lack of information on design time data. Since I really develop every XAML application with MVVM or MVVM like approach, I always have design time data and I’d like Visual Studio to be able to use it during binding operation.</description></item><item><title>Interesting links for Visual Studio 11 and TFS 11</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/interesting-links-for-visual-studio-11-and-tfs-11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/interesting-links-for-visual-studio-11-and-tfs-11/</guid><description>Yesterday Microsoft released a really huge wave of tools as well as the consumer preview of the upcoming operating system Windows 8. For Developers there are a lots of news to learn, especially on the new version of Visual Studio called VS11 , so I decided to create a blog post where I’ll try to list all interesting links related to VS11 Beta. I’ll try to keep this post updated</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio 11 beta is out</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/02/visual-studio-11-beta-is-out/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/02/visual-studio-11-beta-is-out/</guid><description>Finally the beta version of Visual Studio 11 is out, toghter with TFS 11 and windows 8 consumer preview. You can find informations and links to download here, you can also find standalone installer for various components of Visual Studio ALM at this address. All download can be found at the home page of the Visual Studio 11 Beta downloads.
For those ones that wants to read information about this new version there is a nice PDF full of information at this address ( http://go.</description></item><item><title>Customize output windows in Visual Studio</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/01/customize-output-windows-in-visual-studio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/01/customize-output-windows-in-visual-studio/</guid><description>I really like WPF for showing directly in the Visual Studio Output folder all binding errors, but one annoying stuff is that the output windows is usually crowded with all sort of stuff, so you have an hard life identifying the binding errors from all the other output contained in there. Since Visual Studio 2010 use WPF to render the output windows and use MEF for extension, modifying the aspect of the content of VS2010 is really simple.</description></item><item><title>Parallel build in VS2010</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/10/parallel-build-in-vs2010/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/10/parallel-build-in-vs2010/</guid><description>If you have solutions with multiple projects, compile time can increase a lot, but if you have multicore machine you can reduce compilation time using a little trick described in the blog of Scott Hanselman.
In a solution I work with, after a clean of the solution, standard build took 23 seconds to finish, while with this trick the build time is decreased to 14 seconds, so it worth trying it out :).</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio macro to group files</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/visual-studio-macro-to-group-files/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/visual-studio-macro-to-group-files/</guid><description>Visual Studio has the concept of grouping files together a feature used mainly from code generation tools to groups generated files under the main file, but this feature can be used even for your class, as shown in Figure1.
Figure 1 : Two code files nested inside program.cs
There are a lot of reasons to group files togheter, you can use this technique for group partial classes definition or you can simply want to group logically related files, etc etc.</description></item><item><title>Multi monitor remote desktop on a Windows 7 virtual machine</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/multi-monitor-remote-desktop-on-a-windows-7-virtual-machine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/multi-monitor-remote-desktop-on-a-windows-7-virtual-machine/</guid><description>To test dev 11 preview I’ve setup several virtual machines, just to be sure not to ruin my main installation box, since dev 11 is a developer previewand is not a good idea installing pre-beta release on production machine (even if dev 11 preview is really stable).
One of the annoying stuff in running inside a virtual machine is losing the ability to use all of your monitors… or not? If the virtualized and host operating system are Windows7 or Windows Server 2008, you can connect to the virtual machine using Remote Desktop (remember to enable it on windows7 because is not enabled by default), because it has full support for multiple monitors.</description></item><item><title>Macro to attach to local IIS take 3</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/macro-to-attach-to-local-iis-take-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2011 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/macro-to-attach-to-local-iis-take-3/</guid><description>This is the third post on the series create a macro to Attach to Local IIS. The last modification I want to implement is the ability to list all the w3wp.exe active processes, if more than one process is present, I want it to show a list of all IIS processes and let the user choose the list of processes to attach to. Clearly if I have no w3wp.exe active processes, or I have only one, there is no need to bother the user to choose the single available process.</description></item><item><title>Attach to local IIS Macro evolution</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/attach-to-local-iis-macro-evolution/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/attach-to-local-iis-macro-evolution/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve already blogged about the creation of a macro that permits you to attach to IIS worker process pressing a key combination. This approach does not work if you have multiple w3wp.exe processes that are actually running into your machine, because the macro only attach to the very first of them.
A simple and stupid solution is to attach to every w3wp.exe processes that is actually running in the system :), it is somewhat a patch solution, but it is really easy to implement, because it requires only a minor modification of the code generated by the Macro Recorder.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio Macro-Attach To Local IIS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/visual-studio-macroattach-to-local-iis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/visual-studio-macroattach-to-local-iis/</guid><description>As I stated previously, the capability of Visual Studio to use Macro is probably one of the less known feature and one of the coolest. Thanks to macro you can automate standard task you do in VS to speed-up your everyday coding experience. Since I work heavily with WCF services hosted in IIS and Web Application, quite often I need to attach the debugger to my local IIS instance.
This requires me to navigate to Debug-&amp;gt;Attach to process, show the list of processes, find the w3wp.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio Debugger Canvas</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/visual-studio-debugger-canvas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/visual-studio-debugger-canvas/</guid><description>Debugger Canvas is now released, it promises to be an useful addin for VS 2010 Ultimate to easy debugging process for big projects. The site has an introductory video that shows all major feature of this tool. First impression is really good, especially for the integration with the Intellitrace log, so I strongly suggest you to install it if you use the Ultimate version of Visual Studio.
Alk.</description></item><item><title>Visual studio Macro to the rescue</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/visual-studio-macro-to-the-rescue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/visual-studio-macro-to-the-rescue/</guid><description>If you heavily work with branches, one of the most frustrating error you can do is modify the wrong branch. I have a project composed by several solution each one containing different UI Projects, each one using WCF as back end but released as separate software. Whenever we do a release of a new version of one of the UI we create a branch, so we can support hotfix, SP, etc.</description></item><item><title>VS 2010 SP1 and PerformMsiOperation returned 0x643</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/03/vs-2010-sp1-and-performmsioperation-returned-0x643/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/03/vs-2010-sp1-and-performmsioperation-returned-0x643/</guid><description>Yesterday I tried to install Service Pack 1 for Visual Studio 2010, and the installation failed after few minutes. Looking in the logfile I found some errors:
PerformMsiOperation returned 0x643
The very first error is
The following applications should be closed before continuing the install:: , TfsCommandRunnerSvr, TfsCommandRunnerSvr (Process Id: 5844), TFS Power Tool Shell Extension (TfsComProviderSvr) [3/8/2011, 22:0:39] Returning IDIGNORE. INSTALLMESSAGE_FILESINUSE [User response to File In Use dialog]
The solution is to install SP1 after a clean reboot, Just login into the system and start installing SP1 before opening VS or using TFS Shell Extension.</description></item><item><title>Migrate MsTest of database edition to VS2010</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/02/migrate-mstest-of-database-edition-to-vs2010/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/02/migrate-mstest-of-database-edition-to-vs2010/</guid><description>I have a VS2008 project that is being converted to VS2010. This solution has a MsTest test project used to run database test against a Database project. After conversion you need to target the 4.0 framework for the test project, you run the test and you get
Microsoft.Build.BuildEngine.InvalidProjectFileException: Microsoft.Build.BuildEngine.InvalidProjectFileException: The expression &amp;ldquo;HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\Microsoft\VisualStudio\9.0\VSTSDB@VSTSDBDirectory&amp;rdquo; cannot be evaluated.. Aborting test execution
This is due to the fact that the test project probably references old version of the Microsoft.</description></item><item><title>Productivity power tools navigation</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/productivity-power-tools-navigation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/productivity-power-tools-navigation/</guid><description>With Visual Studio 2010 we are expecting a great number on new adding, made possible from the new extension point offered by MEF, and in general with the migration of part of the interface to WPF. One of the most exiting addin is the Productivity Power Tool released by Microsoft. It has a great number of features, but one of the most useful is the ability to browse code in a really advanced way.</description></item><item><title>First Visual studio 2010 addin</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/first-visual-studio-2010-addin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2010 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/first-visual-studio-2010-addin/</guid><description>Code Downloadable Here . Visual Studio is really a complex and big product, but it is amazing to see how simple it is to write an addin to extend its functionality. First of all we have a dedicated project type for writing an add-in from inside Visual Studio (dogfooding)
Choosing the Visual Studio Add-in a Wizard helps you to decide the type of the addin.The wizard asks for the language to use, and some information, like if the addin should be loaded at startup and if it must be listed under the tools menu.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio 2008 designer hangs</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/visual-studio-2008-designer-hangs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/visual-studio-2008-designer-hangs/</guid><description>This morning, while I was playing with uninstalling office 2010 beta and reinstalling office 2010 RTM I was working, as usually, on a web application.
I opened an aspx file, then click the Designer button, and Visual Studio 2008 hangs&amp;hellip;I waited a couple of minutes, then I terminated it. I verified and VS2008 is hanging every time I try to open a webform in design mode, going to Tools-&amp;gt;Options-&amp;gt;HTML Designer-&amp;gt;Css Styling, I have the very same problem, VS2008 completely freezed, and I need to terminate it from task manager.</description></item><item><title>Pay attention to file length in database project after a synchronization</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/pay-attention-to-file-length-in-database-project-after-a-synchronization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/pay-attention-to-file-length-in-database-project-after-a-synchronization/</guid><description>One of the coolest feature of Database Projects in VS2008 is the ability to synchronize the database project with a physical instance of SQL server.
This is useful if not all people from the team have the ability to run a database project (this is solved in vs2010 where database project are available even in the professional edition), or if some DBA makes modification to a database with management studio.</description></item><item><title>Create a SqlRule for database project in vs2010 beta2</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/12/create-a-sqlrule-for-database-project-in-vs2010-beta2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2009 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/12/create-a-sqlrule-for-database-project-in-vs2010-beta2/</guid><description>Custom Rule for database projects is one of my favorite extension point of Visual Studio 2008, and I blogged about it some time ago. Yesterday I tried to convert my sample rule for visual studio 2010 beta2, and there are a lot of things that are changed. The result will be a simple rule that force column name to be in form xxxx_xxxxxxxx as in the past example
First of all the extension needs to specify its details with attributes.</description></item><item><title>On a way to lab management</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/12/on-a-way-to-lab-management/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2009 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/12/on-a-way-to-lab-management/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m installing Lab Management, and since it is a complex environment some problems can arise. I&amp;rsquo;m following the four part tutorial that you can find here, and this morning I face the first problem.
When I try to add my Hyper-V host to the Vitual Machine Manager (SCVMM) I have this problem.
As you can see, when I try to add an Hyper-V enabled machine (The same where SCVMM is running) it tells me that virtualization software is Unknown, even if hyper-V is up and running fine.</description></item><item><title>Database Edition Custom Rule</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/database-edition-custom-rule/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/database-edition-custom-rule/</guid><description>One of the coolest feature of Visual Studio Database Edition is the ability to run Rules against a database project, like fxcop against a c# project. And the coolest part about this feature is that is really simple to write a custom rule.
Rules are important, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen project where there is no naming rule for objects in database, and so you will end with tables with column like, ablr_xxxx or xxxxx_xxx_Authorname etc etc, and the whole database looses consistency over time.</description></item><item><title>vsdbcmdexe overriding variable value</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/vsdbcmd-exe-overriding-variable-value/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2009 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/vsdbcmd-exe-overriding-variable-value/</guid><description>When you deploy a database project with the command line utility vsdbcmd.exe you may want to change the value of some variables of the project. Suppose you&amp;rsquo;ve created a variable called Path1
And you have used this variable to specify the location of the files
1 2 ALTER DATABASE [$(DatabaseName)] ADD FILE (NAME = [Northwind], FILENAME = &amp;#39;$(Path1)$(DatabaseName).mdf&amp;#39;, Now you want to decide at deploy time the physical location of your database.</description></item><item><title>Data Dude for Visual Studio 2010</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/data-dude-for-visual-studio-2010/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/data-dude-for-visual-studio-2010/</guid><description>For those out there that are, like me, fans of Data Dude, here is a link that shows you the news about Data Dude in VS2010.
The most appealing part is that database projects are now supported starting from VS professional edition, so I&amp;rsquo;m expecting that more and more people will try to manage databases with Visual Studio. Clearly most of the features are still available only for VS Premium or VS Ultimate users, but at least, people with professional can compile a DB Project, Execute unit testing or data generation plan (but only people with Premium and Ultimate are able to create and manage them).</description></item><item><title>Data Driven Test of a stored procedure in Database Edition</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/data-driven-test-of-a-stored-procedure-in-database-edition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/data-driven-test-of-a-stored-procedure-in-database-edition/</guid><description>Database Tests are really a great feature of Database Edition, and, like other tests, you can create a Data Driven Test of a stored procedure with little effort. The first stuff I do is to create a database project that will contains a table for each sets of data I want to use in a test.
In this project I create a table for each sets of data, and create a script to preload the data as post-deployment script.</description></item><item><title>Coded Ui Test in VS 2010</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/coded-ui-test-in-vs-2010/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/coded-ui-test-in-vs-2010/</guid><description>I must admit that I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely not a fan of testing through UI. A good program keeps the business logic separated from the UI, so it is testable without passing for the UI. In the real world we have application written by others, or you can simply have to test UI control interaction. In these scenario interacting with the UI can be a viable option. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how VS2010 can helps us.</description></item><item><title>Some news on Visual studio 2010 database project</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/some-news-on-visual-studio-2010-database-project/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/some-news-on-visual-studio-2010-database-project/</guid><description>You can find some good news here for Data Dude project system. The most important one is that with VS2010 you will have database project support even with professional edition. You miss some of the advanced features, but you are able to build and deploy database project, and this is really good.
Another point of interest is that Data Dude is installed with TFS build agent, so you do not need to devote one license to the machine where the build agent runs, and this is great.</description></item><item><title>Mvp Team System</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/mvp-team-system/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2009 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/mvp-team-system/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve already announced on my Italian blog, yesterday I received the communication from Microsoft that I awarded a MVP in Team System category. I&amp;rsquo;m very exited for this, and I want to say thanks to all people that read my blog.
Alk.</description></item><item><title>Correct use of a Source Control System branching for long time task</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/09/correct-use-of-a-source-control-system-branching-for-long-time-task/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/09/correct-use-of-a-source-control-system-branching-for-long-time-task/</guid><description>Source control system is probably developer&amp;rsquo;s best friend, but quite often people use only a small percentage of its functionalities. One of the most missed feature is a correct use of a branch. Let&amp;rsquo;s make a concrete example. Suppose that developer A needs to implement a big feature, it estimates a week to complete it, and while he is working at this feature he needs also to modify some basic part of the system.</description></item><item><title>Faster Database Test With database in Virtual Disk</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/09/faster-database-test-with-database-in-virtual-disk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/09/faster-database-test-with-database-in-virtual-disk/</guid><description>When you work with Visual Studio Database Edition, you surely love the data generation plans, and the ability to do database unit testing with automatic deploy and automatic preload. There is only one thing that is bad with database testing, they are usually slowbecause they are accessing disks*.*
To speedup database testing the best solution is to test database in memory, but with sql server it can be difficult&amp;hellip;or not? With a simple software that create a RAMDisk, (a disk made of ram like Dataram one), you are able to create RAMDisk with few clicks and have a disk that actually runs at memory speed.</description></item><item><title>Failed to deploy database project error during database testing</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/failed-to-deploy-database-project-error-during-database-testing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2009 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/failed-to-deploy-database-project-error-during-database-testing/</guid><description>When you create database test in a MsTest project, usually it configure an initialization method that deploy the database schema before test runs.
1 2 3 4 5 6 [AssemblyInitialize()] public static void IntializeAssembly(TestContext ctx) { //Setup the test database based on setting in the //configuration file DatabaseTestClass.TestService.DeployDatabaseProject(); If something went wrong during this phase you probably will end with this not so much useful error message: Failed to deploy database project &amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Code analysis for Sql Project</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/code-analysis-for-sql-project/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2009 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/code-analysis-for-sql-project/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m not a fanatic of Code Analysis, at least I know that it is quite impractical trying to remove all warning of fxcop analysis, but I strongly advice you to run code analysis on your code, and give it a shot from time to time. First of all is a good way to find potential bug, then you will always learn new and more standard way to write your code.</description></item><item><title>Test database with Nunit make easy with Visual Studio Team System For Database Edition</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/test-database-with-nunit-make-easy-with-visual-studio-team-system-for-database-edition/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2009 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/test-database-with-nunit-make-easy-with-visual-studio-team-system-for-database-edition/</guid><description>I have a project born without VSTS database edition, all tests to database are done using custom preload scripts that run.sql scripts to regenerate a sandbox database to use for unit testing. This turns to be a quite good system, but it requires manteniance, since every time you change the database you also need to change sql file to recreate the new structure to run tests.
My goal is to fully automate this process, avoiding manual intervention and running everything in a standard NUNIT project, and make test runnable even from programmer that does not have visual studio database edition installed.</description></item></channel></rss>