<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Programming on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/programming/</link><description>Recent content in Programming on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 08:13:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Symbol server made easy with Azure DevOps</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/programming/aspnet/working-with-symbols/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 08:13:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/programming/aspnet/working-with-symbols/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve blogged in the past about symbol server, to recap here is the scenario.
In your organization you have some sort of common .NET code that is shared between projects, but you have to face and resolve some problems.
How to compile dlls How to distribute dlls How to make debugging easier for the user of the dll. We have clearly some standard solution for all the parts.</description></item><item><title>GitHub security scan - an example</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/github-security-scanning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 15:10:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/github-security-scanning/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve already blogged on the security scanning capability offered by GitHub and in this post I want to give you another example on a possible output. In previous example I&amp;rsquo;ve shown a result that is quite simple the library identified a usage of ECB in AES encryption and flagged it as a wrong usage of crypto api. It is interesting but less impressive, after all it simply spotted the usage of an enum value related to a vulnerable CypherMode, something that it easy to spot.</description></item><item><title>Playing with Cryptography, Part 1</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/playing-with-cryptography-part1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 09:13:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/playing-with-cryptography-part1/</guid><description>Cryptography is a fascinating subject, surely complex, but as a developer you probably have some predefined libraries in your language/environment of choice that you can use. DotNet is not an exception, so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to create a sample repository to play a little bit with all cryptography primitives to show how easy is to use them https://github.com/alkampfergit/DotNetCoreCryptography.
This is not a tutorial, it is more a repository where I played with API to gain more confidence with .</description></item><item><title>Principle of least privilege</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/principle-of-least-privilege/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 08:13:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/principle-of-least-privilege/</guid><description>This is the fourth article in a series of post dealing on why it is important to strictly validate user input.
Do not trust user input part 1 Do not trust user input part 2 Do not trust user input part 3 Validate User Input part 4 Do not disclose errors to the User part 5 A brief recap Let&amp;rsquo;s return to the beginning, the very first version of the vulnerable function.</description></item><item><title>Do Not Disclose Errors to the User</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/do-not-disclose-error-to-the-user/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 22:13:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/security/do-not-disclose-error-to-the-user/</guid><description>This is the fourth article in a series of post dealing on why it is important to strictly validate user input.
Do not trust user input part 1 Do not trust user input part 2 Do not trust user input part 3 Validate User Input part 4 In the last post we analyzed how it is not fully possible to limit user input in some functions like search. The user could almost search for every character and it is not easy to impose a maximum length.</description></item><item><title>ProtocolViolationException when writing on response NetworkStream in c</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/09/protocolviolationexception-when-writing-on-response-networkstream-in-c/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/09/protocolviolationexception-when-writing-on-response-networkstream-in-c/</guid><description>I have a piece of code that is returning data with an HttpListener, but I have intermittent error in logs
Bytes to be written to the stream exceed the Content-Length bytes size specified
I wonder where is the error, because the code is simply returning a string with proper encoding and the ContentLength64 property of the Response was set correctly.
1 2 3 4 5 byte[] buffer = Encoding.</description></item><item><title>Dealing with a lot of data usually lot of problems</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/04/dealing-with-a-lot-of-data-usually-lot-of-problems/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/04/dealing-with-a-lot-of-data-usually-lot-of-problems/</guid><description>I’ve just read a post of my friend Mauro, “Dealing with log of Data” and I really agree with his position, because projects that needs to manage big amount of data usually brings a lot of problems both on production server, but also on the everyday developer life.
We tend to think that since disk space is quite cheap in these days , it is not a big problem, but this is usually false.</description></item><item><title>Change the icon of a folder</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/change-the-icon-of-a-folder/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2011 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/change-the-icon-of-a-folder/</guid><description>I need to change the default icon of Windows Explorer for some special folder inside a my application, I know that it could be done Through Desktop.Ini file, but after some frustrating tentative I did not succeed in using a custom.ico file stored as resource inside the assembly.
It was my fault, because the first resource you should check is MSDN, and when I read the whole page dedicate to this argument I found my error, I forgot to set the System Bit of the folder.</description></item><item><title>GeckoFX for c strange behavior</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/01/geckofx-for-c-strange-behavior/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/01/geckofx-for-c-strange-behavior/</guid><description>Today I faced a very strange problem with GeckoBrowser, after navigating a page I simply need to grab all the HTML of the page to analyze it. I try to access the * GeckoBrowser.Document.TextContentv *property but it is always null.
I searched on the web and found this discussion but it does not work, because the DocumentElement.InnerHtml throws a nullreferenceexception, how sad. In that post a user suggest to download the text manually, but saving bandwidth is one of the requirements, so I really need to use the HTML already downloaded by Gecko Browser.</description></item><item><title>WebBrowser control and Gecko Browser control in a single UI</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/10/webbrowser-control-and-gecko-browser-control-in-a-single-ui/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/10/webbrowser-control-and-gecko-browser-control-in-a-single-ui/</guid><description>I works quite often in last months with WPF programs that need to include a browser control, and the obvious choice is using WebBrowser control. In last days we need to use Gecko Browser, because we like the ability to customize it and to make possible for the user to look at a site with IE rendering or Firefox Rendering.
After some fighting and with the help of my friend Stefano Castriotta we finally manage to have it works now I have a program where you can switch the browser control at real time and with a single click.</description></item><item><title>What Did you start programming on</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/08/what-did-you-start-programming-on/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/08/what-did-you-start-programming-on/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just read this nice blog post, and I want to give my contribute to it :).
I&amp;rsquo;ve started programming on a Vic20 Commodore computer, I began just with copying a couple of programs that are in the manual, and immediately being curious about the Basic language.
So I moved to a Vic20 programming course in Cassette and this was the very first thing that amazed me, the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m able to record a program on a audio cassette, I believed that they could be used only for music.</description></item><item><title>Change base directory of a site in IIS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/change-base-directory-of-a-site-in-iis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/change-base-directory-of-a-site-in-iis/</guid><description>This technique works for IIS6 and IIS7 with the &amp;ldquo;IIS 6 WMI Compatibility* installed. The purpose is changing the directory of a web site in a remote server. The purpose of this action will be clear in a future post, for now only assume that you want to be able to create a piece of c# code that changes directory of a web site in windows server. Here is a test site.</description></item><item><title>Dto generator and repository integration</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/dto-generator-and-repository-integration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/dto-generator-and-repository-integration/</guid><description>I have a project where I use repository pattern, interface code access domain object through a service, and the service return Dto. One of the bad side of the dto is that they are boring to write and to maintain. The main risk is that developers does this error
Mmmm I had to show a combo with all the typologies of the current customer, let me seee, I have already a service that return Typlogy object given the customer Id, ok I&amp;rsquo;ll use it.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on software engineering</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/thoughts-on-software-engineering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2009 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/thoughts-on-software-engineering/</guid><description>I was reading this post of Jeff Atwood that link this interesting article. One of the key point in the article was to consider two different kind of projects
Project A will eventually cost about a million dollars and produce value of around $1.1 million. Project B will eventually cost about a million dollars and produce value of more than $50 million. And the conclusion is that *control is more important in project A and not in project B,*and another astonishing sentence in the article was</description></item><item><title>Manipulation of configuration files for deploy</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/manipulation-of-configuration-files-for-deploy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/manipulation-of-configuration-files-for-deploy/</guid><description>In my experience, one of the most feared problem during the going in production phase of an asp.net site or a complex project is configurations. Usually everything works perfectly on developer machines, but when you move the project in production machines all sort of problems appear.
For Asp.Net, one day one of my colleagues called me asking a little help troubleshooting some performance problem of a site in production, the problem was so big that after a couple of hours the application goes into memory overflow exception.</description></item><item><title>error MSB3321 Importing key file xxx was canceled</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/error-msb3321-importing-key-file-xxx-was-canceled/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 01:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/error-msb3321-importing-key-file-xxx-was-canceled/</guid><description>I start to got this error from my Continuous integration machine, after I setup a project for deploy with clickonce the build begins to fail. I&amp;rsquo;m using CC.net with msbuild scripts and in detailed error I see a message like
The &amp;ldquo;ResolveKeySource&amp;rdquo; task failed unexpectedly.
System.InvalidOperationException: Showing a modal dialog box or form when the application is not running in UserInteractive mode is not a valid operation. Specify the ServiceNotification or DefaultDesktopOnly style to display a notification from a service application.</description></item></channel></rss>