<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 08:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pip and Python in Visual Studio Code</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/pip-and-python-in-vscode/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/pip-and-python-in-vscode/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m not a Python expert, but I used it more often these days and I use Visual Studio Code with Python extension to author my scripts. One of the most annoying problem is receiving a no module named xxx error when you already installed that module with pip.
Figure 1: No module error when running Python code in Visual Studio Code
The problem arise because Visual Studio Code is not using the very same installation of python you are using from your command line / terminal.</description></item><item><title>Sonar Analysis of Python with Azure DevOps pipeline</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/01/sonar-analysis-of-python-with-azure-devops-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/01/sonar-analysis-of-python-with-azure-devops-pipeline/</guid><description>Once you have test and Code Coverage for your build of Python code, last step for a good build is adding support for Code Analysis with Sonar/SonarCloud. SonarCloud is the best option if your code is open source, because it is free and you should not install anything except the free addin in Azure Devops Marketplace.
From original build you need only to add two steps: PrepareAnalysis onSonarCloud and Run SonarCloud analysis, in the same way you do analysis for a.</description></item><item><title>Run code coverage for Python project with Azure DevOps</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/11/run-code-coverage-for-python-project-with-azure-devops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/11/run-code-coverage-for-python-project-with-azure-devops/</guid><description>Creating a simple build that runs Python tests written with PyTest framework is really simple, but now the next step is trying to have code coverage. Even if I’m pretty new to Python, having code coverage in a build is really simple, thanks to a specific task that comes out-of-the-box with Azure DevOps: Publish Code Coverage.
In Azure DevOps you can create build with Web Editor or with simple YAML file, I prefer YAML but since I’ve demonstrated in the old post YAML build for Python, now I’m creating a simple build with standard Web Editor</description></item></channel></rss>