<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OpenXml on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/openxml/</link><description>Recent content in OpenXml on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 06:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/openxml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create Charts in excel with Open Xml Sdk 25</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/08/create-charts-in-excel-with-open-xml-sdk-2-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/08/create-charts-in-excel-with-open-xml-sdk-2-5/</guid><description>&lt;p>OpenXml Sdk is absolutely a fantastic library to &lt;strong>programmatically create Office documents&lt;/strong> , but when it is time to add Chart components in Excel I‘m starting to feel the pain. I’ve searched in MSDN to find resource on “how to create a chart in Excel with OpenXmlSdk 2.5” and the only resource I’ve found is this article: &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/office/cc820055.aspx">How to: Insert a chart into a Spreadhseet document&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The article is good, but you immediately realize that the code is not so simple and that is not easy to understand how to modify it to suite your need. In my specific scenario &lt;strong>I need a Pie Chart and I need also to create a chart that use data located in the same workbook of the Chart Itself&lt;/strong>. Moreover the customer want to choose the format of the graph, with all the 3D options available in Excel 2013. The result is that the aforementioned example in MSDN is quite useless.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Xml Project</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/open-xml-project/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/open-xml-project/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve received some comments in an old &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2008/08/29/openxml-office-format-open-and-substitute-text/">post&lt;/a>, regarding the manipulation of docx documents, with the purpose of substitute parts of the original document with &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2008/09/08/manage-image-in-openxml-format-part2/">images&lt;/a> or pieces of text. I&amp;rsquo;ve blogged also how to use &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2008/11/28/create-a-report-in-excel-2007-with-open-xml-sdk-10/">Excel&lt;/a> to create reports, and populate data programmatically with OpenXml standard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The original code was developed for an Italian company named &lt;a href="http://www.actvalue.com">ActValue&lt;/a> I collaborate with, and some people asked me to publish the full code. I cannot publish the exact version of the current library, but, thanks to the courtesy of &lt;a href="http://www.actvalue.com">ActValue&lt;/a>, I can now publish an old version of the code, that contains all the techniques I&amp;rsquo;ve described in my old post about &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/?s=openxml">OpenXml&lt;/a> Format.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>