<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Books on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/books/</link><description>Recent content in Books on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 17:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Professional Team Foundation Server 2013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/05/professional-team-foundation-server-2013/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/05/professional-team-foundation-server-2013/</guid><description>If the book “Professional Application Lifecycle Management With Visual Studio 2013” is the perfect companion for all members of a software project team using Visual Studio ALM ecosystem, Professional Team Foundation Server 2013 is aimed mainly to “TFS Administrators”.
This book covers every information needed to operate with TFS, it starts with a series of chapters dedicated to Planning, Installing and configuring TFS in your environment, giving you all the details to install the configuration that most suites your need.</description></item><item><title>Professional Application Lifecycle Management With Visual Studio 2013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/05/professional-application-lifecycle-management-with-visual-studio-2013/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2014 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/05/professional-application-lifecycle-management-with-visual-studio-2013/</guid><description>If you use or plan to use Team Foundation Server or Visual Studio Online, this is the book for you.
Professional Application Lifecycle Management with Visual Studio 2013 covers all aspects and tools of Microsoft ALM Ecosystem , giving you all the details on how to implement effectively ALM for your team/s. This book is dedicated to all people involved in a Software Project, from managers who plan work with new Portfolio Management features, to developers that create the product, and finally to testers and end users that could monitor quality with Microsoft Test Manager and Feedback Tool.</description></item><item><title>Electronic bookshellip are they the future</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/10/electronic-books-are-they-the-future/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/10/electronic-books-are-they-the-future/</guid><description>Probably not, until these are the prices
I know that with electronic version I don&amp;rsquo;t spend the shipping cost (That for me in Italy are quite high respect citizen in the US) and I got my book almost istantaneously, but it seems to me ridiculous that the electronic version of the book actually costs MORE than the printed version.
Until price of E-Books are so high, they will not replace the paper form in my opinion.</description></item></channel></rss>