<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nablasoft on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/nablasoft/</link><description>Recent content in Nablasoft on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 12:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/nablasoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Disabled permalink on the site</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/disabled-permalink-on-the-site/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 12:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/disabled-permalink-on-the-site/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve disabled all the permalinks on my site. They ceased to work with no reason, both on my blog and guardian&amp;rsquo;s one (www.nablasoft.com/guardian). After a couple of days, we still do not know why, it seems that suddenly, with no apparent reason, some setting on php.ini are now ignored. I know that wordpress in IIS has some problems with permalink, but with fix_pathinfo trick everything worked for more than one year.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to New Nablasoft Blog</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/welcome-to-new-nablasoft-blog/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2008 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/welcome-to-new-nablasoft-blog/</guid><description>I forget to welcome guardian’s home the new blog of another nablasoft member. After long time it seems that he now realized that blogging is a real interesting activity to do.
Since He is a better graphic designer than me (I think I can tell the same of everyone, I’m a really poor graphic designer) he spent some time to improve the look of the site….it reminds me that I really need to improve the layout of my blog.</description></item><item><title>Google analytics</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/05/google-analytics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2007 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/05/google-analytics/</guid><description>I have to admit that WordPress is a great blog engine, today I activated google analytics, and after a 10 seconds search I found a plugin to insert automatically the analytics code in the blog. I must admit that even if I’m a.NET programmer php blogs such WordPress are still superior.
Alk.</description></item><item><title>First blog</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/04/first-blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2007 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/04/first-blog/</guid><description>This is the first blog on word press, we switched the hosting from italy to IX web hosting that will give us more tools and the possibility to use a lot of database space for ours blog.
Alk.</description></item></channel></rss>