<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pull Requests on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/pull-requests/</link><description>Recent content in Pull Requests on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 08:10:42 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/pull-requests/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pill: Enhancing DevOps with Automated Pull Requests</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/azdo/pills/automatic-pull-request-close/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 08:10:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/azdo/pills/automatic-pull-request-close/</guid><description>Pull requests are a cornerstone of collaborative software development, particularly with distributed version control systems like Git and platforms such as GitHub or Azure DevOps. However, managing pull requests can become cumbersome, particularly for branches undergoing extensive modifications and receiving frequent feedback. This complexity is evident when preparing a pull request only to find it needs additional changes due to peer review, necessitating a complete retest of the code.
Such workflows highlight the challenges in finalizing a branch.</description></item><item><title>Resolving Credential Conflicts in Git</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/github/pills/multiple-credentials-in-credential-manager/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 08:10:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/github/pills/multiple-credentials-in-credential-manager/</guid><description>Have you ever found yourself being asked to select a GitHub account every time you make a push? This is often due to multiple access tokens being stored in your Windows credential manager.
The Git Credential Manager can become confused when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t know which account to use. It&amp;rsquo;s only option in these situations is to ask you which of the stored credentials it should utilize.
Figure 1: Command line interface suddenly opens a window asking you to select accounts.</description></item><item><title>Using GitHub Command Line Tool to View Pull Request Info</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/github/pills/gh_command_line_tool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 08:10:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/github/pills/gh_command_line_tool/</guid><description>For people like me who prefer using Git in the command line, there are times when I need to retrieve information about pull requests or other GitHub related tasks. For example, suppose I need to share a link to a pull request that is under review with one of my colleagues for them to comment on. Sure, I could navigate to the GitHub website, locate the repository, navigate to the pull request page and get the link.</description></item></channel></rss>