<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gecko on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/gecko/</link><description>Recent content in Gecko on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 14:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/gecko/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GeckoFX for c strange behavior</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/01/geckofx-for-c-strange-behavior/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/01/geckofx-for-c-strange-behavior/</guid><description>Today I faced a very strange problem with GeckoBrowser, after navigating a page I simply need to grab all the HTML of the page to analyze it. I try to access the * GeckoBrowser.Document.TextContentv *property but it is always null.
I searched on the web and found this discussion but it does not work, because the DocumentElement.InnerHtml throws a nullreferenceexception, how sad. In that post a user suggest to download the text manually, but saving bandwidth is one of the requirements, so I really need to use the HTML already downloaded by Gecko Browser.</description></item><item><title>WebBrowser control and Gecko Browser control in a single UI</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/10/webbrowser-control-and-gecko-browser-control-in-a-single-ui/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/10/webbrowser-control-and-gecko-browser-control-in-a-single-ui/</guid><description>I works quite often in last months with WPF programs that need to include a browser control, and the obvious choice is using WebBrowser control. In last days we need to use Gecko Browser, because we like the ability to customize it and to make possible for the user to look at a site with IE rendering or Firefox Rendering.
After some fighting and with the help of my friend Stefano Castriotta we finally manage to have it works now I have a program where you can switch the browser control at real time and with a single click.</description></item></channel></rss>