<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Office on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/office/</link><description>Recent content in Office on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 10:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/office/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use different Excel TFS VSTS Addin at the same time</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/09/use-different-excel-tfs-vsts-addin-at-the-same-time/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/09/use-different-excel-tfs-vsts-addin-at-the-same-time/</guid><description>If you are a consultant, it is quite common that you work with various version of TFS Server at the same time. I have my personal account on VSTS, always updated to the latest version, but I have also customer that still uses TFS 2012 or TFS 2010.
Microsoft test newer version of TFS against lots of applications to be sure that newer versions of TFS do not break usage of existing tools.</description></item><item><title>Open Xml Project</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/open-xml-project/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/open-xml-project/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve received some comments in an old post, regarding the manipulation of docx documents, with the purpose of substitute parts of the original document with images or pieces of text. I&amp;rsquo;ve blogged also how to use Excel to create reports, and populate data programmatically with OpenXml standard.
The original code was developed for an Italian company named ActValue I collaborate with, and some people asked me to publish the full code.</description></item><item><title>OpenXml excel and formulas</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/openxml-excel-and-formulas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/openxml-excel-and-formulas/</guid><description>In an old post, I deal with a simple way to create excel report using openXml format. The trick is a simple manipulation of the document with Linq to Xml.
Now I need to add another feature, I need to open an excel document with formulas, fill some cells, leaving formulas intact. My first version does not work as expected, I simply created an excel with simple formulas, then fire my function and when I open the resulting excel I see all zero on formula column, but the formula is there, and if I change some cell referenced by the formula I&amp;rsquo;ll obtain the right value.</description></item><item><title>Manage image in openXml format part2</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/manage-image-in-openxml-format-part2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/manage-image-in-openxml-format-part2/</guid><description>In a previous post I deal with image insertion into an openXml document. Now it is time to show how to change image dimension, I want to be able to define new dimension and to choose if the image should be stretched or no. The w:drawingelement has two distinct part to manage image dimension, the first is the wp:extentnode, child of the wp:inline one.
This node determines the extent of the area of the document that will contain the image, but to really change dimension of the image we should operate in a different tag:</description></item><item><title>OpenXml format insert an image into a document</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/openxml-format-insert-an-image-into-a-document/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/openxml-format-insert-an-image-into-a-document/</guid><description>In previous post I showed how to open a docx file, search for a specific text, and replace the text with another string. The reason for doing this is simply to create a master report file in docx format, and let an application insert data in specific part of the document itself.
The next step is to substitute text with an image, this is a more complex process, because we need first to insert the image into the package, then we need to reference it in the main document.</description></item><item><title>OpenXml Office format open and substitute text</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/openxml-office-format-open-and-substitute-text/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2008 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/openxml-office-format-open-and-substitute-text/</guid><description>Quite often, customers ask us to generate reports in word format, the main advantage of this approach is that people feels comfortable working with word, and they love the possibility to modify the report once generated. In the past years I used many techniques to reach this goal, but in the end, a lot of time ago I resort to write a simple RTF generator that suites my needs.
In these days I reach the point where the complexities of the documents became really difficult to manage with RTF generator, moreover we need a software that permits the customers to create a master word document, then the software should only makes substitution in some prefixed part with the real data.</description></item></channel></rss>