<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>general on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/general/</link><description>Recent content in general on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 08:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Generate Git graph with Gitgraph.js and Python</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/git-graph/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/git-graph/</guid><description>GitGraph is a nice library to create a graphic representation of Git log and the really nice aspect is that it is widely used and produces picture that are easily recognized as Git History. It can basically work in many ways, but the easiest is importing commit as json in an HTML page.
Thanks to very few lines of Python code I realized a simple POC that is able to use git log to extract log as json then create an html page with extracted json that renders a simple png with the full history.</description></item><item><title>How to create a list of non upgradable software for winget</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/winget-update-selective/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/winget-update-selective/</guid><description>Winget is finally here and we can, at least, using a package manager on windows to simplify application management. Everything is good, except that some packages are not ready to be upgraded. As an example in my system I have python 2.7 and 3.x, winget always try to upgrade 3.x version at each run and messed up my installation. At the end of the Nth upgrade of python my Visual Studio code was not able anymore to debug and run python.</description></item><item><title>How to resolve hostname in a WSL instance with internal IP</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/wsl-hostname/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 18:40:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/wsl-hostname/</guid><description>Edit: actually I missed that I can add mshome.net to host name to correctly identify the ip of the host computer, like suggested here
In a WSL2 instance you are running inside a Virtual Environment managed by your Windows Operating system, and the greatest advantage is the ability to work with a unified filesystem and being able to have a great communication between the two system. This is perfect but I have a small problem, if I want to use the WSL2 instance to test some software I&amp;rsquo;m developing I&amp;rsquo;d like to access services running on my host operating system.</description></item><item><title>Winget is finally a thing</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/winget-intro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/winget-intro/</guid><description>After a really loooooong time, finally Windows has its own Package Manager called Windows Package Manager 1.0. It was firstly announced last year at build, but with 2021 build conference it was announced that it is now in version 1.0. I do not want to do a full coverage of all the features, but simply share why this is a thing.
Linux users had package managers from almost the beginning, this imply that to install all of your favorite tools, you can simply use command line to install everything.</description></item><item><title>Quick ftp upload of multiple files</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/quick-ftp-upload-for-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/quick-ftp-upload-for-blog/</guid><description>After conversion of all of my blog posts, I have more than 1000 page to upload, and even if I left old image in original location my publish time increased a lot as you can see from Figure 1.
Figure 1: Upload time is becoming unbearable
I&amp;rsquo;ve scheduled automatic publish with GitHub Actions, but using a standard ftp action I&amp;rsquo;ve found in the marketplace, my build time increased from 5 minutes to more than one hour.</description></item><item><title>Moving old posts from WordPress to Hugo</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/conversion-of-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/conversion-of-wordpress/</guid><description>It was almost one year from my switch from WordPress to Hugo and I&amp;rsquo;m really really satisfied from the result. After some months the only thing that bother me is the fact that I still need to maintain an instance of WordPress just to keep old posts. The only thing that prevented me to migrate was the loss of comments, but actually, after looking to all of my old blog posts, I&amp;rsquo;ve not such a big amount of comments that worth migrating, the only thing that is important to me is the ability to keep my old post without comments so I can get rid of WordPress.</description></item><item><title>Speedup WSUS in your AD (Part 2)</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/speed-up-wsus-part2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/speed-up-wsus-part2/</guid><description>After I did some maintenance on my WSUS with some tricks I still had problem, after hours of cleanup, PowerShell script stopped working and constantly gave me a timeout.
Figure 1: WSUS was unable to perform cleanup
I did not had time to investigate the issue, but I got saved in my disk a small notes I&amp;rsquo;ve found somewhere that suggested how to cleanup manually directly with SQL.
1 2 EXEC spGetObsoleteUpdatesToCleanup EXEC spDeleteUpdate @localUpdateID=&amp;lt;LocalUpdateID&amp;gt; In such situation my temptation to wipe out everything and start a new WSUS is really high, but I always resort on spending a little time trying to do some manual tentative.</description></item><item><title>Speedup WSUS in your AD</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/speed-up-wsus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/speed-up-wsus/</guid><description>I have a very old HP Proliant Microserver, it has 16 GB of RAM and an SSD, but it is really old, it is powered by a really old Turion CPU and WSUS is starting to becoming unresponsive. That machine act as a test domain controller for a bunch of test virtual machines, WSUS always was a little bit slow, but it worked, until few days ago, when it constantly fails to load data.</description></item><item><title>GitHub Codespaces first impression</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/github-codespaces-first-impression/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/github-codespaces-first-impression/</guid><description>What is GitHub codespaces Visual Studio Code is becoming one of the most used and productive editors in all operating system and it is used by most developers. During these years Visual Studio Code introduced lots of interesting features, like the ability to connect to Linux or Docker Container and develop inside that container. This means that your machine can run Windows / Linux / MacOS or whatever, but you can connect to a Linux machine or Linux Docker instance and develop inside that container</description></item><item><title>Double T shaped professional</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/double-t-shaped-professional/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 18:40:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/double-t-shaped-professional/</guid><description>The term T-Shaped Professional or T-Shaped Skills is widely used to identify a person that has a good deep knowledge in a specific area and a broad knowledge on other areas.
This kind of professional is perfect to fit into DevOps culture, because it can collaborate better with others in the team. As an example, a front-end Developer usually has the leg of his T in web technologies (angular, Typescript, HTML, etc.</description></item><item><title>Set ip of WSL2 machine in host file</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/powershell/wsl2-set-ip-in-hosts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/powershell/wsl2-set-ip-in-hosts/</guid><description>I have a WSL2 ubuntu installation where I have SAMBA installed and I really need it to answer to a specific name, something like \ubuntuwsl.
In WSL2 the machine got its IP assigned from Hyper-V so it is dynamic and change at each reboot
To solve this problem it is interesting to look on how you can interact to your WSL2 distribution from PowerShell, this exercise will show you how powerful WSL2 is.</description></item><item><title>Some fix for Word Exporter</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/azdo/misc/export-to-word-img-and-work-item-type/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/azdo/misc/export-to-word-img-and-work-item-type/</guid><description>This is another post in the series &amp;ldquo;how to export Work Item data to Word Document&amp;rdquo;.
Complete code for project can be found in GitHub - https://github.com/alkampfergit/AzureDevopsWordPlayground
Post in the series:
API Connection Retrieve Work Items Information Azure DevOps API, Embed images into HTML Create Word Document For Work Items Retrieve image in Work Item Description with TFS API Retrieve Attachment in Azure DevOps with REST API in C# Exporter project was updated a little bit in past months, I had no time for blogging about it but probably it is the time to give further information on how to export all of your Work Items to a Word File.</description></item><item><title>Error 0x8004212 during Bare Metal Recovery</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/bare-metal-recovery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 17:56:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/bare-metal-recovery/</guid><description>I got an old HP Proliant Microserver Gen7, it has Turion CPU, quite slow in these days, but I got 16GB RAM and 6 TB of caviar Red. The overall performances are acceptable, it is a domain controller for a test domain, it is used as NAS and Windows Update services.
Last week primary disk died, it starts with an annoying Tick Tick noise, then it is dead, so I bough a SAMSUNG 860 500GB SSD to replace the drive.</description></item><item><title>Compiling Angular app in WSL2</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/compile-angular-in-wsl2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/compile-angular-in-wsl2/</guid><description>Windows Subsystem for Linux was a nice toy to play, but never impressed me very much, one of the reason is its limitations. I do not work much on Linux, but usually I have Linux boxes with MongoDB, Elasticsearch and play with security related stuff and for those purposes I have dedicated virtual machines.
This was the reason why I did not found any real useful usage for WSL, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to quick do NMAP scan, but I got errors since it did not run a real Linux full kernel and NMap wants to have full access to the NIC to do its stuff.</description></item><item><title>Advantage of Hugo</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/advantage-of-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/advantage-of-hugo/</guid><description>I should admit that I was one of the people that loved blogging with Windows Live Writer and in general with software that is able to simple edit content, paste images, press a button and your post is online.
Sometimes you just need to go out from your comfort zone a little bit to change perspective and to find what you are doing wrong. Let me do an example: I used different plugins to print formatted code in my blog and after some migration you can see what happened to very first posts (around 2007).</description></item><item><title>Moving to Hugo</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/firstpost/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 17:17:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/firstpost/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started blogging in English in 2007 and clearly the choice was WordPress. I must admit that in lots of years of WordPress I always was quite satisfied by the result, lots of plugin, lots of resources on the internet and the ability to post from programs like Windows Live Writer having a WYSIWYG program.
You can also read one of the first post where I enjoyed blogging in Word, really long time passed since that really old post.</description></item><item><title>Strange error disallow my NET core application to start</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/03/strange-error-disallow-my-net-core-application-to-start/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/03/strange-error-disallow-my-net-core-application-to-start/</guid><description>Today I cloned in my workstation a.NET core application that works perfectly on my laptop, but when I started it I got this error
An attempt was made to access a socket in a way forbidden by its access permissions
I’ve spent almost 10 minutes to find why my netsh rule is not working (I work with a user that is not administrator of the machine) and finally, by frustration I opened Visual Studio with administrator user, just to verify that the error is still there.</description></item><item><title>Release software with GitHub actions and GitVersion</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/03/github-actions-plus-gitversion/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/03/github-actions-plus-gitversion/</guid><description>One of the nice aspect of GitHub actions is that you can automate stuff simply with command line tools. If you want to do continuous release of your software and you want to use GitVersion tool to determine a unique SemVer version from the history, here is the sequence of steps.
Iinstall/update gitversion tool with commandline tools Run GitVersio to determine SemVer numbers Issue a standard build/test using SemVerNumbers of step 2 If tests are ok, use dotnet publish command (with SemVer numbers) to publish software Zip and upload publish result It the branch is Master publish a GitHub release of your software.</description></item><item><title>Publish artifacts in GitHub actions</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/03/publish-artifacts-in-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/03/publish-artifacts-in-github-actions/</guid><description>GitHub action is perfect to automate simple build workflow and can also be used to publish “releases” of our software. While we can do actions to publish on cloud or elsewhere, what I appreciate from a tool is: allow me to make simple things with simple workflow. While I appreciate being able to obtain complex result and indeed, sometimes we evaluate products on the ability to fulfill complex scenario, often we forgot about the simple things.</description></item><item><title>How to configure Visual Studio as Diff and Merge tool for Git</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/07/how-to-configure-visual-studio-as-diff-and-merge-tool-for-git/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 12:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/07/how-to-configure-visual-studio-as-diff-and-merge-tool-for-git/</guid><description>After almost six years, the post on How to configure diff and merge tool in Visual Studio Git Tools is still read by people that found it useful, but it is now really really old and needs to be updated.
That post was written when Visual Studio 2012 was the latest version and the integration with Git was still really young, made with an external plugin made by Microsoft and with really basic support.</description></item><item><title>Unable to Sysprep Windows 10 due to Candy Crush hellip</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/07/unable-to-sysprep-windows-10-due-to-candy-crush/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/07/unable-to-sysprep-windows-10-due-to-candy-crush/</guid><description>I was trying to sysprep a Windows 10 virtual machine hosted in Hyper-V but I got error messages like
Package CandyCrush.. was installed for a user, but not provisioned …
It turns out that Win 10 standard installer installs some application from the store that conflicts with sysprep. Now I need to uninstall one by one and to speedup the process I suggest you to use Get-AppxPackage powershell commandlet.</description></item><item><title>Hosted Agents plus Docker perfect match for Azure DevOps and Open source Project</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/06/hosted-agents-plus-docker-perfect-match-for-azure-devops-and-open-source-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/06/hosted-agents-plus-docker-perfect-match-for-azure-devops-and-open-source-project/</guid><description>If you want to build an OpenSource project with Azure DevOps, you can open a free account and you have 10 concurrent pipelines with free agents to build your project, yes, completely free. The only problem you have in this scenario is that, sometimes, you need some prerequisites installed on the build machine, like MongoDb and they are missing on hosted build.
Lets take as use case NStore, an open source library for Event Sourcing in C# that needs to run unit test against MongoDb and SqlServer, prerequisites that are not present in Linux Hosted Agents.</description></item><item><title>Import Work Item from external system to Azure DevOps</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/01/import-work-item-from-external-system-to-azure-devops/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/01/import-work-item-from-external-system-to-azure-devops/</guid><description>In previous post I’ve dealt with exporting Work Item information in Word file with AzureDevOps API, now I want to deal with the inverse operation, importing data from external service into Azure DevOps. If the source service is a Team Foundation Server, you can use the really good tool by Naked Agility Ltd you can find in marketplace , you can also have a shot at the official migration tool if you need to migrate an entire collection, but if you have some data to import from an external system, using API can be a viable solution.</description></item><item><title>End of life of PHP 56 please upgrade to 7 version</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/11/end-of-life-of-php-5-6-please-upgrade-to-7-version/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/11/end-of-life-of-php-5-6-please-upgrade-to-7-version/</guid><description>Php 5.6 reached end of life support and this means that it will not receive anymore any security update. If you, like me, run a site with WordPress or any other technology based on PHP you should consider moving to PHP 7 as soon as possible. This is needed to avoid having a bad surprise if someone discover a new security bug and he will use to own your site.</description></item><item><title>Using vmWare machine when you have Hyper-V</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/10/using-vmware-machine-when-you-have-hyper-v/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/10/using-vmware-machine-when-you-have-hyper-v/</guid><description>There are lots of VM containing Demo, Labs etc around the internet and surely Hyper-V is not the primary target as virtualization system. This because it is present on desktop OS only from Windows 8, it is not free (present in windows professional) and bound to windows. If you have to create a VM to share in internet, 99% of the time you want to target vmWare or Virtual Box and a linux guest system (no license needed).</description></item><item><title>Esxi Hyper-V and Linux</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/12/esxi-hyper-v-and-linux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/12/esxi-hyper-v-and-linux/</guid><description>I mainly use Hyper-V to virtualize my test environments and I’m really happy with it, the only problem is virtualizing Linux Desktop environments, especially if you have monitors with higher resolution than Full-HD (since in Hyper-V I’ve not found a way to run with a greater resolution than Full HD).
To overcome this limitation, I’ve converted my old workstation in a virtualization host running VMWare ESXi and I’m really satisfied. Here is a couple of tricks that I’ve learned (I’m a completely new to latest version of ESXi).</description></item><item><title>Dotnetcore CI Linux and VSTS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/09/dotnetcore-ci-linux-and-vsts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/09/dotnetcore-ci-linux-and-vsts/</guid><description>If you have a dotnetcore project, it is a good idea to setup continuous integration on a Linux machine. This will guarantee that the solution actually compiles correctly and all the tests run perfectly, even in Linux environment. If you are 100% sure that, if a dotnetcore project runs fine under Windows it should run fine under Linux, you will have some interesting surprises. The first and trivial difference is that Linux filesystem is case sensitive.</description></item><item><title>Error in WSUS after Windows Update KB3148812</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/04/error-in-wsus-after-windows-update-kb3148812/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/04/error-in-wsus-after-windows-update-kb3148812/</guid><description>I have a test lab with a Windows Server 2012 R2 domain controller, and one of the feature I like the most is WSUS, that allows me to spin of an update new Virtual Machines without the need to wait for all Windows Update to be downloaded from the Internet.
Yesterday I noticed that suddently the WSUS service stopped working , a couple of Test VS gaves me error trying to connect to the update service, and in the WSUS Server the service was indeed stopped.</description></item><item><title>How I brought my Nexus7 Back to life</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/04/how-i-brought-my-nexus7-back-to-life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/04/how-i-brought-my-nexus7-back-to-life/</guid><description>I own a Nexus 7 (2012 version) and I was pretty satisifed with it, it is small, and I used primarly with Zite / Flipboard and to quickly read some news feed. The device is nice, but it has crappy hardware and, after a couple of years, it stops charging.
It turns out that there is some problem on the USB port that prevent proper charging , the simplest solution is buying a Docking Station, but asus decided to stop producing it, and now you can find on the internet at really high price.</description></item><item><title>Facebook Code Generator on Windows Phone</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/11/facebook-code-generator-on-windows-phone/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/11/facebook-code-generator-on-windows-phone/</guid><description>If you care about your online security, you would probably enable two factor authentication on every service that supports it. If you enable in facebook you would be prompted to enter a code of your Code Generator application. If you do not know how to obtain such code and ask for helps the site tells you that it is available on your Phone application.
Sadly enough, it seems that Windows Phone Facebook app does not have this option.</description></item><item><title>Outlook 2013 social connector does not works with linkedin</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/04/outlook-2013-social-connector-does-not-works-with-linkedin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/04/outlook-2013-social-connector-does-not-works-with-linkedin/</guid><description>It is a couple of days that Outlook 2013 cannot connect with linkedin anymore, I’ve tried to remove and readd again my account but it fails telling me that Password is not valid.
After a brief lookup in the internet I’ve found the reason, the certificate that outlook uses to connect to linkedin is expired (check this on https://outlook.linkedinlabs.com/ ) so we need to wait until linkedin updates the certificate.</description></item><item><title>My blog moved to Windows Azure</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/12/my-blog-moved-to-windows-azure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/12/my-blog-moved-to-windows-azure/</guid><description>Actually it is a few days I’ve moved my blog to Windows Azure using Web Sites , still in Preview, but really stable. The only problem with my WordPress Site, is that I’m not able to use the automatic update of plugins, due to some problem in writing on the virtual file system, but apart from this little problem (I updated my plugin with standard FTP) I’m really satisfied of azure.</description></item><item><title>I do not like Git if you want blame me for this</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/07/i-do-not-like-git-if-you-want-blame-me-for-this/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/07/i-do-not-like-git-if-you-want-blame-me-for-this/</guid><description>I did not like Git, it is a really personal opinion, but I work a really limited time on github project with some friend of mine and I always find surprise using git, surprises that never happened with other SCS (Hg, Subversion, TFS, etc).
Today I modified a file in my working copy, but after some code I want to revert to the original version, so I issue the revert command with tortoise Git.</description></item><item><title>New Blog theme</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/new-blog-theme/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2012 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/new-blog-theme/</guid><description>I’m working on a new blog theme, but I’m surely not a good designer :), but thanks to metro design it is quite simple to create a readable style for the site.
Here is a screenshot of the work in process.
I think that it will improve the readability of the blog, at least I hope :).
Have a great weekend.
Alk.</description></item><item><title>The real price of hardware</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/02/the-real-price-of-hardware/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/02/the-real-price-of-hardware/</guid><description>I bought a Vertex 3 240GB SSD drive for 270€ VAT included and some of my friend told that this is an expensive drive and they do not want to spend so much money for a Drive. The problem is how you use your hardware, in my life I work as a software consultant, and I spent most of the time in front of a computer compiling and programming and if spending 270€ can make my work more productive it worth the money I spent, because I can work faster.</description></item><item><title>Pay attention where you attach your SSD Driver</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/02/pay-attention-where-you-attach-your-ssd-driver/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/02/pay-attention-where-you-attach-your-ssd-driver/</guid><description>I blogged a couple of days ago about my new Vertex3 SSD Disk, and I gave a screenshot of the CrystalDiskmark result, that I report here for the sake of discussion.
Yesterday I decided to work on my laptop while I did a fresh windows 7 install on the new disk, then I installed everything and finally re-run Crystal Diskmark again…. and I got a really different result. I did not take a screenshot, but basically I got a 350MB/sec sequential read and and an awful 150 MB/Sec on write 4K QD32, that basically is one of the reason why I choose Vertex 3 disk.</description></item><item><title>Difference between various SSD</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/02/difference-between-various-ssd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/02/difference-between-various-ssd/</guid><description>Some time ago I posted some benchmark of my SSD, this is the result I got from my Intel X25-M
It is a really good result compared to a standard disk, expecially in the 4K and 4K QD32, now I bought a Vertex 3 SSD 240 GB and first of all I run again diskmark to see if it is really faster respect my old Intel X25-M, and result are awesome.</description></item><item><title>visifire chart hung</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/01/visifire-chart-hung/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 12:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/01/visifire-chart-hung/</guid><description>Today I lost a lot of time diagnosing a problematic Visifire Silverlight chart. If you own 3.X version of the visifirechart and you experience some Chart to completely hung the browser you should update to the 4.x version, as described in this article.
I’ve found it after a couple of hour of diagnosing why the page hung, actually I hit two of the bug, the last one that makes chart crash when dataseries was empty, and the first one.</description></item><item><title>Metro like powerpoint deck</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/12/metro-like-powerpoint-deck/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/12/metro-like-powerpoint-deck/</guid><description>I’ve just uploaded to SlideShare a presentation created with Metro Interface in mind. It is a draft on a presentation for a course on Unit Testing and I wanted to spend some time to design it to resemble a Metro interface, because I liked it really much :).
Feel free to give me any comments/suggestion/critics on the appearance of the slide, and feel free to use it as a base for your presentation if you liked the appearance.</description></item><item><title>Extract the maximum from your Hardware</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/extract-the-maximum-from-your-hardware/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/extract-the-maximum-from-your-hardware/</guid><description>I used to be a hardware enthusiast in the past, I start overclocking PC in the old day of 486, and I loved to tweak my system to squeeze out the most I can. After lots of years are passed, I have no time to follow overclocking forum, and I do not want to risk system stability to have a little increase in performance.
In the last post I show the benchmark for all of my disks units, and after the benchmark I got a suggestion of running the Intel Solid State Drive Toolbox to verify that my settings makes my ssd disk operates at maximum speed.</description></item><item><title>Benchmarking your disks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/benchmarking-your-disks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/benchmarking-your-disks/</guid><description>I love Fast Hard Disks and in the last month I bought an SSD and a replacement 2TB disk for my Virtual Machine disk that failed last week. Today I wanted to do a little benchmark on all the disks that are inside my machine to verify the differencies between the various units.
These are the results from my Intel-X25 M disk
These ones are for RAID-0 of two WD Velociraptor 10K RPM (150 GB each)</description></item><item><title>Test post</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/test-post-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2011 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/test-post-3/</guid><description>This is a test post after the catastrophic failure of mysql database engine.</description></item><item><title>This post is a test to force feed regeneration</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/07/this-post-is-a-test-to-force-feed-regeneration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/07/this-post-is-a-test-to-force-feed-regeneration/</guid><description>For some reasons it seems that my wordpress does not update the feed until I post something to the blog, :) this is a test post to force feed regeneration.
alk.</description></item><item><title>Changed the feed to show only excerpt</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/07/changed-the-feed-to-show-only-excerpt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/07/changed-the-feed-to-show-only-excerpt/</guid><description>It seems that my feed become too big for Feedburner :), this is a standard issue, so I decided to show only the most recent 10 post in the feed, but strangely enough, wordpress ignore that settings and my feed continue to show latest 15 blog entry :(.
To keep the feed updated I decided to include only an excerpt in the feed, trying to understand how to tell wordpress to use only 10 latest posts for the feed.</description></item><item><title>If you need Tfs Hosting you can consider Azure</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/if-you-need-tfs-hosting-you-can-consider-azure/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2011 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/if-you-need-tfs-hosting-you-can-consider-azure/</guid><description>Yes, as Brian Harry announced some months ago, TFS on Azure will be a reality, actually there is a platform preview here, but it is actually closed, so you need to wait to have your TFS on Azure, but if you are planning to move on TFS and you&amp;rsquo;d like to use an hosted version of TFS this could be really a good option.
If you could not wait to have your hosted TFS server, this is another useful link that contains various offers made by different companies.</description></item><item><title>Test posts on the new host</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/05/test-posts-on-the-new-host/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2011 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/05/test-posts-on-the-new-host/</guid><description>My blog is moved to another host, the old one was dismissed, this is a test post to verify that everything is ok.
Alk.</description></item><item><title>Need to save a little bit ATI from my ranting</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/05/need-to-save-a-little-bit-ati-from-my-ranting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2011 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/05/need-to-save-a-little-bit-ati-from-my-ranting/</guid><description>In previous post I did a lot of ranting against my new video cards, ATI Radeon HD 4600. Now I need to save ATI a little bit from my ranting, because after one hour of investigation I finally managed to understand the reason behind such crappy desktop performances.
I need two video card because I have three monitors, I used to keep my central and primary monitor attached to primary video card, while the other two (24&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; and, 17&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; on the secondary video card).</description></item><item><title>New Video card are only for gamershellip maybe</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/05/new-video-card-are-only-for-gamers-maybe/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2011 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/05/new-video-card-are-only-for-gamers-maybe/</guid><description>Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m the only person that have this opinion, but frankly speaking I was impressed on how bad my new video card performs on my new system. In this system I have 2 ATI Radeon HD4600, while in the old system I have two old X1550 video card, so I did not expect that dramatic loss of desktop graphics experience.
I need to confess you that desktop experience was really better with older cards.</description></item><item><title>My new Workstation is arrived</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/05/my-new-workstation-is-arrived/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/05/my-new-workstation-is-arrived/</guid><description>After a couple of years of upgrades, my old workstation reached a limit and another upgrade would not make me benefit so much, so I decided that is time to move to an entire new workstation. As usual I started to look around to decide what to buy to avoid spending big money, while having a good increase of performances.
Here is what I bought after some month of ranting against Intel, because bug in chipset of Sandy Bridge based processor motherboard had delayed my new system of 3 month.</description></item><item><title>Changing language specification is a risky business</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/changing-language-specification-is-a-risky-business/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2011 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/changing-language-specification-is-a-risky-business/</guid><description>Sometimes I heard people crying to have new features in languages like C#, and sometimes they believe that adding this and that feature is simple for a team working on language compiler. I want to remember to everyone how risky and delicate process is to change language specification.
I installed the Async CTP refresh on a production machine, and I discovered that some of my project now fails to compile, simply because I used the token async as function parameter name, and now it is a reserved keyword.</description></item><item><title>Handle an event with reflection</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/handle-an-event-with-reflection/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 12:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/handle-an-event-with-reflection/</guid><description>Scenario: You have a generic event handler function
1 2 3 4 private void GenericHandler(object sender, EventArgs e) { MessageBox.Show(&amp;#34;TEST&amp;#34;); } Now you have an object and a string representing a name of an event raised from that object and you want to call your GenericHandler whenever the object is raised. This is possible thanks to Contravariance.
Suppose you have a WebBrowserFlexible Wpf Control (it is actually a custom control capable of browsing using WebBrowser control or Gecko) that raise an DocumentCompleted event declared in this way.</description></item><item><title>MIX11 videos downloadable from RSS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/mix11-videos-downloadable-from-rss/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/mix11-videos-downloadable-from-rss/</guid><description>Scott Hanselman published a post explaining how to download MIX11 videos from the RSS, and there are a lot of comments that explain how to use a script to have an automatic download.
To download all of them, simply install Free Download Manager. When fdm is installed, navigate on one of the rss page in IE, as an example the High Res WMV (http://channel9.msdn.com/Events/MIX/MIX11/RSS/wmvhigh), then Right-click and select Download all with Free Download Manager.</description></item><item><title>Unable to open word or excel document from sky Drive</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/unable-to-open-word-or-excel-document-from-sky-drive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/unable-to-open-word-or-excel-document-from-sky-drive/</guid><description>I want to share a problem that happened ro me after I changed my passport password. When I login to skyDrive with IE and try to open a document in Word or excel, the program (Word or Excel) opens, but it is completely hung, trying to open the document.
I left splash screen of word opened for more than 20 minutes, but nothing happens so I press ESC and close Word.</description></item><item><title>Test Post from windows live writer</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/02/test-post-from-windows-live-writer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/02/test-post-from-windows-live-writer/</guid><description>Test Post</description></item><item><title>Change the spelling language of Windows live writer</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/01/change-the-spelling-language-of-windows-live-writer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2011 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/01/change-the-spelling-language-of-windows-live-writer/</guid><description>I used to blog in English, but sometimes I wrote something for my Italian Blog. I got disappointed by the fact that Windows Live Writer permits me to use only English spelling language, because I&amp;rsquo;ve installed the english version of Live Tools.
Then I read in the internet that language dictionary files used by WLW are the same of office, so I go to C:\Program Files (x86)\Microsoft Office\Office14\PROOF and look for any file that suggest me of Italian dictionaries.</description></item><item><title>Error Cannot publish because a project failed to build</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/01/error-cannot-publish-because-a-project-failed-to-build/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/01/error-cannot-publish-because-a-project-failed-to-build/</guid><description>Today I got this strange error when I tried to publish a project with clickonce, what I do not understand it is why it is telling me that a project failed to build when
If I build all solution every project builds ok It did not give me any clue on what is wrong. This is due to a bug in MSBuild system, and you can read the details here, but there is a simple workaround, instead of publishing from the project properties, you should right click on the project and then choose publish.</description></item><item><title>So many source control</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/12/so-many-source-control/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/12/so-many-source-control/</guid><description>I realize this morning that I need to install tortoise Git to have a better Git Experience (I&amp;rsquo;m not a Git fan) and after the installation now I have three version of Tortoise
And this remind me of my early age of programming at high school, when I did not know even what a source control system is, now I use 4 of them, TFS, Subversion, and HG and Git for some open source project o_O.</description></item><item><title>Silverlight and HTML5</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/11/silverlight-and-html5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/11/silverlight-and-html5/</guid><description>I was reading this post of my dear friend Shai and it brings in my mind some consideration. I never saw silverlight as a replacement for HTML even for HTML4, so I&amp;rsquo;m not so surprised by this new direction of SL that emerges from PDC.
SL could be useful to build RIA application on the web, but you should explain to your customers that they need to install a plugin, that it will not run on all platforms, etc etc, and I prefer plain HTML and jQuery.</description></item><item><title>Time to upgrade my Disks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/10/time-to-upgrade-my-disks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/10/time-to-upgrade-my-disks/</guid><description>I always love to have fast computer and sadly enough, the slowest part is always the HD. In my desktop computer I reach a good compromise with three 10.000 RPM Raptor disk, but in the laptop, having a single 7.200 RPM&amp;hellip; it is simply a pain.
This morning I was reading an old post of Jeff, that reminds me of the existence of Hybrid HD drives :). Basically at very low price you can buy an HD that is surely not fast as an SSD, but is better than a simple 7.</description></item><item><title>Electronic bookshellip are they the future</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/10/electronic-books-are-they-the-future/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/10/electronic-books-are-they-the-future/</guid><description>Probably not, until these are the prices
I know that with electronic version I don&amp;rsquo;t spend the shipping cost (That for me in Italy are quite high respect citizen in the US) and I got my book almost istantaneously, but it seems to me ridiculous that the electronic version of the book actually costs MORE than the printed version.
Until price of E-Books are so high, they will not replace the paper form in my opinion.</description></item><item><title>New release of the power toys</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/09/new-release-of-the-power-toys/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2010 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/09/new-release-of-the-power-toys/</guid><description>Brian Harry has just announced a new release for TFS Power toys here. One of the most important news is the new admin Console Backup/Restore Wizard, that will simplify a lot the administration of tfs server.
Other important new feature is the ability to copy Build Definition and Work Item. Thanks to Power Tools we have the possibility to have new feature of TFS without the need to wait for a Major Release.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Scrum 10 released</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/microsoft-scrum-1-0-released/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/microsoft-scrum-1-0-released/</guid><description>Microsoft have just released the 1.0 version of the scrum template for TFS. The reason behind this, is that a lot of person wish a template that closely match the scrum process, as described in the literature.
With this template we now have two agile process template, the first is the classic MSF Agile 5.0, that is based on scrum, but is more generic and is not strictly based on a Scrum process, and the new Scrum template to satisfy those one that want to implement a full feature Scrum process.</description></item><item><title>NHibernate filter-def for filter named was never used to filter classes nor collections</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/nhibernate-filter-def-for-filter-named-was-never-used-to-filter-classes-nor-collections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/nhibernate-filter-def-for-filter-named-was-never-used-to-filter-classes-nor-collections/</guid><description>While I was upgrading a project to the latest version of nhibernate I encounter this error
filter-def for filter named UserContext was never used to filter classes nor collections
The code worked perfectly with the older version of nhibernate, but with the new version it does not work. Thanks to my friend Guardian we have found the problem. The problem is due to a filter used only into a formula, the validator of nhibernate configuration, does not find the filter used in any mapping, does not scan formula, and thinks that the filter is never used.</description></item><item><title>Visual studio Pro Power Tools Tab Well</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/visual-studio-pro-power-tools-tab-well/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2010 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/visual-studio-pro-power-tools-tab-well/</guid><description>One of the most exiting addin for VS2010 is the Visual Studio 2010 Pro Power Tools that has a great number of features, but the most interesting one is the Document well, you can read everything about it in this post.
This really boost productivity for those one having wide monitor, such as 24&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; that has a horizontal resolution of 1920 pixels, because I really loved the ability to use vertical document well, with project colored tab.</description></item><item><title>Hackability</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/hackability/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/hackability/</guid><description>I really believe that such a word (Hackability) does not exists but a tweet I saw minutes ago makes me think a little bit, the tweet was this one
I hear about WordPress blogs getting hacked HOURLY. What is it about WP that makes it so hacker friendly? * The answer is simple IMHO, wordpress is the most used blog engine, so hackers always try to break it, because if you hack wordpress you virtually hack a large amount of blogs, while if you hack other blog platform you will hack a minor number of sites.</description></item><item><title>Changing application configuration file from a deployed click once application</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/changing-application-configuration-file-from-a-deployed-click-once-application/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/changing-application-configuration-file-from-a-deployed-click-once-application/</guid><description>I have a simple scenario, I have an application deployed internally with click once, and some of the internal versions are made avaliable externally. The problem is that I need to change the application configuration file before deploying them to production server. To accomplish this you can simply locate the file applicationname.exe.config.deploy in the deploy directory of clickonce, but if you change it you will got an error during installation similar to this one</description></item><item><title>Move a click once deployed application between servers</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/move-a-click-once-deployed-application-between-servers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/move-a-click-once-deployed-application-between-servers/</guid><description>I have a winform application that is distributed internally through a dev server with IIS, the application is distributed in the address
http://10.8.0.5:10444/MyApplicationNameInternal/publish.htm
This application is deployed for internal use and test, and when it is stable it gets deployed to customers machine. To avoid problem I need simply to take the version deployed in our internal server and move it in production machine. To do this you can simply move all the content of the IIS folder from the dev server to production server, then use the MageUi.</description></item><item><title>Running test in lab management 'Error adding test case there is no test with specified id</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/running-test-in-lab-management-error-adding-test-case-there-is-no-test-with-specified-id/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/running-test-in-lab-management-error-adding-test-case-there-is-no-test-with-specified-id/</guid><description>One of the most exiting capability of Lab Environment is the ability to
Record a Coded Ui Test Assign it to a test Run the test in an lab management virtual environment. It is possible that running the test will return an error, and in the log you find an error like
Error adding test case [xx] to test run: There is no test with specified Id {xxxxxxxx-xxxx-xxxx-xxxx-xxxxxxxxxxxx}.</description></item><item><title>Event 1006 Distributed Com</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/event-1006-distributed-com/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2010 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/event-1006-distributed-com/</guid><description>In a Tfs Test machine I have I see that there are error in the System log
The application-specific permission settings do not grant Local Activation permission for the COM Server application with CLSID {&amp;lt;CLSID&amp;gt;} to the user &amp;lt;user&amp;gt; SID (&amp;lt;SID&amp;gt;). This security permission can be modified using the Component Services administrative tool.
To solve this problem simply open Component Services tool, expand the Computers/MyComputer/DCOMConfig, then locate the entry with the CLSID you find in the message, then right click and select property</description></item><item><title>SSIS use parameter with ADO Net source in DataFlow</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/ssis-use-parameter-with-ado-net-source-in-dataflow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2010 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/ssis-use-parameter-with-ado-net-source-in-dataflow/</guid><description>I have a database where reports are done with stored procedure over the OLTP database, and we begin to suffer poor performance because we have a lot of data and sometimes reports are locked by transaction issued from components that does bulk data insertion.
A viable solution is moving all data in a DataWarehouse server where I can copy all denormalized data. This permits me to do a report query with only a simple select over a single table, then queries are issued against a database with no lock.</description></item><item><title>PopupControlExtender set focus to a control on popup</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/popupcontrolextender-set-focus-to-a-control-on-popup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/popupcontrolextender-set-focus-to-a-control-on-popup/</guid><description>I have a project with a complex user control used to select some values in hierarchic categories, it was realized with the UpdatePanel, it supports searching, selection by cascade of combo and much more, everything works great, but performances are not so good.
Now I decide to create another version that use jQuery to do real ajax calls and manage json data to maximize performances, but I face a problem</description></item><item><title>Writing a custom Activity for TFS 2010 Build workflow</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/02/writing-a-custom-activity-for-tfs-2010-build-workflow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2010 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/02/writing-a-custom-activity-for-tfs-2010-build-workflow/</guid><description>A good option to customize TFS2010 build workflow is creating a Custom Activity, an operation that is quite different from creating a Custom Code Activity. A custom activity does not contain any code at all and it is only composed by sub activities. This kind of customization is really useful to create pieces of workflow that will be inserted in main build workflow. As an example I created a simple custom activity to deploy a database project on a custom Database Server.</description></item><item><title>Facebook profile 'The page you requested was not found' Fix</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/01/facebook-profile-the-page-you-requested-was-not-found-fix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2010 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/01/facebook-profile-the-page-you-requested-was-not-found-fix/</guid><description>Sometimes I wonder the reason of some strange error in really big application. Facebook is surely one of the biggest application on the planet, it manages millions of user, but it has strange bug. I use facebook rarely, but in the last few days I was not able to look at my profile, whenever I click on PRofile I got this.
It happens with every browser, and I wonder what is happened to my profile.</description></item><item><title>Moving a TeamProjectCollection from one server to another</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/01/moving-a-teamprojectcollection-from-one-server-to-another/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/01/moving-a-teamprojectcollection-from-one-server-to-another/</guid><description>One of the new feature of TFS 2010 is the concept of Project Collection, that is a sort of container for Team Projects. You can think that a Project Collection can be used to have a sort of multiple TFS inside one single server. If you have multiple customers, and you want them to access your TFS, but you want to be sure that customer A cannot see team projects of customer B, you can create a separate project collection for each customer.</description></item><item><title>Again on IoC windsor and Release</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/01/again-on-ioc-windsor-and-release/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2010 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/01/again-on-ioc-windsor-and-release/</guid><description>I have a windows service that is used as a scheduler to launch actions in a pluggable way. It possesses a basic bunch of logic, and the user can simply derive from an ActionBase, doing whatever he want in the Execute method and let basic scheduler classes to manage the rest. In the last month I begin to experience some memory leak on an installation of the scheduler, this leak manifests itself with a constant increase of used RAM, until the process (64 bit) reaches approx 4.</description></item><item><title>SATA and E-Sata</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/01/sata-and-e-sata/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/01/sata-and-e-sata/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve bought recently an external 3.5 HD usb2.0/E-sata enclosure. I mounted a 1 Terabyte HD into it, and connected to my desktop pc with E-Sata. It does not work.
Then I take the cable that was furnished with enclosure, that permits me to bring standard SATA port of the motherboard with an external E-Sata connector. With this one the HD works well.
Then I bought an express card e-sata card for my laptop, and the HD wont work with it.</description></item><item><title>Again on backup RAID 1 is not backup</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/12/again-on-backup-raid-1-is-not-backup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 21:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/12/again-on-backup-raid-1-is-not-backup/</guid><description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve posted about backup, and I want to make another little tough, RAID 1 is not meant to replace backup. During the past I&amp;rsquo;ve heard people saying, *Hey I&amp;rsquo;ve this RAID 1 array, so I do not need backup, because if a disk will fail I have data in the other one.
This is WRONG!!!
If you are still convinced that RAID 1 or 5 can replace a backup consider these situations.</description></item><item><title>Have you backup your data today</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/12/have-you-backup-your-data-today/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2009 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/12/have-you-backup-your-data-today/</guid><description>I was reading this post, and I really agree with Jeff, every day is international Backup Awareness Day.
People usually learn the importance of a good backup the first time they have a great data loss, or when you see others having greats data loss. I remember, loong time ago, when I worked in a computer shop in my city, one day a person came with his computer and told us it does not power up.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Ajax Chrome and dynamic javascript loading</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/12/microsoft-ajax-chrome-and-dynamic-javascript-loading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2009 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/12/microsoft-ajax-chrome-and-dynamic-javascript-loading/</guid><description>In a site I need to dynamically load a javascript from javascript code, and I used this function.
1 2 3 4 5 6 function AddScriptTag(src) { var node = document.getElementsByTagName(&amp;#34;head&amp;#34;)[0] || document.body; if (node) {var script = document.createElement(&amp;#34;script&amp;#34;);script.type = &amp;#34;text/javascript&amp;#34;;script.src = srcnode.appendChild(script); } else {document.write(&amp;#34;&amp;lt;script src=&amp;#39;&amp;#34; + src + &amp;#34;&amp;#39; type=&amp;#39;text/javascript&amp;#39;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&amp;#34;); } } Now my problem is the following, one of the dynamically loaded script is made with microsoft ajax, and it uses namespace and class like piece of code.</description></item><item><title>Try visual studio beta with windows 7 with xp mode</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/try-visual-studio-beta-with-windows-7-with-xp-mode/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/try-visual-studio-beta-with-windows-7-with-xp-mode/</guid><description>This is not a new tip, it was already gave by many others, but it worth mentioning again. When you want to try beta software the best solution is using a virtual machine, to avoid the installer to break your dev machine. With windows7 you have another option, the xp mode.
AS you can see I can launch visual studio 2010 from my main machine, but it runs inside a virtual pc virtual machine.</description></item><item><title>Technorati claim</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/technorati-claim/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/technorati-claim/</guid><description>This is a post for technorati claim. K7N8HF95YA8J
Alk.</description></item><item><title>Windows Live Mesh</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/windows-live-mesh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/windows-live-mesh/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m trying to use Windows Live Mesh, and I must admit that it is quite interesting. The interface is good, the speed of synchronization is really good, and all I need to do is Right Click and add a folder to Live Mesh. The space is limited to 512 mb in the beta version, but it is enough for me, because IÃ¬'m using to keep in Sync files I&amp;rsquo;m actively working with, between my desktop and my laptop.</description></item><item><title>Test of post in the new host</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/test-of-post-in-the-new-host/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2009 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/test-of-post-in-the-new-host/</guid><description>As you can see I&amp;rsquo;ve changed the host and domain name of this blog. It was somewhat forced by old hosting, because suddenly, permalinks stopped working on our site.
I have two way, the first is trying to solve the problem, the second one is moving the blog to another host. I and Guardian tried to solve the problem, but it was impossible, so I decided to move away from the host, but since I do not want to force all other Guys of Nablasoft to move on, I decided to move onto another completely different domain by my own.</description></item><item><title>Disabled permalink on the site</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/disabled-permalink-on-the-site/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 12:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/disabled-permalink-on-the-site/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve disabled all the permalinks on my site. They ceased to work with no reason, both on my blog and guardian&amp;rsquo;s one (www.nablasoft.com/guardian). After a couple of days, we still do not know why, it seems that suddenly, with no apparent reason, some setting on php.ini are now ignored. I know that wordpress in IIS has some problems with permalink, but with fix_pathinfo trick everything worked for more than one year.</description></item><item><title>Blog permalink is dead</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/blog-permalink-is-dead/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/blog-permalink-is-dead/</guid><description>Today all of our blogs stopped working, it seems that permalink does not works anymore, it is a problem that occurred today, and our host service does not know why. I&amp;rsquo;m convinced that to host seriously something, you need to have full control on the machine where the webserver lives.
Sorry for all you guy, but until we will not found a solution (the only one I see is change hosting), all of the links to our nablasoft blogs are broken :( it is so sad :( :(</description></item><item><title>Saturdayrsquos Rant</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/saturdays-rant/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2009 04:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/saturdays-rant/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m not used to ranting&amp;hellip;but this morning I&amp;rsquo;m really hating Adaptec. I need to install Windows Server 2008 R2 on a bootable VHD. I need to access my RAID Disk array from that system, so I go to adaptec site and download the drivers. Drivers are only for board with a bios version higher than my actual bios, so I need to update bios of RAID card.
In the bios page I see with horror that I need to boot by DOS and there is no windows utility.</description></item><item><title>My web bookmarkhellip probably is google</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/my-web-bookmark-probably-is-google/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2009 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/my-web-bookmark-probably-is-google/</guid><description>This morning I need to install a Windows Server on a VHD and boot from VHD, I do not remember all the steps needed to achieve this, so I know that I&amp;rsquo;ve previously bookmarked a page from Scott Hanselman&amp;rsquo;s blog that have all links and all information to solve my problem
I remember that I bookmarked it, probably in delicious, but I have chrome open, and I have no addin that permits me to search delicious, so it is really simpler writing Scott hanselman boot from vhd in the address bar, and the first link is the one I want.</description></item><item><title>My Cats now lolled</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/my-cats-now-lolled/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2009 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/my-cats-now-lolled/</guid><description>One dear friend of mine just makes me discovered a great site :D I could not resist so I decided to post a couple of shot of my cat called Sgrinfio
http://cheezburger.com/View.aspx?aid=2757172224
http://cheezburger.com/View.aspx?aid=2757193984
Alk
Tags: Cats</description></item><item><title>Speedup Visual Studio with RAMDIsk</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/speedup-visual-studio-with-ramdisk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2009 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/speedup-visual-studio-with-ramdisk/</guid><description>In previous post I showed how using a RAMDisk does not offer speed gain when you have fast disk subsystem, but RAMDisk can still comes to an help to speedup visual studio.
Visual Studio uses windows TEMP directory during normal usage, so you can encounter some advantage if you move your temporary files on a RAM disk, as well as asp.net temporary folder. First of all create a Virtual RAMDisk of small size (you can use even 256 MB of memory) then if you have asp.</description></item><item><title>Speedup Visual Studio with faster disk</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/speedup-visual-studio-with-faster-disk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2009 04:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/speedup-visual-studio-with-faster-disk/</guid><description>We always know that to speedup visual studio a fast disk is quite always a good choice, but what is best configuration?
I&amp;rsquo;ve done some little benchmark on the compilation of a project with a msbuild script and here is the result.
When all sources are stored in C:\ drive (A velociraptor 10k disk) it compiles in 58 sec the first time, and 44 sec the second time and subsequent ones.</description></item><item><title>Another 10K RPM Disk</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/another-10k-rpm-disk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2009 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/another-10k-rpm-disk/</guid><description>Today I ordered a third velociraptor disk to replace my old secondary disk that is a 120GB 5 years old disk (an EIDE one). I noticed that to speed up building process, nothing is better than buy faster disk. I plan to use this disk to move windows swap file, asp.net temporary folder and system temp folder as well as a couple of virtual machine that actually are on old disk.</description></item><item><title>Living without internet connection</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/living-without-internet-connection/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/living-without-internet-connection/</guid><description>In the last 6 days I lived without an internet connection at home, I felt really strange, no way to contact your friends with skype or msn, no way to read mail, consult some site, buy something on amazon&amp;hellip;I really realized that my life is tightly bounded to internet world :D. I wonder how can we live 10 years ago, when internet connection was done with 33kbps modem :) time changes&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Test posting in the future</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/test-posting-in-the-future/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/test-posting-in-the-future/</guid><description>Probably one of the most missed feature of wordpress is the possibility to post in the future. There are days when you have tons of ideas, but you simply avoid to blog just because you&amp;rsquo;ve already blogged a lot in the last days. One of the most interesting feature of wordpress, as well as other blog engine is the ability to post in the future.
The good stuff is that windows live writer is able to decide date of the post directly on the post page, I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post 03 July 2009, but it will be published only the next day.</description></item><item><title>I do not have time to write tests excuse</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/i-do-not-have-time-to-write-tests-excuse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2009 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/i-do-not-have-time-to-write-tests-excuse/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m not a tests fanatic, but I use a lot of unit tests in during my development days. I do not aim to 100% coverage, and I do not believe that TDD can be used in every moment, and I use unit testing when it is necessary for me.
Sometimes it happens that someone calls me to solve a problem in code, and quite often i say Write a unit test that reproduce the problem, then begin to investigate.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio Database edition How to find objects that reference other objects</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/visual-studio-database-edition-how-to-find-objects-that-reference-other-objects/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/visual-studio-database-edition-how-to-find-objects-that-reference-other-objects/</guid><description>Another feature of Visual Studio Database Edition I cannot live without, is the possibility to find all objects that references a specific table or stored procedure etc. To see a dependency for an object simply click on the SchemaView and then you can right click on a table, and choose View Dependencies
This command will open a menu that shows all objects that references this specific object, as well as all database objects that are referenced by this object.</description></item><item><title>Twitter Blue screen D</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/twitter-blue-screen-d/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/twitter-blue-screen-d/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just twittered about a blue screen, and after some minutes I see from twitterfox that I have a reply message&amp;hellip;here it is
Amazing :D, WindowsDeath answered me, I&amp;rsquo;m impressed hahahahaha
alk.</description></item><item><title>Windows 7 RC acquisition from DV camera</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/05/windows-7-rc-acquisition-from-dv-camera/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 01:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/05/windows-7-rc-acquisition-from-dv-camera/</guid><description>I hope I can help others because it took me about a couple of hour to find a solution to this problem.
I have a mini DV camera SONY DCR CH51E and windows 7 rc 1. When I connect the camera to the pc the first time I see a baloon in the systray area that tells me new hardware found, installing drivers drivers install is OK, I can now see my camera in the list of available hardware.</description></item><item><title>Remote desktop clipboard problems</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/05/remote-desktop-clipboard-problems/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/05/remote-desktop-clipboard-problems/</guid><description>Today I have a server used in remote desktop where clipboard stops to transfer to my machine. Usually the clipboard data of the server is transferred to my machine, but this afternoon it stops working. The server cannot be restarted, I tried to logoff my user from the machine, then enter again with RDP..nothing. To transfer large text data to my dev machine now I&amp;rsquo;m forced to use a shared file&amp;hellip;here is my new powerclipboard</description></item><item><title>How secure is your password</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/05/how-secure-is-your-password/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2009 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/05/how-secure-is-your-password/</guid><description>This is a simple question but is very hard to answer correctly. I just finished reading this post by Jeff Atwood that makes me rethink on how secure my passwords are. As you can see from that post someone found Jeff password stealing it from a site that does not hash it, this is something that worried me for a long time.
I cannot be sure that my passwords are really secure, so I always think on how much damage someone will do to me when he will steal my password, this lead to some rules I follow, I discussed some time ago.</description></item><item><title>Optimizing regular expression part 2</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/04/optimizing-regular-expression-part-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/04/optimizing-regular-expression-part-2/</guid><description>If you look at this post, you can see that I had some performance problem with regular expression. After the first round of optimization it turns out that performances are still quite slow. My next step will be to remove regular expression doing search by a custom algorithm.
I need to search word in text with the possibility to specify wildcards like Sampl?, or Samp*. This kind of search is really simple with regular expression, but is slow.</description></item><item><title>Java versus Net programmers</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/04/java-versus-net-programmers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/04/java-versus-net-programmers/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve come across this post, that deals about java and.net programmers. I must admit that the situation is the one depicted by the author, probably in the average, java programmers are better accustomed with stuff like DI, IoC, ORM, AOP, and design principle, respect of.net developer; but is it really ok to reduce programming skills only to the knowledge of those concepts?. In the end the main question is Who states what is really important to know for a developer?</description></item><item><title>Cannot obtain Metadata from when trying to create references with serviceutilexe</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/04/cannot-obtain-metadata-from-when-trying-to-create-references-with-serviceutilexe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2009 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/04/cannot-obtain-metadata-from-when-trying-to-create-references-with-serviceutilexe/</guid><description>I have a simple wcf service hosted in IIS6, when I launch serviceutil.exe ( svcutil.exe http://10.8.50.1:7507/FileReceiver.svc?wsdl ) to create a proxy I get a complex and long error, but the first part of the error tells me
Error: Cannot obtain Metadata from http://10.8.50.1:7507/FileReceiver.svc?wsdl
I lost about half an hour triying to figure out what is wrong. First of all I tried to expose metadata, but this is not possible in IIS6 or at least I got some errors, and nothing works.</description></item><item><title>PHP odyssey</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/02/php-odyssey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2009 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/02/php-odyssey/</guid><description>I have a local copy of my blog in my machine, just to test if I need to do some modification to the skin or to some pages of the blog, everything is always gone ok, just installing php, mysql and the blog works great.
Today I need to reinstall php and mysql because my machine was formatted 3 month ago, I thought it will be a quick process, but I had this problem</description></item><item><title>Highlight words in webbrowser control</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/02/highlight-words-in-webbrowser-control/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/02/highlight-words-in-webbrowser-control/</guid><description>In windows forms the WebBrowser control permits to include a fully funcional browser into your application. The interesting things is that you can interact with the html of the site with no problem. As an example you can load a page and highlight some words into the text, here is the result of loading www.nablasoft.com and I want to highlight &amp;ldquo;laureati&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;passione&amp;rdquo;.
As you can see I’ve highlighted the two words, the code is really simple.</description></item><item><title>Disappointed about diskeeper</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/disappointed-about-diskeeper/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2009 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/disappointed-about-diskeeper/</guid><description>When I reinstalled my system last month, I bough a licence of diskeeper. I used the trial 30 gg in my laptop, and I really like its feature to automatically defragment the file system during Idle time.
Since trial time with laptop went good I decided to buy a licence and install diskeeper in my desktop system, and after some days of usage I noticed that it really slows up my wmware machines.</description></item><item><title>Community server gateway NNTP missing sql scripts</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/community-server-gateway-nntp-missing-sql-scripts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/community-server-gateway-nntp-missing-sql-scripts/</guid><description>I’m configuring a Community Server 2008 with the NNTP gateway, in the instructions you are asked to install some sql scripts that are missing, and when you try to access to the forums with nntp you gets exception like could not find stored procedure xxx
The reason is explained here, in the latest distribution the scripts are missing, you can also file link to the scripts in the post.
If someone is stuck with this missing scripts this link can really save your life :P</description></item><item><title>Test Post</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/test-post-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 04:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/test-post-2/</guid><description>I’ve finished reinstalling almost everything on my new RAID 1 array, this is a test post to check if Window Live Writer works well again.
alk.</description></item><item><title>New year8217s Disk</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/new-years-disk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2009 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/new-years-disk/</guid><description>I’ve bought a second SATA 10.000 RPM disk, along with an adaptec raid controller to move toward a RAID 1 array. The RAID1 array have more performance in reading, along as increase security because the data are mirrored on two disks. It was a long time (about 1 year) that I did not open a single pc to play with hardware, it is a thing that I like very much, but my actual case is a middle tower (I always Had big Tower case) and putting three disks into it was not a breeze.</description></item><item><title>T-SQL - selecting top X element for each group</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/t-sql-selecting-top-x-element-for-each-group/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2009 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/t-sql-selecting-top-x-element-for-each-group/</guid><description>Today I need to build a query that selects the most expensive three orders made in a date range for each customer. This is the typical query where the ROW_NUMBER() function introduced with Sql Server 2005 can really helps you. Here is a solution in northwind database.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 select orderId, CustomerId, Freight from ( select ROW_NUMBER() over (partition by CustomerId order by Freight desc) as RowNumber, orderId, CustomerId, Freight from orders ) as innerTable where RowNumber &amp;lt; 4 order by CustomerId, Freight desc the ROW_NUMBER creates a column with an incremental number over some order clause and optionally partitioned over some columns.</description></item><item><title>Firefox and missing offsetX value from event object</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/firefox-and-missing-offsetx-value-from-event-object/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2009 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/firefox-and-missing-offsetx-value-from-event-object/</guid><description>As you can verify in various articles the event object in javascript is really different between IE and firefox. This is one of the most annoying part of javascript programming, taking into account the various differences of avaliable browser.
I have an old routing that uses event.offsetX to do some logic on an image depending on the relative position of the mouse respect to the image top-left corner, it works only for IE but now I need to make it compatible with firefox.</description></item><item><title>Analyze a slow aspnet web page tale of</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/12/analyze-a-slow-aspnet-web-page-tale-of/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2008 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/12/analyze-a-slow-aspnet-web-page-tale-of/</guid><description>Asp.net is a great environment to quickly develop sites, but if you does not know what you are doing you can get hurt with poor performances.
Today I was analyzing a web page of a site because a developer reported to me that it is really really slow (more than 10 seconds to render), here it is how I proceed in similar situation
1) Check the size of the page I fired Fiddler and loaded the page with IE, then I look at the size of the page.</description></item><item><title>Create a report in excel 2007 with Open Xml SDK 10</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/11/create-a-report-in-excel-2007-with-open-xml-sdk-10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2008 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/11/create-a-report-in-excel-2007-with-open-xml-sdk-10/</guid><description>I need a program that send by email some reports each day to a certain number of recipients. The first thing I need to solve is the format of the report, a pdf could be a good thing, but I need to find a library to generate pdf etc etc. The best solution is to use Excel 2007 and send the whole excel file by email. The good thing about excel is that he already possess an incredible number of graph style, and thanks to the open Xml format creating a report is a breeze.</description></item><item><title>ye old XCopy</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/11/ye-old-xcopy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/11/ye-old-xcopy/</guid><description>My new external usb disk is just arrived, so I begin to move stuff into it&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;since I&amp;rsquo;m a great fan of command line tool I fired an XCopy of a really big big folder with really lot of files and the result is
E:\Codice Libri\WCF Unleashed\Examples\Windows Communication Foundation Unleashed \ef_Chapter5_and_6_WindowsWorkflowFoundation\WCFUnleashedSamples\Chapter 6\Basic WCFHostedWorkflow\BasicWCFHostedWorkflow\bin\Debug\Interfaces.pdb Insufficient memory whoa&amp;hellip;it is the first time that xcopy gives me an insufficient memory&amp;hellip;
alk.</description></item><item><title>MySQL server has gone away during restore</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/11/mysql-server-has-gone-away-during-restore/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/11/mysql-server-has-gone-away-during-restore/</guid><description>Today I was upgrading a Mantis bug tracking system, to avoid problems I backup the db and tried to restore in a different catalog. The restore procedure fail with the error
MySQL server has gone away
My first question is gone away? and where? it is gone in vacation? this is a perfect example of strange error message, fortunately I suspect that the problem was due to a table with BLOB field with great data, and in fact the restore process generated this error during the restore of a very big row.</description></item><item><title>A custom publishsubscriber appender for log4net</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/11/a-custom-publishsubscriber-appender-for-log4net/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2008 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/11/a-custom-publishsubscriber-appender-for-log4net/</guid><description>Logging is one of the most important part of an application, the ability to detect cause of failures or malfunctions from the log is invaluable, but generating good logs is not easy.
The fundamental step to obtain a good logging infrastructure, is to use one of the libraries available in the open source world, and probably you will end using log4net because it is really good. One of the most important characteristic of a good infrastructure for logging is the ability to change the destination of logs without recompiling, and the possibility to extend the basic logging facility with custom destination storage.</description></item><item><title>svcutil and the infamous This URL does not support DISCO</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/11/svcutil-and-the-infamous-this-url-does-not-support-disco/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/11/svcutil-and-the-infamous-this-url-does-not-support-disco/</guid><description>WCF is undoubtedly a complex beast, and sometimes you gets stuck on some strange errors. Suppose you have this configuration
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 &amp;lt;host&amp;gt; &amp;lt;baseAddresses&amp;gt; &amp;lt;add baseAddress=&amp;#34;http://localhost:9000/L4NServer/&amp;#34;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;add baseAddress=&amp;#34;net.tcp://localhost:8000/L4NServer/&amp;#34;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/baseAddresses&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/host&amp;gt; &amp;lt;endpoint address=&amp;#34;MainLog&amp;#34; binding=&amp;#34;basicHttpBinding&amp;#34; contract=&amp;#34;LiveLogger4Log4Net.IL4NServer&amp;#34; /&amp;gt; you can generate the proxy with the command
svcutil http://localhost:9000/L4NServer/ /out:client.cs /config:service.config
suppose you want to switch over net.tcp binding, you change the binding for the endpoint (netTcpBinding), you try to generate again the proxy classes with svcutil</description></item><item><title>Some details on older post about usertype</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/10/some-details-on-older-post-about-usertype/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2008 04:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/10/some-details-on-older-post-about-usertype/</guid><description>In this old post I spoke about a user type that permits you to store a IList&amp;lt;String&amp;gt; property with nhibernate in a single field of a database with a # separated list of string. That example did not contain the full code of the usertype, so here it is.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63 64 65 66 67 68 69 70 71 72 73 74 75 76 77 78 79 80 81 82 83 84 85 86 87 88 89 90 91 92 1 class StringListUserType : IUserType 2 { 3 private const char cStringSeparator = &amp;#39;#&amp;#39;; 4 5 #region Equals member 6 7 bool IUserType.</description></item><item><title>The value of infrastructure</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/10/the-value-of-infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/10/the-value-of-infrastructure/</guid><description>The infrastructure of a project is really important for a lot of reasons, first of all it should make possible to accomplish standard tasks with simple code avoiding duplication. Lets do a little example. In.NET if you want to issue a simple query to a database you really have to do a lot of things. First of all you need to create a Connection object, then create a Command object, populate the command with query and parameter, open the connection and execute the command.</description></item><item><title>Expression Tree vs reflection</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/10/expression-tree-vs-reflection/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/10/expression-tree-vs-reflection/</guid><description>Everyone knows that invoking method through reflection is slower than direct invocation, here is a little test.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 Int32 iterations = 100000; Stopwatch watch = new Stopwatch(); MyObject obj = new MyObject(); obj.Prop = 0; watch.Start(); for (Int32 I = 0; I &amp;lt; iterations; ++I) { obj.</description></item><item><title>Use Extension methods to create a safe enumerate</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/10/use-extension-methods-to-create-a-safe-enumerate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/10/use-extension-methods-to-create-a-safe-enumerate/</guid><description>When you use the foreach construct to enumerate in a IEnumerable object, one of the most annoying things is that you cannot modify the IEnumerable object adding or removing component. This is a really standard way to work, since when you are enumerating a sequence, if you add or remove an element, the sequence is changed and the whole enumeration operation should be aborted. This behaviour can be frustrating, because quite often I need to iterate through a dictionary object, and I want to be able to remove some element depending on some condition, but I cannot use a foreach beacuse I cannot modify the dictionary while enumerating.</description></item><item><title>A good log can really helps you to write better application</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/a-good-log-can-really-helps-you-to-write-better-application/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/a-good-log-can-really-helps-you-to-write-better-application/</guid><description>Actually I&amp;rsquo;m working on a project that have a windows service that does a lot of calculation, invokes external servers, and stuff like these. Since we have no user interface, how can you know when error occurred and how can you be informed on the detail of the error? The solution is to create a good infrastructure of logging.
Thanks to Log4Net writing such a layer is incredible simple. I build a static class called GeneralLogger, then create a series of method to log information such as AnalyzerError, AnalyzerVerbose, WebError, WebVerbose etc etc.</description></item><item><title>Test of a couple of wlw plugins</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/test-of-a-couple-of-wlw-plugins/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2008 04:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/test-of-a-couple-of-wlw-plugins/</guid><description>This post is a simple test for a couple of plugins that Guardian signaled me. The first one is to insert a DotNetKick tag, I already used one, but this is automatic and does not require me to insert in each post. The second one is a plugin for dzone. Both of them are targeted for the last technical preview of windows live writer.
Alk.</description></item><item><title>Russian spam</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/russian-spam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 04:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/russian-spam/</guid><description>Today I found a lot of mail like this in my inbox
I really does not know the meaning of these, I’m pretty sure that they are spam, but they are not caught by my antispam filter…..I wonder on what is written on these mails.
alk.</description></item><item><title>New Skin for the blog</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/new-skin-for-the-blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/new-skin-for-the-blog/</guid><description>I’m a really bad graphics designer, but the old skin I used for my blog is really old, and does not fit well with wordpress 2.6, so I take an already existing theme, and modified it to make it similar to the old skin.
I won’t tell you issue I had writing php code, fortunately I needed only to change a little bit here and there, I create some icons with axialis icon worshop and here my new skin is online.</description></item><item><title>Favor small and frequent checkin over big ones</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/favor-small-and-frequent-checkin-over-big-ones/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2008 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/favor-small-and-frequent-checkin-over-big-ones/</guid><description>This is a rule that I try to adopt since long time in the past, and few days ago Jeff Atwood enforces this concept in his blog. I completely agree with him, code should be checked in often, especially when you have continuous integration server. Checking in often reduce the risk of conflicts, makes tests run often (you should have setup your continuous server to run all tests for each checkin) and makes integration simplier.</description></item><item><title>E-Book on data structure and algorithms</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/e-book-on-data-structure-and-algorithms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2008 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/e-book-on-data-structure-and-algorithms/</guid><description>My italian friend Luca Del Tongo had just published an ebook on Data Structure and Algorithms. The book is free to download and it is supported by code examples at http://codeplex.com/dsa.
The argument is really interesting and I suggest you to download and read it ;)
Alk.
Tags: Algorithm</description></item><item><title>Chrome is out</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/chrome-is-out/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 01:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/chrome-is-out/</guid><description>I’m installing google Chrome, the new browser from Google. I suspect that it will not became my favourite browser in the near future, I use a lot of addins for Firefox and I’m very satisfied with it, so I does not feel the need for another browser.
Probably Chrome will rapidly become one of the most used browser, so we’ll see in the future how this will change the web. For web developers it will be another browser were we need to test our applications, but maybe it will really simplify writing RIA and will bring a new generation of application to the web.</description></item><item><title>Adobe Acrobat new is better or worse</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/adobe-acrobat-new-is-better-or-worse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/adobe-acrobat-new-is-better-or-worse/</guid><description>I’m working with OpenXml format of office 2007, so I keep the reference document open because I constantly need to search information into the document. The reference document is a 5200 huge 37 mb pdf, when I open it in Adobe reader 8 the acrobat process uses 60MB of ram, when I start a search of a text the search is incredibly slow, acrobat begin to use more memory. To make a comparison I try to search the text youcannotfoundThis and after 30 seconds acrobat is still at page 500, and the memory consumption is 125 mb.</description></item><item><title>Outlook spam filter</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/outlook-spam-filter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2008 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/outlook-spam-filter/</guid><description>It seems absurd, but I made a simple test to verify if my smtp server is working, I sent to one of my address one mail with subject “test” and body “test”. Then after 1 minutes the mail still did not arrived, so I deduced that my smtp server is not working properly….then…I goes into the junk mail folder of outlook and I found that my mail was flagged as spam :D, I do not know the reason, but I suppose that outlook is smart enough to consider all your addresses as trusted ones :D</description></item><item><title>Really strange error in production server a tale of named pipes</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/really-strange-error-in-production-server-a-tale-of-named-pipes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2008 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/really-strange-error-in-production-server-a-tale-of-named-pipes/</guid><description>I have a production server with an asp.net application, it run for months without errors. 10 days ago the elmah page begins to shows an error that occurred in a lot of pages.
The application uses a standard ado.net Data access Layer, but a module uses nhibernate, and it turns out that all the errors happened when a page use some function in this module. I tried to access some pages in the site that uses nhibernate, and every page raises an error of type.</description></item><item><title>Remove comment moderation</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/remove-comment-moderation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2008 04:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/remove-comment-moderation/</guid><description>I decided to remove comment moderation for the blog. I used it mainly to be sure that no spam pass the filter, but after some months of testing I verify that Akismet really does a good work, intercepting all the spam comments.
Moreover I setup the WP-reCAPTCHA plugin to add a CAPTCHA in the end of the post, making life harder for spammers. I really like to have moderation removed, primarily because I have to check it often to be sure that no comment gets lost, moreover I like that readers can immediately see comments in the post.</description></item><item><title>Is really microsoft killing open source</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/is-really-microsoft-killing-open-source/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2008 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/is-really-microsoft-killing-open-source/</guid><description>This morning I read this post linked from Ayende’s post. I really does not agree with the author. Open source is a movement where people are happy to use their time to develop solution for everyone, quite often for free, sometimes with more restrictive license (free only for non commercial product) but really noone has the right to say “hey, this MUST be free”.
We must really thanks people for dedicating their precious time to the community, and we cannot blame them for not doing or stopping that.</description></item><item><title>WordPress and permalink make your url case sensitive</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/wordpress-and-permalink-case-sensitive/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2008 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/wordpress-and-permalink-case-sensitive/</guid><description>This morning I browse some stats that google made on my blog, and saw that there are some 404 (Not Found) page. After some inspection I see that all the 404 have the form
http://www.nablasoft.com/Alkampfer/xxx
They have capital A for Alkampfer, if I changed the Alkampfer in alkampfer everything work……the strange thing is that I perfectly remember that it does work when I first setup the blog. After some inspection I found that the problem is due to the permalink, when you activate permalink in wordpress the url became case sensitive.</description></item><item><title>Overriding the Equals Method for object used as a key in hashtable</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/overriding-the-equalsmethod/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/overriding-the-equalsmethod/</guid><description>Overriding the Equals method is not a stuff for the fainted-hearts; it could seems absolutely a simple thing to do, but there are a lot of subtleties that had to be keep in mind.
Here is a typical implementation of Equals for a Customer entity made by Resharper (R# permits you to define equals with a single click)
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 public class Customer : IEquatable&amp;lt;Customer&amp;gt; { public String Name { get; set; } public String Surname { get; set; } public bool Equals(Customer obj) { if (ReferenceEquals(null, obj)) return false; if (ReferenceEquals(this, obj)) return true; return Equals(obj.</description></item><item><title>Lambda recursion pay attention to performances</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/lambda-recursion-pay-attention-to-performances/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2008 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/lambda-recursion-pay-attention-to-performances/</guid><description>This morning I stumble across this old post, that shows how to create a recursive function with lambda. The article is very interesting and has a second part that deal with memoization. These two articles are really great ones, but I want to point out that you need really pay attention to performance each time you speak about recursion. This piece of code shows an interesting thing
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 class Program { private static Stopwatch sw = new Stopwatch(); static void TestSpeed(Func&amp;lt;int, int&amp;gt; f, int i, string msg) { sw.</description></item><item><title>My DampD Character</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/my-dd-character/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2008 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/my-dd-character/</guid><description>I’m a great fan of Dungeons And Dragons, I began playing when I was 12 years old, and after more that 20 years I still play, a little less but still have a lot of fun with my friends.
I think that role playing games are really useful to keep your creativity up and running, someone told me that speaking about Dragon, Bugbear and stuff like that at the age of 34 is really strange, some other tell me that they envy me for still having fun with those games.</description></item><item><title>Morning in panic</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/morning-in-panic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2008 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/morning-in-panic/</guid><description>This morning I upgraded my wordpress blog from 2.5 to 2.6, I made backup, then installed new files, but when I upgraded my database the routine gives me some errors…
After a brief look I found a post that shows that my error happened to some other people, but is not blocking one, and it can be ignored…except that all my permalinks are broken…… time to panic alk….
I restored everything…now all the page returned blank page…… panic level is reaching maximum level alk….</description></item><item><title>I really like AVG</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/i-really-like-avg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2008 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/i-really-like-avg/</guid><description>Some days ago I posted about a problem with avg 8.0 that makes me impossible to login in Windows Live Messenger. The great number of comments to that post showed me that a really great number of people suffered the same problem.
Today I reactivated AVG MSN protection, and now everything works fine. It seems that AVG corrected the problem.
I really like AVG, I used it for the past 5 years and it seems a very good product.</description></item><item><title>We love our hardware really true</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/we-love-our-hardware-really-true/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2008 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/we-love-our-hardware-really-true/</guid><description>As Jeff Atwood says “we love computers”, yes, we are developer, but in the end we choose this profession because is the one that make us possible to work with the object of our love…computer.
I’m one of those person that build his development machine, I want to choose every pieces of hardware, and this is mainly because I worked as a technician during my university period, so I used to work with a lot of different hardware, and I cannot think to own a computer that is “packaged by someone else”, each part of my pc is there because I want it to be there.</description></item><item><title>There are some thing a developer is not required to knowreally</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/there-are-some-thing-a-developer-is-not-required-to-knowreally/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2008 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/there-are-some-thing-a-developer-is-not-required-to-knowreally/</guid><description>This morning I was reading this post, the author links Jeff Atwood blog and the post speaks about that some thing that are important to know to be a good developer, one of the controversial part is
Know how long it takes your computer to execute an instruction, fetch a word from memory (with and without a cache miss), read consecutive words from disk, and seek to a new location on disk</description></item><item><title>WCF services and silverlight</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/wcf-services-and-silverlight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2008 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/wcf-services-and-silverlight/</guid><description>I’m doing the first steps with silverlight, and today I incurred in a very strange behavior. First of all I see that in my web project I can add WCF service or Silverlight-enabled WCF services. My first thought was…”why a wcf service should be different for silverlight”?
The only difference is that with a silverlight enabled wcf you will get a service already configured in a very specific way. First of all it does not use the separation of the interface, so you have only the service class like an old asmx service, moreover it configures web.</description></item><item><title>Windows Live Messenger error 81000395</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/windows-live-messenger-error-81000395/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/windows-live-messenger-error-81000395/</guid><description>Yesterday I could not connect to Windows live messenger, it gave me error 81000395 telling me that the service was not avaliable. This morning the problem is still there…so I googled a little bit to find solution. I found a lot of thing but noone worked
Uninstall and reinstall (did not work) Uninstall and reinstall old version (It tells me that I need to upgrade an I cannot log) Disable firewall Dance some macumba in front of the the pc….</description></item><item><title>Current directory in a library that should work for aspnet and windows app</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/current-directory-in-a-library-that-should-work-for-aspnet-and-windows-app/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2008 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/current-directory-in-a-library-that-should-work-for-aspnet-and-windows-app/</guid><description>Suppose you created a library that needs to scan the “current directory” looking for some files, first solution that came in my mind was to use Enviroment.CurrentDirectory, but this is not correct. In a web.application or windows service you will find that CurrentDirectory is c:\windows\system32.
I need a generic way to find a file that is located in the same path of the executables in a windows app, and in base directory for a web.</description></item><item><title>How I Got Started in Software Development</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/how-i-got-started-in-software-development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/how-i-got-started-in-software-development/</guid><description>Ok, my friend Marco tagged me and I cannot escape from doing this post :D.
How old were you when you started programming? I do not remember exactly, It was Vic20 and it was early 80. I really loved basic at these times :D.
How did you get started in programming? I simply turned on Vic 20, ran some games loaded from tape (yuck……it seems strange for me that music tape could contain games :D ) and then I began to read manuals.</description></item><item><title>I really enjoy Says-it</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/i-really-enjoy-says-it/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2008 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/i-really-enjoy-says-it/</guid><description>Today I discovered http://www.says-it.com/ it is really a funny site. Actually I’m making silly thing :D but I created this logo
And the thing I miss most is that I cannot include in source code :(. It would be funny if visual studio make it possible to include images in source code and show them directly in the IDE. Sometimes I found in project code that really needs to be refactored, usually I setup a comment in the class and then issue a bug in the bug tracker…but having such a logo at the beginning of file would be really better :D</description></item><item><title>Generate RTF library in NET</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/generate-rtf-library-in-net/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2008 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/generate-rtf-library-in-net/</guid><description>This rtf generator is one of my first projects in.net, it started in Visual studio 2002 :D, then it was converted to visual studio 2003 and.net 1.1. Some time ago one of the developer of my team ask me if I know a quick way to generate an rtf file from asp.net, so I simply say
“Hey, I have this really old library of mine…..you can try at your own risk :D”</description></item><item><title>error MSB3323 Unable to find manifest signing certificate in the certificate store and CCNEt</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/error-msb3323-unable-to-find-manifest-signing-certificate-in-the-certificate-store-and-ccnet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2008 04:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/error-msb3323-unable-to-find-manifest-signing-certificate-in-the-certificate-store-and-ccnet/</guid><description>This morning I did some modification to a project that is deployed with click once, I checked in and the build was broken. I go to CC.NET dashboard and I see that the error is
error MSB3323 Unable to find manifest signing certificate in the certificate store
I tried to do various experiments, but after half hour I came to the solution, simply go to the Project Properties, Signing tab, then I deselect “Sign the ClickOnce manifest” and check it again, all works well again.</description></item><item><title>Find value of ASPNET ObjectDataSource or SqlDataSource at runtime</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/find-value-of-aspnet-objectdatasource-or-sqldatasource-at-runtime/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/find-value-of-aspnet-objectdatasource-or-sqldatasource-at-runtime/</guid><description>I must admit that I do not like very much the XXXDataSource control of ASP.NET 2.0 library, but the ObjectDataSource is sometimes a quick solution to interface the UI with own LogicLayer.
In a recent project I have a complex page that set up some complex filter for data in a Sql Server engine, the logic of filtering is exposed by an object queried by an ObjectDataSource. this DataSource has QueryString Parameters, Control Parameter, and some other custom parameter to take parameter value from other sources.</description></item><item><title>AcrobatSDK Find the name of active document</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/acrobatsdk-find-the-name-of-active-document/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/acrobatsdk-find-the-name-of-active-document/</guid><description>Using AcrobatSDK is damned a hard stuff, the documentation is too big, and there are lot of examples but quite often I do not find useful ones, the result is that I’m feeling lost into all the layers, functions etc. Moreover doing simple things is so damn hard…as an example, here is the code to find the name of the current front document.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 1 // try to get front PDF document 2 AVDoc avDoc = AVAppGetActiveDoc(); 3 4 if(avDoc==NULL) { 5 // if no doc is loaded, make a message.</description></item><item><title>debugging Javascript with Visual Studio 2005</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/debugging-javascript-with-visual-studio-2005/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2008 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/debugging-javascript-with-visual-studio-2005/</guid><description>Sometimes it happens that people told me…in visual studio 2005 it is difficul to debug Javascript, this is not true, simply write this istruction in a script
debugger;
and when you will execute the page in IE it ask you if you want to debug the script, this is damn easy :D
alk.
Tags: Javascript debugging</description></item><item><title>Using a single ModalPopupExtender to show Dynamic Complex Data</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/using-a-single-modalpopupextender-to-show-dynamic-complex-data/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/using-a-single-modalpopupextender-to-show-dynamic-complex-data/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m not a javascript fan, but sometimes I have the need to write some client script code, to make the application more responsive.
In a project I was working on, we have the main page with a gridview that shows 15 components at time, each component has really a lot of information to show to the user, so the first version uses the ModalPopupExtender from AjaxControlToolkit to move in a popup the extended informations.</description></item><item><title>After a long time some code on C Again</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/after-a-long-time-some-code-on-c-again/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/after-a-long-time-some-code-on-c-again/</guid><description>It was a really long time I did not code C++, now I got a tricky work, it consist in massively open pdf files, examine the structure of the file, find page with graphic data, then export the page in tiff along with all the text found in page with relative coordinate.
The starting point is to download acrobatSdk and adobe acrobat trial and set up the environment.
The amount of classes into the SDK is overwhelming….</description></item><item><title>Pay attention when you delete some stuff from your hard disk</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/pay-attention-when-you-delete-some-stuff-from-your-hard-disk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/pay-attention-when-you-delete-some-stuff-from-your-hard-disk/</guid><description>Some days ago I was cleaning stuffs from my HD, just to regain space. I found that a lot of space is occupied by old virtual disc of my old virtual machines (vmware). I decided that there is no need to keep these machine again, since now I have newer VM with windows server 2008, and because I use VM primarly to try some software not to make my principal installation dirty.</description></item><item><title>WordPress Permalink on IXwebhosting and IIS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/wordpress-permalink-on-ixwebhosting-and-iis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2008 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/wordpress-permalink-on-ixwebhosting-and-iis/</guid><description>Uff…that was thought, it is almost one year I opened my blog, wordpress is great, but I never be able to set permalink to work correctly, caused by the fact that my hosting use IIS, and wordpress likes to be hosted on apache. In a lot of blog I found that to enable permalink I need to change some settings in php.ini, these settings are
cgi.fix_pathinfo = 1
cgi.force_redirect = 0</description></item><item><title>Simple skinnable and Theme management in WPF user interface</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/simple-skinnable-and-theme-management-in-wpf-user-interface/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2008 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/simple-skinnable-and-theme-management-in-wpf-user-interface/</guid><description>A skinnable interface is the gotha of the user interface, the developer use standard control and set the behaviour, the designer skin it with some tool and creates a beautiful user interface. In WPF this is possible thanks to XAML and styles, but it is possible to simple include in an application a series of skin and load at runtime??. The answer is Yes, it is possible.
Let’s Start with a simple page with a combo and a textblock</description></item><item><title>Delegates and Rhino Mocks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/delegates-and-rhino-mocks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/delegates-and-rhino-mocks/</guid><description>I love delegates, with c# 2.0 anonymous delegates and with C# 3.0 lambda, working with delegates is simply wonderful. Anonymous delegates makes possible to create closure, and I like to use delegate in a lot of places. When you have to test objects that accepts external delegates Rhino Mock is simply exceptional, here is a test I write this afternoon
1 2 3 4 5 6 MultiRange sut1 = CreateMultiRange(50, &amp;#34;pippo&amp;#34;, 100, &amp;#34;pluto&amp;#34;); MultiRange sut2 = CreateMultiRange(60, &amp;#34;ted&amp;#34;); MultiRange.</description></item><item><title>XmlDocument XmlResolver and cache the schema of XHTML</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/xmldocument-xmlresolver-and-cache-the-schema-of-xhtml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/xmldocument-xmlresolver-and-cache-the-schema-of-xhtml/</guid><description>I’m working with a class created by my colleague, this class has a function that accept a uri, a string (that represent the content of a page) and tells me if in that string there are some links to an RssFeed. I have a full page content store in files, so I simply load files one by one and then pass to this function.
It seems to me that the execution is quite slow and looking into fiddler I found that almost each file I pass to the function the function download some files related to xml schema.</description></item><item><title>Loading dictionary of resources runtime in WPF</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/loading-dictionary-of-resources-runtime-in-wpf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/loading-dictionary-of-resources-runtime-in-wpf/</guid><description>This morning I had a little task, I’going to a Customer to install a simple WPF application in a touch screen. The problem is: I do not know how the customer want to format the form: font, color and so on. The problem is that I do not want to setup a procedural code to change these setting runtime, I only want to change the first time, then all goes on forever with that settings.</description></item><item><title>XamlReader quotMissing XmlNamespace Assembly or ClrNamespace in Mapping instructionquot</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/xamlreader-missing-xmlnamespace-assembly-or-clrnamespace-in-mapping-instruction/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/xamlreader-missing-xmlnamespace-assembly-or-clrnamespace-in-mapping-instruction/</guid><description>This post is a clarification of the preceding post.
If you try to load XAML file at runtime with the XamlReader it is important that you specify the full assembly if the file contain reference to local defined object. As an example, if I use a custom IValueConverter defined in my assembly, the cyder designer can generate such a XAML file for a resource
1 2 3 &amp;lt;ResourceDictionary xmlns=&amp;#34;http://schemas.microsoft.com/winfx/2006/xaml/presentation&amp;#34; xmlns:x=&amp;#34;http://schemas.</description></item><item><title>WordPress and IIS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/wordpress-and-iis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2008 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/wordpress-and-iis/</guid><description>When the last year I setup this blog I choose wordpress because It is the most common blog on the net, I told myself, “lets try, and see how it works”.
I think that wordpress is a really good blog engine, but my hosting use IIS…and this makes me not possible to enable Permalink. I’ve check some solutions on the web, but none of them worked.
This makes me reflect on how the Internet is a real complex environment to live in, many hosting, many technologies and many different problem.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft html parser</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/microsoft-html-parser/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2008 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/microsoft-html-parser/</guid><description>When working with HTML the microsoft HTML parser can be useful, but surely is not a simple beast to deal on. I have no great familiarity, but I was astonished on the interface in my first try.
Situation 1: You have a string with the HTML content, here is the code to load the html into the object
This is really simple, but pay attention, the object has to be casted to IHTMLDocument2, if you cast to HTMLDocumentClass the above method does not work.</description></item><item><title>A simple try for the KickIt plugin</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/a-simple-try-for-the-kickit-plugin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2008 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/a-simple-try-for-the-kickit-plugin/</guid><description>The DotNetKicks community is really new for me, But I decided to try to contribute, and I found a really interesting plugin for Windows Live Writer here. I’ve installed also the WordPress related plugin, so let’s see if all works.
Tags: DotNetKicks
Alk.</description></item><item><title>CodeMetropolis new blog for Marco De Sanctis</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/codemetropolis-new-blog-for-marco-de-sanctis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2008 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/codemetropolis-new-blog-for-marco-de-sanctis/</guid><description>Today I found that my friend Marco has finally opened his english blog, you can find at http://www.codemetropolis.com. Marco already has a great italian blog at (http://blogs.ugidotnet.org/crad/Default.aspx) but recently decided to begin a new adventure in English.
Another Rss for my Omea Reader :D
Alk.</description></item><item><title>New AVG really interesting features</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/new-avg-really-interesting-features/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2008 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/new-avg-really-interesting-features/</guid><description>I upgraded today my avg 7.5 to version 8.0, and when I rebooted and did a search in google I found some important updates
AVG integrates on google, and every link that google shows is marked safe or unsafe, with a nice tooltip explaining me that the site is ok, it seems to me really interesting.
alk.
Tags: AVG</description></item><item><title>The importance of quotconventionsquot</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/the-importance-of-conventions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2008 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/the-importance-of-conventions/</guid><description>I like in C# not to have the open bracket in newline, it is not the default setting of Visual Studio but I was used to this scheme since I worked with C++ in linux, so I’m used with it. This is a “convention” and seems not to be so important…until you work in a team
The most important problem with different indentation or layout scheme, is that when you press the magic CTRL+K CTRL+D you reformat the source code with your layout scheme, when you use winmerge or similar tool to find differencies between the various version in a source control you find often that all the file is changed…because of the layout.</description></item><item><title>FeedBurner stats</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/feedburner-stats/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2008 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/feedburner-stats/</guid><description>This morning I had a great surprise, I saw in feedburner 103 readers of my blog, it is really great for me to reach three digit count :D, it means that my blog interests some people. 103 is not such a great number, but thinking that in the world 100 person are interested in what I’m saying is really exiting. Hope to raise this stat in the future, thanks to everyone, have a great day.</description></item><item><title>Desktop Space</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/desktop-space/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2008 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/desktop-space/</guid><description>I was always astonished when I think to the evolution of pc. I’m 34 years old and my first pc was a 8086 with a 13” monitor with a resolution of 640×480=307.200 pixel.
Then I moved to a 14” monitor and I used to work mainly at 800×600 = 480.000 pixel, so I have 56% more space on screen.
After a quite long time I moved to 17”, and switched to 1024×768 = 786.</description></item><item><title>Windows Xp and file copy</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/windows-xp-and-file-copy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2008 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/windows-xp-and-file-copy/</guid><description>This morning I select some folders from my external HD, CTRL+C and then CTRL-V in a folder of my secondary disk. The external disk begins to read at full speed, the OS shows me a windows that tells
Preparing to copy operation
That windows stands on my desktop for 20 minutes before it begins actually to copy the files….. The real copy operation take 20 minutes. So I’m asking myself, “why the OS spent 20 minutes preparing the copy?</description></item><item><title>Technorati tags</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/technorati-tags/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2008 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/technorati-tags/</guid><description>I realized that technorati tags does not work well in my blog, if I click in tags cloud technorati tells me that are no post with that tag. I’ll investigate the problem
alk.
Tags: Technorati
Tags</description></item><item><title>Blog upgrade</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/blog-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2008 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/blog-upgrade/</guid><description>I must admit that wordpress is really exceptional, in few minutes I upgraded my blog to the new version. Now I hope that everything is ok! :D
Alk.
Tags: WordPress</description></item><item><title>LINQ to XML 8211 really interesting</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/linq-to-xml-really-interesting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/linq-to-xml-really-interesting/</guid><description>A lot of people tend to consider linq2sql the most important provider for linq, this is not true for me. First of all I tend to prefer NHibernate over Entity Framework and LINQ2SQL, and moreover I think that Linq 2 XML really rocks.
If you worked like me with XML you probably are frustrated of the many api you have to deal with: you have to know XPATH 1.0 and 2.</description></item><item><title>Entity Framework span and eager fetch</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/entity-framework-spam-and-eager-fetch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/entity-framework-spam-and-eager-fetch/</guid><description>Some minutes ago I posted about the Entity Framework and fetching strategy. After a little search in the documentation, I finally found how to prefetch using a concept called * span *. Here is a LINQ query that load a department eagerly fetching the courses collection
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 var query = from d in conn.Department.Include(&amp;#34;Course&amp;#34;) where d.Name == &amp;#34;Economics&amp;#34; select d; foreach (Department dep in query) { Console.</description></item><item><title>windows server 2008</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/windows-server-2008/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2008 01:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/windows-server-2008/</guid><description>Today I installed windows server 2008 into VmWare Server. I must admit that VmWare server is fantastic, the system goes smooth, it seems to work on a real machine and not on a windows server.
The only thing that does not work is the aero desktop, probably because the SVGA video emulation does not support 3D function to support aero.
Alk.
Tags: Windows Server 2008 vmware</description></item><item><title>error MSB3464</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/error-msb3464/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2008 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/error-msb3464/</guid><description>Today I was creating some nant build to automate the deploy of a webproject, I use the wdproj extension for visual studio 2005 to create a web deployment project, then I add a task to the nant script to simply build the wdproj with msbuild.exe.
The script give me error MSB3464, it turns out that I call msbuild with the parameter /p:Platform=&amp;quot;Any CPU&amp;rdquo; and this was the cause of the problem.</description></item><item><title>Technorati tags does not work</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/technorati-tags-does-not-work/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2008 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/technorati-tags-does-not-work/</guid><description>This is a test to technorati Tags, It seems that technorati tags does not work anymore.
Technorati Tags: Technorati
Tags: Technorati</description></item><item><title>CCNEt and error in file ccnetconfig</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/ccnet-and-error-in-file-ccnetconfig/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2008 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/04/ccnet-and-error-in-file-ccnetconfig/</guid><description>Sometimes it happens that editing xml file ccnet.config you can made some mistake, if for example the xml is not well formed, the cc.net server simply ignore the change.
As a rule of thumb, when I make modification in ccnet.config file I stopped the server, modify the file and then launch ccnet.exe from commandline, in this way I can easily find any error in the config. When the config is ok I start the service again.</description></item><item><title>Test post</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/03/test-post/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2008 01:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/03/test-post/</guid><description>I have moved to a new computer this is a test post.
Alk.</description></item><item><title>IQueryable</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/03/iqueryable/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 01:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/03/iqueryable/</guid><description>Implementing IQueryable is not a joke, here there is an excellent tutorial. I’m actually playing on Linq2Nhibernate by ayende and I realize that traversing an Expression Tree is not so painful, but surely complicated.
Alk.</description></item><item><title>C 30 Expression Trees</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/02/c-30-expression-trees/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2008 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/02/c-30-expression-trees/</guid><description>One of the most impressing features of C# 3.0 are Lamba expression, because they are *not only syntactic sugar.*If you are not convinced try to run the following two pieces of codes in LINQ to SQL
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 FirstTestDataContext context = new FirstTestDataContext(); context.Log = Console.Out; IEnumerable&amp;lt;Customer&amp;gt; custs = context.Customers .Where(C =&amp;gt; C.CustomerID.StartsWith(&amp;#34;A&amp;#34;)); Console.WriteLine(&amp;#34;Recuperati {0} oggetti Customer&amp;#34;, custs.Count()); custs = context.Customers .Where(delegate(Customer C) { return C.</description></item><item><title>Nant and The specified solution configuration Debugmcd is invalid</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/02/nant-and-the-specified-solution-configuration-debugmcd-is-invalid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2008 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/02/nant-and-the-specified-solution-configuration-debugmcd-is-invalid/</guid><description>Today a friend of mine tell me that in his new windows vista computer one nant scritp stopped working giving the error The specified solution configuration “Debug|MCD” is invalid during the msbuild part of the script. After a brief search it turns out that the msbuild command line is not correct because it miss the /p:Platform instruction, my command line now is
1 2 3 &amp;lt;exec program=&amp;#34;${MSBuild}&amp;#34; commandline=&amp;#39; ${ProjectDir}\${BuildSolutionName} /verbosity:quiet /T:rebuild /p:Configuration=Debug /p:Platform=&amp;#34;Any CPU&amp;#34;&amp;#39; basedir=&amp;#34;.</description></item><item><title>sgenexe and strongly named assemblies</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/02/sgenexe-and-strongly-named-assemblies/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2008 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/02/sgenexe-and-strongly-named-assemblies/</guid><description>Today I was facing a strange exception with a XmlSerializer, it gives to me FileNotFoundException NHibernate.XmlSerializers, it turns out that the debug settings are set to “break to all exceptions” and so the visual studio Ide warn me even for handled exception.
After some search I found that the xxxx.XmlSerializers assembly is a pregenerated assembly that the xmlserializers looks for before attempting to generate one at runtime, so if you want to have better performance you can pregenerate such an assembly.</description></item><item><title>Test with windows live writer</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/02/test-with-windows-live-writer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2008 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/02/test-with-windows-live-writer/</guid><description>After some months, I decided that Microsoft Word maybe is not the best app to blog, so I come back to Window Live Writer, but now I had to choose the plugin to insert code. I have some old plugin for the beta version, this post is a try to understand if they works again well.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 private void DoBind() { Int32 count = GetCount(); String Query = PrepareQuery(CurrentOrder, AscendingOrder, MyGridView1.</description></item><item><title>Some thinking in a Cold day</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/10/119/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2007 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/10/119/</guid><description>Today I was reading some posts (Simone, Ayende, Alessandro and others). I want now to express my opinion, I’m using my English blog, even if English is not my first language because I like to make it readable by all people, and I hope that I can be clear enough, please everyone to excuse my English :D
I found myself in the same situation of Simone, quite often I’m the one who strive itself to be up to date, I use most of my spare time reading books, blogs, trying new techniques, trying to learn how to write better code, but quite often I’m the only one to do this kind of process at work.</description></item><item><title>Pocket pc emulator and cradle in windos vista</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/09/pocket-pc-emulator-and-cradle-in-windos-vista/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2007 12:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/09/pocket-pc-emulator-and-cradle-in-windos-vista/</guid><description>Today I open my visual studio, open “Device emulator manager” started an emulator of virtual pc and then “Cradle” the decive to access with WMDC (Windows mobile device center)&amp;hellip;the result is nothing, my emulator won’t cradle L
After a little search I found that there is a new version for WMDC downloadable here, this resolves partially my problem, sometimes my device continue to refuse to cradle, the only way to make it work is close and reopen WMDC.</description></item><item><title>Custom services failed to start even if automatic start is enabled</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/09/custom-services-failed-to-start-even-if-automatic-start-is-enabled/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2007 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/09/custom-services-failed-to-start-even-if-automatic-start-is-enabled/</guid><description>One of my colleague write a service for windows, he install the service on a server, then set the startup mode as “automatic” but the service fail to start. When the server is rebooted the service is in state stopped, if you start the service all is good, but the service is not started whenever the system restarts.
The major cause of the problem is that the service is installed without specifying some dependency.</description></item><item><title>How to add reference to MicrosoftVisualStudioDesignerInterfaces</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/09/how-to-add-reference-to-microsoftvisualstudiodesignerinterfaces/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2007 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/09/how-to-add-reference-to-microsoftvisualstudiodesignerinterfaces/</guid><description>I need to create a project and add references to Microsoft.VisualStuidio.Designer.Interfaces, since it does not get listed on the standard reference pane I resort editing the csproj manually adding the references.
&amp;lt;Reference Include=”Microsoft.VisualStudio.Designer.Interfaces, Version=1.0.5000.0, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=b03f5f7f11d50a3a”&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;SpecificVersion&amp;gt;False&amp;lt;/SpecificVersion&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;HintPath&amp;gt;D:\Program Files\Microsoft Visual Studio 8\Common7\IDE\Microsoft.VisualStudio.Designer.Interfaces.DLL&amp;lt;/HintPath&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/Reference&amp;gt;
Someone could suggest a better and less hardcore way?
Alk.</description></item><item><title>Test</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/09/test/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2007 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/09/test/</guid><description>This week I come back from vacation, and I found that word cannot publish anymore on my blog, I recreate all the settings for the blog and this is the first try. I hope things went ok.
This is to try to post an image, this is my simpsonization.
Alk.</description></item><item><title>VmWare update installer Vmdb error -2 Schema path not found</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/08/vmware-update-installer-vmdb-error-2-schema-path-not-found/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2007 22:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/08/vmware-update-installer-vmdb-error-2-schema-path-not-found/</guid><description>This morning I turn on a virtual machine, and when I try to change configuration a strange error (Vmdb error -2: Schema path not found ) appears. After a little search I discover that my server version is version 1.0.3 and the console is 1.0.2. The error turns out to be caused by the installer of the upgrade. Instead of upgrading the old link it install side by site newer version of the client and create a new link.</description></item><item><title>When older is better</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/07/when-older-is-better/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2007 01:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/07/when-older-is-better/</guid><description>Yesterday I was called to solve a problem. There is a web application that works with a ActiveX control packaged in a.Cab file, but client machine have standard user logged. What we needed was the following, when a user navigate to a page that contain a reference to that control, IE should automatically download and install the control even if the user have not administrative rights on the machine.
Microsoft explain how to use Active Directory to do this, it is really useful and I found another article that explain how to create a valid msi installer file to achieve the result.</description></item><item><title>Parse a date in NET</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/parse-a-date-in-net/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2007 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/parse-a-date-in-net/</guid><description>Today I had a little bug in an application of mine, I have a routine that accepts a series of parameter through a comma separated string of values, this kind of interface to a function is not a good thing to do, expecially when DateTime variables are transmitted, but this is an old routine and worked well for a while, so I did not refactor.
The problem is arising now when the application build another function on top of this routine.</description></item><item><title>Padding is invalid and cannot be removed</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/padding-is-invalid-and-cannot-be-removed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2007 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/padding-is-invalid-and-cannot-be-removed/</guid><description>After another release of our project in production machine sometimes I see in the log this strange error
System.Security.Cryptography.CryptographicException: Padding is invalid and cannot be removed.
System.Security.Cryptography.CryptographicException: Padding is invalid and cannot be removed.
at System.Security.Cryptography.RijndaelManagedTransform.DecryptData(Byte[] inputBuffer, Int32 inputOffset, Int32 inputCount, Byte[]&amp;amp; outputBuffer, Int32 outputOffset, PaddingMode paddingMode, Boolean fLast)
at System.Security.Cryptography.RijndaelManagedTransform.TransformFinalBlock(Byte[] inputBuffer, Int32 inputOffset, Int32 inputCount)
at System.Security.Cryptography.CryptoStream.FlushFinalBlock()
at System.Web.Configuration.MachineKeySection.EncryptOrDecryptData(Boolean fEncrypt, Byte[] buf, Byte[] modifier, Int32 start, Int32 length, Boolean useValidationSymAlgo)</description></item><item><title>WatiN looking for content in GridView</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/watin-looking-for-content-in-gridview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2007 04:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/watin-looking-for-content-in-gridview/</guid><description>Quite often I need to automate test page and check that the contents of a GridView contains exactly some strings. First of all I have an helper class that helps me to cope with the name that asp.net give to controls contained in another controls, then I write some helper methods to assert that the content of a grid is what I expected to be.
publicstaticvoid TableContentEqAssertion(IE ie, String tableName, Int32 row, Int32 col, String expectedvalue) {</description></item><item><title>A pattern to access DB with IDataReader</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/a-pattern-to-access-db-with-idatareader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2007 04:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/a-pattern-to-access-db-with-idatareader/</guid><description>Some days ago I posted about an helper class to easy the access to database. I took original code by ayende and do slightly modifications to make database indipendent. A natural extension to that class is the ability to retrieve a datareader with some data. An initial solution is simply call the core Execute() function with this code.
Nablasoft.Helpers.DataAccess.Execute(
delegate(DbCommand command, DbProviderFactory factory) {
command.CommandType = System.Data.CommandType.Text;
command.CommandText = “SELECT CompanyName FROM Customers WHERE CustomerId = @id”;</description></item><item><title>I really love amazon</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/i-really-love-amazon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2007 01:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/i-really-love-amazon/</guid><description>Few clicks, 100$ and in only 4 days from Amazon directly to my desk in Italy J
Alk.</description></item><item><title>Falling in love with a ghost D</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/falling-in-love-with-a-ghost-d/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2007 22:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/falling-in-love-with-a-ghost-d/</guid><description>After a long time that some friends told me about boo language, finally yesterday I downloaded the trunk and began to familiarize with the language. The first thing that surprised me is the ability to break into debugger with simple instruction like these
import System.Diagnostics
Debug.Fail(“”)
And your favorite debugger will show up with full support for intellisense, step and so on, I’m very pleased with this.
Alk.</description></item><item><title>An helper class to access databases with ado</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/an-helper-class-to-access-databases-with-ado/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2007 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/an-helper-class-to-access-databases-with-ado/</guid><description>A while ago I read an exceptional post by Ayende, I found it very interesting, and I decided to use his technique with some projects, but I choose to do a little modification to make the code works with every type of database, not only with SqlServer. Here is my version. All real code is made by ayende, I simply do some changes to make it database agnostic.
publicstaticvoid Execute(VoidFunc&amp;lt;DbCommand, DbProviderFactory&amp;gt; functionToExecute) {</description></item><item><title>Today is not a good day</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/today-is-not-a-good-day/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/06/today-is-not-a-good-day/</guid><description>Today is not a good day for a couple of reasons, but now my visual studio instance begins to behave in a strange manner, when I digit ALT+126 to make tilde character in a code windows, a strange chars appears instead of tilde, and the font of the visual studio changes, here how it looks like on my monitor
In every other window ALT+126 works as expected (~), mah&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>First month of my blog</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/05/first-month-of-my-blog/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2007 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/05/first-month-of-my-blog/</guid><description>This is a snapshot of the first month’s statistics by Google Analytics :D. It was really not a lot of traffic :D, but I hope that next month will be better.</description></item><item><title>Windows vista and the nostalgic users of command line D</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/05/windows-vista-and-the-nostalgic-users-of-command-line-d/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2007 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/05/windows-vista-and-the-nostalgic-users-of-command-line-d/</guid><description>I needed to copy the windows sdk file (1.2 Gigabytes) from the desktop pc to my laptop, via Ethernet 100 mbps. I begin navigating to the network folder and try to right click the file to select copy. The result is that my laptop get hung&amp;hellip;after some while I realized that my antivirus is trying to scan the network file to see if the file is virus free&amp;hellip;I immediately terminate the antivirus, and change the option not to scan network files.</description></item><item><title>Subversion Versus Team Foundation</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/05/subversion-versus-team-foundation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2007 22:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/05/subversion-versus-team-foundation/</guid><description>This morning I was reading this post, and I must admit that even I with my AbstractView project use Subversion (Google Code) to keep track of the sources of the project. Team Foundation Server and the features exposed through codeplex are really amazing, but when it is time to speak about Source Control I think that Subversion is a product really superior.
I use Subversion not only with Google Code but also with a dedicated server to keep all the source code of the company where I work.</description></item></channel></rss>