<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Visual Studio Database Edition on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/visual-studio-database-edition/</link><description>Recent content in Visual Studio Database Edition on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 10:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/visual-studio-database-edition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Database Edition Custom Rule</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/database-edition-custom-rule/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/database-edition-custom-rule/</guid><description>One of the coolest feature of Visual Studio Database Edition is the ability to run Rules against a database project, like fxcop against a c# project. And the coolest part about this feature is that is really simple to write a custom rule.
Rules are important, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen project where there is no naming rule for objects in database, and so you will end with tables with column like, ablr_xxxx or xxxxx_xxx_Authorname etc etc, and the whole database looses consistency over time.</description></item><item><title>vsdbcmdexe overriding variable value</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/vsdbcmd-exe-overriding-variable-value/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2009 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/vsdbcmd-exe-overriding-variable-value/</guid><description>When you deploy a database project with the command line utility vsdbcmd.exe you may want to change the value of some variables of the project. Suppose you&amp;rsquo;ve created a variable called Path1
And you have used this variable to specify the location of the files
1 2 ALTER DATABASE [$(DatabaseName)] ADD FILE (NAME = [Northwind], FILENAME = &amp;#39;$(Path1)$(DatabaseName).mdf&amp;#39;, Now you want to decide at deploy time the physical location of your database.</description></item><item><title>Data Dude for Visual Studio 2010</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/data-dude-for-visual-studio-2010/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/data-dude-for-visual-studio-2010/</guid><description>For those out there that are, like me, fans of Data Dude, here is a link that shows you the news about Data Dude in VS2010.
The most appealing part is that database projects are now supported starting from VS professional edition, so I&amp;rsquo;m expecting that more and more people will try to manage databases with Visual Studio. Clearly most of the features are still available only for VS Premium or VS Ultimate users, but at least, people with professional can compile a DB Project, Execute unit testing or data generation plan (but only people with Premium and Ultimate are able to create and manage them).</description></item><item><title>Data Driven Test of a stored procedure in Database Edition</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/data-driven-test-of-a-stored-procedure-in-database-edition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/data-driven-test-of-a-stored-procedure-in-database-edition/</guid><description>Database Tests are really a great feature of Database Edition, and, like other tests, you can create a Data Driven Test of a stored procedure with little effort. The first stuff I do is to create a database project that will contains a table for each sets of data I want to use in a test.
In this project I create a table for each sets of data, and create a script to preload the data as post-deployment script.</description></item><item><title>Faster Database Test With database in Virtual Disk</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/09/faster-database-test-with-database-in-virtual-disk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/09/faster-database-test-with-database-in-virtual-disk/</guid><description>When you work with Visual Studio Database Edition, you surely love the data generation plans, and the ability to do database unit testing with automatic deploy and automatic preload. There is only one thing that is bad with database testing, they are usually slowbecause they are accessing disks*.*
To speedup database testing the best solution is to test database in memory, but with sql server it can be difficult&amp;hellip;or not? With a simple software that create a RAMDisk, (a disk made of ram like Dataram one), you are able to create RAMDisk with few clicks and have a disk that actually runs at memory speed.</description></item></channel></rss>