<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Searching on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/searching/</link><description>Recent content in Searching on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 19:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/searching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TFS 2018 Update 3 is out what changes for Search</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/09/tfs-2018-update-3-is-out-what-changes-for-search/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/09/tfs-2018-update-3-is-out-what-changes-for-search/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/visualstudio/releasenotes/tfs2018-update3">TFS 2018 Update 3 is finally out&lt;/a> and in release notes there is a nice news for Search functionality, &lt;strong>basic security now enforced through a custom plugin&lt;/strong>. Here is what you can read in release notes&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Basic authorization is now enabled on the communication between the TFS and Search services to make it more secure. Any user installing or upgrading to Update 3 will need to provide a user name / password while configuring Search (and also during Search Service setup in case of remote Search Service).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increase RAM for ElasticSearch for TFS Search</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/01/increase-ram-for-elasticsearch-for-tfs-search/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/01/increase-ram-for-elasticsearch-for-tfs-search/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are experiencing slow search in TFS with the new Search functionality based on ElasticSearch a typical suggestion is to give more RAM to the machine where ES is installed. Clearly you should use HQ or other tools to really pin down the root cause but &lt;strong>most of the time the problem is not enough RAM, or slow disks&lt;/strong>. The second cause can be easily solved moving data to an SSD disk, but giving more RAM to the machine, usually gives more space for OS File cache and can solve even the problem of slow disk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monitor TFS Search data Usage</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/01/monitor-tfs-search-data-usage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 12:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/01/monitor-tfs-search-data-usage/</guid><description>&lt;p>In previous post I’ve explained how to move searches component in a different machine in a TFS 2018 installation, now it is time to &lt;strong>understand how to monitor that instance.&lt;/strong> First of all you should monitor the folder that physically contains data, in my installation is C:\tfs\ESDATA (it is a parameter you choose when you configure the Search Server with &lt;strong>Configure-TFSSearch.ps1 -Operation install&lt;/strong> PowerShell script). &lt;strong>Data folder should be placed on a fast disk, usually SSD are the best choice&lt;/strong>. If the SSD will ever fail, you can always restart ES with empty data folder and use scripts to force TFS to reindex everything.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TFS 2018 search components in different server</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/01/tfs-2018-search-components-in-different-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/01/tfs-2018-search-components-in-different-server/</guid><description>&lt;p>When it is time to design topology of a TFS installation, for small team the &lt;strong>single server is usually the best choice in term of licensing (one one Windows Server license is  needed) and simplicity of maintenance.&lt;/strong> Traditionally the only problem that can occur is: some component (especially the Analysis and Reporting services) starts to slow down the machine if the amount of data starts to become consistent.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Single machine TFS installation is probably the best choice for small teams..&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Case sensitivity in lucene search</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/07/case-sensitivity-in-lucene-search/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/07/case-sensitivity-in-lucene-search/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2012/06/20/getting-started-with-lucene-net/">Getting Started With Lucene.NET&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2012/06/21/getting-started-with-lucene-netsearching/">Searching and more detail on Documents Fields&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2012/07/03/advanced-queries-with-lucene-net/">Advanced Queries with Lucene.NET&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We ended last post with a good knowledge of how to do complex searches in Lucene.NET indexes but a question remains unresolved, is Lucene.NET search &lt;strong>case insensitive or case insensitive?&lt;/strong>. Suppose you search for&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>+mime + format&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is the first result returned from the above query.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/image1.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/image_thumb1.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/image_thumb1.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Figure 1&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>: &lt;em>Searching for +mime +format returns a document that contains MIME in uppercase.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Lucenenet</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/06/getting-started-with-lucene-net/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/06/getting-started-with-lucene-net/</guid><description>&lt;p>I started working with &lt;a href="http://incubator.apache.org/lucene.net/">Lucene.Net&lt;/a> and I should admit that is a real powerful library, but it is really huge and needs a little bit of time to be mastered completely. Probably one of the best resource to keep in mind is the &lt;a href="http://wiki.apache.org/lucene-java/LuceneFAQ">FAQ&lt;/a>, because it contains really most of the more common question you can have on Lucene and it is a good place to start. Another good place is the &lt;a href="http://wiki.apache.org/lucene-java/FrontPage?action=show&amp;amp;amp;redirect=FrontPageEN">Wiki&lt;/a> that contains other useful information and many other link to relevant resources.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>