<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tools and Library on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/tools-and-library/</link><description>Recent content in Tools and Library on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 16:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/tools-and-library/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Application insight Snapshot debugger and strange production problem</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/07/application-insight-snapshot-debugger-and-strange-production-problem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/07/application-insight-snapshot-debugger-and-strange-production-problem/</guid><description>&lt;p>I want to share with you an history of a problem we had in production last week, because after lots of internet search no article lead us to find the solution, so I hope that this article can help you if you experience the very same problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Situation: we deployed new version of a web application based on ASP.NET Web API, it was a small increment (we deploy frequently), but suddenly the customer starts experiencing slowness of the application and intermittent errors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Load Security Alerts in Azure Application Insight</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/08/load-security-alert-in-azure-application-insight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/08/load-security-alert-in-azure-application-insight/</guid><description>&lt;p>Security is one of the big problem of the modern web, business moved to web application and security become an important part of application development. One side of the problem is adding standard and proved procedure to avoid risk of basic attacks like SQL or NO SQL injection, but &lt;strong>big part of security was programmed at application level.&lt;/strong> If you are using SPA with some client framework like Angular and have business logic exposed with API, (Ex ASP NET Web API), you cannot trust the client, thus &lt;strong>you need to validate every server call for authorization and authentication.&lt;/strong> &amp;gt; &lt;strong>When API layer is exposed to a web application it is one of the preferred attack surfaces for your application. Never ever trust your UI logic to protect from malicious calls&lt;/strong> One of the most typical attack is forging calls to your API layer, a task that can be automated with tools like BURP Suite or WAPT and it is a major source of problem. As an example, if you have some administrative page where you grant or deny claim to users, it is imperative that every call should be accepted only if the authenticated user is an administrator of the system. &lt;strong>Application logic can become complicated, as an example you can have access to a document because it is linked to an offer made in France and you are the Area Manager for France.&lt;/strong> The more security logic is complex the more you should test it, but you probably cannot cover 100% of the situations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Exclude Folders from SonarQube analysis</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/07/exclude-folders-from-sonarqube-analysis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/07/exclude-folders-from-sonarqube-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;p>Creating a build that is capable of perform a SonarQube analysis on a VSTS /  TFS is a really simple task, thanks to the two tasks that are present out-of-the box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image-9.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image_thumb-9.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/image_thumb-9.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Figure 1&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>: &lt;em>Build that uses Sonarqube tasks to perform analysis&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem in a project that was alive for more than a couple of years is that &lt;strong>you usually have a really bad report when you do your first analysis.&lt;/strong> This happens because, without a constant analysis, the code have surely some smells.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sonar Upgrade from 51 to 53</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/02/sonar-upgrade-from-5-1-to-5-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/02/sonar-upgrade-from-5-1-to-5-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>I really like SonarQube, but I need to admit that upgrade procedures are not the best experience I’ve had. &lt;strong>Upgrading from 5.1 to 5.3 should be a simple task, but I had a couple of problems.&lt;/strong> I’ve followed the official upgrade instruction: &lt;a href="http://docs.sonarqube.org/display/SONAR/Upgrading" title="http://docs.sonarqube.org/display/SONAR/Upgrading">http://docs.sonarqube.org/display/SONAR/Upgrading&lt;/a> but the first problem was my connection string to SQL Server, that needs to be changed. Original connection string was&lt;/p>
&lt;p>sonar.jdbc.url=jdbc:jtds:sqlserver://localhost/Sonar;SelectMethod=Cursor;instance=sqlexpress&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But it seems that with the new version of Solr it needs to be changed because jtds is not anymore used. The string was changed to&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BufferingAppenderSkeleton performance problem in log4net</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/03/bufferingappenderskeleton-performance-problem-in-log4net/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/03/bufferingappenderskeleton-performance-problem-in-log4net/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-problem">The problem&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today I was working to &lt;a href="http://www.ienumerable.it/">Jarvis&lt;/a> project and I got a warning from another developer telling me that MongoDbAppender for Log4net slows down the application during a full Rebuild of all projections. In that specific situation we have log level set to DEBUG and the rebuild generates 800k logs inside mongo database, so I’m expecting Mongo Appender to slow down a little bit. The problem is: &lt;strong>using a standard FileAppender to verify difference in speed it results that the FileAppender was really faster than the MongoDbAppender&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Deploy Web Site with PowerShell DSC</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/06/how-to-deploy-web-site-with-powershell-dsc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/06/how-to-deploy-web-site-with-powershell-dsc/</guid><description>&lt;p>I do not want to create another tutorial on DSC and I suggest you reading some introductory articles like: &lt;a href="http://blogs.technet.com/b/privatecloud/archive/2013/08/30/introducing-powershell-desired-state-configuration-dsc.aspx">Introducing PowerShell Desired State Configuration&lt;/a> before reading this article. Since I’m pretty new with PowerShell and I’m starting experimenting with DSC I decided to &lt;strong>start creating a script to deploy my favorite test application (TailspinToys :) ) on a single Windows 2012 R2 server using only DSC&lt;/strong>. This post aims to share my thought on the subject.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NDepend 4 and CQLinq</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/ndepend-4-and-cqlinq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/05/ndepend-4-and-cqlinq/</guid><description>&lt;p>You already know that &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2010/11/03/ndepend-to-the-resque/">I’m a fan of NDepend&lt;/a> because &lt;strong>it is a really useful tool to have a deep insight on your code and especially to spot out troublesome areas in your project&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With version 4 it added a really cool capability called &lt;a href="http://www.ndepend.com/doc_cqlinq_features.aspx">CQLinq&lt;/a> or Code Query Linq; an amazing feature that permits you to query your code using LINQ stile queries. Basically after I’ve analyzed a solution I got presented with a simple dialog that asked me what I’m interested to do primarily with the result of the analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Git is fantastic but IMHO too complex to use</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/git-is-fantastic-but-imho-too-complex-to-use/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/git-is-fantastic-but-imho-too-complex-to-use/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve blogged some time ago on the basic fact that &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2012/07/25/i-do-not-like-git-if-you-want-blame-me-for-this/">I’m not a Git lover&lt;/a> and a couple of days ago I stumbled upon this post (&lt;a href="https://steveko.wordpress.com/2012/02/24/10-things-i-hate-about-git/">10 things I hate about Git&lt;/a>), where the author did a full explanation of various reason why he does not like Git.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have read in the past the excellent book by David Platt &lt;a href="http://www.whysoftwaresucks.com/">Why Software Sucks&lt;/a> you should agree that, while Git is surely a really good, fast, powerful, complete source control system, that permits you to do marvelous stuff, it lacks simplicity. And although it is a tool for programmer I think that it is too difficult to use for the basic everyday operations. In my opinion Git is a perfect example of a tool that was &lt;strong>built to make complex thing possible but not to make simple things simpler&lt;/strong> (as suggested in David Platt’s book).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting started with LuceneNET-Searching</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/06/getting-started-with-lucene-netsearching/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/06/getting-started-with-lucene-netsearching/</guid><description>&lt;p>Previous part of the series&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2012/06/20/getting-started-with-lucene-net/">Getting Started With Lucene.NET&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In the previous part I’ve showed how easy is to create an index with lucene.net, but in this post I’ll start to explain how to search into it, first of all what I need is &lt;strong>a more interesting example, so I decided to download a &lt;a href="http://blog.stackoverflow.com/2009/06/stack-overflow-creative-commons-data-dump/">dump of stack overflow&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> , and I’ve extracted the Posts.Xml file (10 GB of XML file), then I wrote this &lt;strong>simple piece of text to create the lucene index&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting Started with Lucenenet</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/06/getting-started-with-lucene-net/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/06/getting-started-with-lucene-net/</guid><description>&lt;p>I started working with &lt;a href="http://incubator.apache.org/lucene.net/">Lucene.Net&lt;/a> and I should admit that is a real powerful library, but it is really huge and needs a little bit of time to be mastered completely. Probably one of the best resource to keep in mind is the &lt;a href="http://wiki.apache.org/lucene-java/LuceneFAQ">FAQ&lt;/a>, because it contains really most of the more common question you can have on Lucene and it is a good place to start. Another good place is the &lt;a href="http://wiki.apache.org/lucene-java/FrontPage?action=show&amp;amp;amp;redirect=FrontPageEN">Wiki&lt;/a> that contains other useful information and many other link to relevant resources.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Mongo Database to store Log4Net logs</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/using-mongo-database-to-store-log4net-logs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/using-mongo-database-to-store-log4net-logs/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most simple and useful way to introduce a &lt;strong>Documents Database&lt;/strong> like &lt;strong>Mongo&lt;/strong> in your organization is to use as Log Storage. If you use &lt;a href="http://logging.apache.org/log4net/">&lt;strong>log4Net&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> you can download a &lt;a href="http://maddemcode.com/net/log4net-mongodb-appender/">Mongo appender&lt;/a> capable of storing logs inside mongo with few lines of code and you are ready to go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The original appender is really good but I’ve done a little modification to make it capable of storing complex item in extended properties, just locate the function LogginEventToBSON and modify the section that stores Composite Properties with following code&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Red-Gate Webinars</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/01/red-gate-webinar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/01/red-gate-webinar/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you work with Sql Server and like &lt;a href="http://www.red-gate.com">Red-Gate&lt;/a> tools, you can find a couple of interesting webinars to see some features of their exceptional tools in action. If you are interested you can find &lt;a href="http://www.red-gate.com/products/sql-development/sql-source-control/webinars">all the details here&lt;/a>; webinars are free and require only a registration, so go and take a look at what Red Gate can offer :).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gian Maria.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Subversion 17 and the new workspace</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/10/subversion-1-7-and-the-new-workspace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/10/subversion-1-7-and-the-new-workspace/</guid><description>&lt;p>Subversion 1.7 has a new format of the workspace, the first important stuff is that there are not a.svn folder for each mapped folder, but it has only a single.svn folder in the root of the local mapping of the repository. This lead to a tremendous improvement in performance with very big repository. Actually doing an update from my SSD on a project that has thousands of folder is almost instantaneous. Just install the new version of tortoise, update the local workspace and you are done.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting Microsoft Dynamic CRM 2011 connection with Outlook</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/07/troubleshooting-microsoft-dynamic-crm-2011-connection-with-outlook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/07/troubleshooting-microsoft-dynamic-crm-2011-connection-with-outlook/</guid><description>&lt;p>I should specify that I really do not know Microsoft Dynamic CRM 2011, but this morning a friend of mine called me to troubleshoot a problem with Outlook integration. The problem with Outlook connection is that it is based upon a WCF service and my friend told me that the service did not start, each time he tried to browser to the service with a browser (&lt;a href="http://crm.mycompany.com:5555/XRMServices/2011/discovery.svc">http://crm.mycompany.com:5555/XRMServices/2011/discovery.svc&lt;/a>) he got an error and watching the Event Viewer he found the exception message, but he was not able to understand what was wrong.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploy on remote machine during builds</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/deploy-on-remote-machine-during-builds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2010 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/deploy-on-remote-machine-during-builds/</guid><description>&lt;p>Clearly Lab Management is really good to &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2010/06/29/deploy-a-solution-and-a-database-in-a-lab-management-virtual-environment/">manage virtual environment&lt;/a>s and give a lot of flexibility on how to deploy your application on virtual machines, but if you do not have Lab Management you can still use the same technique to deploy application in remote computer during a build with the use of a simple scripts. The key is the ability to execute code on a remote computer with &lt;a href="http://www.beyondlogic.org/solutions/remoteprocess/BeyondExec.htm">beyondexec&lt;/a> or similar tool. Suppose you need to deploy an application called demo, you have a Tfs build called Demo, and you want to be able to deploy a specific build on a remote server, the solution could be this simple script&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Extremely slow operation and log4net</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/extremely-slow-operation-and-log4net/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/extremely-slow-operation-and-log4net/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m currently profiling a web application, and I noticed that for some combination of input, a specific search into the database is really really slow. After verifying that the query is not responsible for this problem I fire a profiler, load the page, issue the search and then verify with ant profiler the method that need more time to be executed. The result was that the method that needs more time to be executed is one called Send Alert, that simply logs with log4net to a specific logger called Alert.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Change return value of a mock based on parameters in Rhino mocks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/change-return-value-of-a-mock-based-on-parameters-in-rhino-mocks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/change-return-value-of-a-mock-based-on-parameters-in-rhino-mocks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes there is the need to change the return value of an expectation to a Mock with a value based on parameters used in the call. Suppose you need to create a mock, and want to verify that the method DoInt() gets called with a value greater than 42 and it should return the value augmented by one, how you can setup the expectation?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The secret is in the WhenCalled method exposed by the mock, that permits you to access the full MethodInvocation object that gets generated during the real invocation. Here is the solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Repair Visual Studio template</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/repair-visual-studio-template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/06/repair-visual-studio-template/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some minutes ago I installed Expression studio 4.0, while I&amp;rsquo;m working with a couple of solution in VS2008, when I close the solution and open another solution I see that I was not able anymore to work with test projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All test projects inside any solution appear as folder, and I was not able anymore to create a test project. I do not know if something get wrong during installation of Expression tools while I have a couple of VS instances opened or there was some problem on my machine that happened for any other reason :), but whenever you got problem with project templates in Visual Studio, such as missing project types, you can try to run&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NDepend 30 a must have tool</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/ndepend-3-0-a-must-have-tool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/ndepend-3-0-a-must-have-tool/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m exploring the new capabilities of NDepend 3.0, and the very first interesting stuff is that I&amp;rsquo;m now able in VS2010 to add a NDepend project to the solution, so I&amp;rsquo;m able to manage ndepend project properties inside from VS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/image13.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/image_thumb13.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/05/image_thumb13.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can drag and drop project inside the windows to add and remove project from the analysis, and this is very productive. After you run the analysis you can navigate into the result, as an example you can choose from the NDepend menu the CQL explorer&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Red Gate Sql Prompt Expand wildcard</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/red-gate-sql-prompt-expand-wildcard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/red-gate-sql-prompt-expand-wildcard/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the feature that I loved most from &lt;a href="http://www.red-gate.com/">Red Gate&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.red-gate.com/products/sql_prompt/index.htm">Sql Prompt&lt;/a> is the ability to expand wildcards on queries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Suppose I write this little query:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">
&lt;table style="border-spacing:0;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">&lt;tr>&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">1
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">2
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">3
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;;width:100%">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>SELECT *
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>FROM dbo.Items
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>WHERE item_scan_id = &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">2&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When I press play the query is very slow because the Item table has a column that stores large BLOB data, so I want to recover all the columns except that one that contains binary data. With Sql Prompt you can simple put the cursor after the * and press tab&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A quick look at NDepend</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/a-quick-look-at-ndepend/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2010 12:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/05/a-quick-look-at-ndepend/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ndepend.com/">NDepend&lt;/a> is a must have tool for people that manages seriously.NET projects, because it give you an overwhelming amount of information and metrics with few clicks. A complete tour of NDepend is really difficult to do, but I want to highlight what you got when you analyze a complex project, because NDepend can really save you a lot of troubles :).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After you load an entire project you can immediately see errors and warning&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Red Gate Tools Sql Dependency Tracker</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/red-gate-tools-sql-dependency-tracker/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2010 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/red-gate-tools-sql-dependency-tracker/</guid><description>&lt;p>I must admit that I really loves tools from &lt;a href="http://www.red-gate.com">RedGate&lt;/a> and recently I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered the &lt;a href="http://www.red-gate.com/products/SQL_Dependency_Tracker/index.htm">Sql Dependency Tracker&lt;/a>, an exceptional tool to manage dependencies between objects in a database.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This tool is really great because with a few click you can have different graphs that represents dependency relation between objects in the database. I&amp;rsquo;m working on a legacy database, and I have two very old view that were replaced by another indexed view, that performs better and has better column names. We ported almost everything, but I need to know if some stored procedure or object still uses the old views. I simply open the Sql Dependency Tracker and immediately I found this graph&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Temporary disable Resharper 5</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/temporary-disable-resharper-5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/04/temporary-disable-resharper-5/</guid><description>&lt;p>R# is really useful, but sometimes, when I&amp;rsquo;m working to very big web forms or winform projects, and I know that I do not need R# feature because I&amp;rsquo;m only designing the UI, it can be useful to temporary suspend R#, freeing memory and speeding a little bit VS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In R#5 the option to disable it is in the Tools-&amp;gt;Options menu&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/image19.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/image_thumb19.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2010/04/image_thumb19.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where you can easily stop and resume R# functionality. But the coolest feature is that you can simply disable and reenable R# with command Windows&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A useful tool Microsoft Baseline security Analyzer</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/a-useful-tool-microsoft-baseline-security-analyzer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/a-useful-tool-microsoft-baseline-security-analyzer/</guid><description>&lt;p>MBSA is a great tool, today I&amp;rsquo;m configuring a new production server, after I configure everything I simply run it and immediately it found some issues&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/10/image28.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/10/image-thumb28.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/10/image-thumb28.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I love of MBSA is that he immediately tells you how to solve the specific problem, in this situation I&amp;rsquo;ve installed a redistributable component, and mbsa tells me that he needs a critical update, and it points me immediately to the result&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TeamFuze Beta</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/teamfuze-beta/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/teamfuze-beta/</guid><description>&lt;p>Teamfuze (&lt;a href="http://www.teamfuze.net/index.jspa">http://www.teamfuze.net/index.jspa&lt;/a>) is gone beta, finally Oracle developers with Visual Studio 2010 Database Edition beta will experience the same feeling of Sql Server developers, when moving from old-style database development to VS Database Edition. You can sync database, put every object in source control system, generate test data, automate database sync during team build and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you develope with oracle you really have to try the beta ;) you will never want to come back :D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Manipulation of configuration files for deploy</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/manipulation-of-configuration-files-for-deploy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/manipulation-of-configuration-files-for-deploy/</guid><description>&lt;p>In my experience, one of the most feared problem during the &lt;em>going in production&lt;/em> phase of an asp.net site or a complex project is configurations. Usually everything works perfectly on developer machines, but when you move the project in production machines all sort of problems appear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For Asp.Net, one day one of my colleagues called me asking a little help troubleshooting some performance problem of a site in production, the problem was so big that after a couple of hours the application goes into memory overflow exception. After a brief inspection I saw that trace was keep enabled with a request limit of 10000 request&amp;hellip;the problem was simply due to wrong configuration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What makes a poor programmer happy</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/what-makes-a-poor-programmer-happy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/what-makes-a-poor-programmer-happy/</guid><description>&lt;p>I must create a duplicate of a database in another server, I need to duplicate only the structure of actual production database to use with a test web application to check how the webapp works with an empty database. I simply fired a command prompt, went to output directory of my database project, and typed&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">
&lt;table style="border-spacing:0;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">&lt;tr>&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">1
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;;width:100%">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>vsdbcmd /a:Deploy /ConnectionString:&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Data Source=10.8.x.x\sql2008;user=sa;pwd=xxxxxxxx&amp;#34;&lt;/span> /dsp:SQL /manifest:MyProject.deploymanifest /p:TargetDatabase=MyProjectEmptyDb&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;!-- Code inserted with Steve Dunn's Windows Live Writer Code Formatter Plugin. http://dunnhq.com -->
&lt;p>And after a couple of minutes the empty db is ready, with its 9 physical files, 5 filegroups, all the indexes, all fulltext defined etc etc  :D Thanks to Visual Studio Database Edition.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reshaper 45 beta</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/03/reshaper-45-beta/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/03/reshaper-45-beta/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I decided to install the beta of the new version of &lt;a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/resharper/beta.html">Resharper&lt;/a>. I must admit that I cannot work without reshaper :D now I&amp;rsquo;m so used to it that if I work with computers with no R# I spent some second Hitting shortcut and wondering why nothing happens :D. Here is my impression&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Installer is quick, it seems me quickier than older version, in about 30 seconds it uninstalled previous version and integrates in both vs2005 and vs2008. Solution opening time is improved, I did not made an exact measurement, but for a solution with a lot of project and a big asp.net site it can be noticed without actually measuring anything. With the 4.1 version I need to wait for about 20 second before being able to edit a file, now in about 10 seconds I can open and edit pages. (I have a 2 RAPTOR 10.000 rpm disk).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First Steps with Unity</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/first-steps-with-unity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2009 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/first-steps-with-unity/</guid><description>&lt;p>I use Castle.Windsor for IoC, and sometimes I used Spring; those two are really enough to cover all IoC problems I had in the past. I do no like very much &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/cc467894.aspx">Enterprise Library&lt;/a> but in some situation customers does not like open source code, and ask you to use only MS product, so it is worth to give a look at unity that is shipped as part of the enterprise library, but also distributed in stand alone form.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intellisense in Sql Server 2008 missing backward compatibility</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/intellisense-in-sql-server-2008-missing-backward-compatibility/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2009 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/intellisense-in-sql-server-2008-missing-backward-compatibility/</guid><description>&lt;p>I Know that Sql SErver 2008 have a lot of new feature in Database Engine, but one of the most loved feature is intellisense in Management Studio. Intellisense really helps you to improve productivity when you write T-Sql code, and it is great to have it included in base version of the MS. The disappointing stuff is that &lt;a href="http://connect.microsoft.com/SQLServer/feedback/ViewFeedback.aspx?FeedbackID=341872">it does not work when you connect to a sql server 2005 instance&lt;/a>. In my opinion this is bad, but MS have its reason to do so.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Optimize aspnet web application</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/optimize-aspnet-web-application/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 12:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/optimize-aspnet-web-application/</guid><description>&lt;p>The first step to optimize an application is &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/ricom/archive/2007/06/13/partly-sunny-chance-of-showers-bring-an-umbrella.aspx">measure measure measure&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo;, you cannot optimize nothing without measuring, you need some number that tells you where the application is slow and suggests you where to apply modifications, then after your optimization is done, run test suite again and measure again to check if performance are improved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In web applications one of the most annoying stuff is a slow home page, and asp.net sites quite often can suffer of this problem. To analyze why a page is slow you can use a lot of tools, but two of them are worth to mention. The first is &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/magazine/dd188562.aspx">Microsoft Visual Round Trip Analyzer&lt;/a>, it is a great tool, but you cannot use in an environment where the browser and the server are on the same machine &lt;a href="http://rangeofmotion.spaces.live.com/blog/cns!7C83677C017E6E58!155.entry">as you can read here&lt;/a>. The obvious solution is installing a virtual machine, then install VRTA on that machine and navigate from the virtual machine to your development machine, so you can use VRTA without any problem. You can read Msdn article above to find some useful informations on how to use VRTA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speed up your visual studio</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/speed-up-your-visual-studio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/speed-up-your-visual-studio/</guid><description>&lt;p>After a lot of years working with visual studio I realized that to speed up building process you need faster Disks. My actual configuration consists of Three disks, two of them are 10.000 RPM Western digital, with 16 MB cache configured in RAID 1 array with a dedicated adaptec RAID card. Then I have a secondary 7.200 Disk that I use to store temporary backup, download, and file of little importance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Resharper and switch to a different solution</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/resharper-and-switch-to-a-different-solution/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/01/resharper-and-switch-to-a-different-solution/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I close a solution from visual studio quite often resharper does not release memory&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/01/image.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/01/image-thumb.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/01/image-thumb.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To show this information you can simply go to Resharper-&amp;gt;options and in the General section under System check the &amp;ldquo;show managed memory usage in status bar&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/01/image1.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/01/image-thumb1.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/01/image-thumb1.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you can see I store caches in TEMP folder, this because I have two disks, so I prefer to keep caches in a disk different from the one used to store source code, in this way overall disk usage is better.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Performance of logging system</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/11/performance-of-logging-system/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/11/performance-of-logging-system/</guid><description>&lt;p>When you insert a logging system into your application you should do some preliminary test for performance issue. The most important thing is that logging infrastructure should not introduce too much overhead when the log is disabled. With log4net you have different way to handle the log, suppose you have a logger and the DEBUG level is disabled; you can use one of these three form&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">
&lt;table style="border-spacing:0;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">&lt;tr>&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">1
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">2
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">3
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">4
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">5
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;;width:100%">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>log1.Debug(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;TEST&amp;#34;&lt;/span>);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">if&lt;/span> (log1.IsDebugEnabled) log1.Debug(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;TEST&amp;#34;&lt;/span>);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Boolean isDebugEnabled = log1.IsDebugEnabled;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">if&lt;/span> (isDebugEnabled) log1.Debug(&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;TEST&amp;#34;&lt;/span>);&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;!-- Code inserted with Steve Dunn's Windows Live Writer Code Formatter Plugin. http://dunnhq.com -->
&lt;p>The first version rely on the fact that log4net infrastructure internally checks if debug is enabled so you can call Debug function directly. The second technique is to check if log1.IsDebugEnabled before calling log1.Debug(), and the third stores the IsDebugEnabled in a local variable to check that variable instead of calling IsDebugEnabled each time. If you do one million log calls you will obtain these rough measurements in milliseconds.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>View the current exception in Visual Studio</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/view-the-current-exception-in-visual-studio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2008 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/view-the-current-exception-in-visual-studio/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes you write pieces of code like this.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">
&lt;table style="border-spacing:0;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">&lt;tr>&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">1
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">2
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">3
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;;width:100%">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">catch&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> {
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> LogException(....&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;!-- Code inserted with Steve Dunn's Windows Live Writer Code Formatter Plugin. http://dunnhq.com -->
&lt;p>This type of exception handler catch everything and log, despite the fact that is not so good practice to catch every exception that a piece of code could raise, one of the most frustrating thing is that if you place a breakpoint in the LogException line, since you have not specified in the catch clause no exception you have no way to see detail of the exception.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Resharper and plugins</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/resharper-and-plugin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/resharper-and-plugin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Version 4.0 of &lt;a href="http://www.jetbrains.com">resharper&lt;/a> offers the ability to create &lt;a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/resharper/plugins/">plugins&lt;/a>. This is very important, because you can use the basic structure of resharper to offer additional features. One of the most interesting, in my opinion, is the NHibernate plugin, I suggest you to have a try of it, another good reason to use resharper ;).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>alk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Resharper 40 goes in RC almost finished</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/resharper-40-goes-in-rc-almost-finished/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/resharper-40-goes-in-rc-almost-finished/</guid><description>&lt;p>I must admit that resharper is really the most useful plugin for visual studio I use, I’m testing the nightly build but the &lt;a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/resharper/beta/beta.html">Release Candidate is now avaliable&lt;/a>, and this means that in a short time we can have final version, Stay tuned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tags: &lt;a href="http://technorati.com/tag/Resharper">Resharper&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Argotic Rss Library for NET</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/argotic-rss-library-for-net/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/argotic-rss-library-for-net/</guid><description>&lt;p>I need to work with rss, so I wandered a little bit in the net and found &lt;a href="http://www.codeplex.com/Argotic/">Argotic&lt;/a> library. At the first glance the library is really good, but a simple thing appears to be missing (or probably I did not find in the documentation)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I need to examine a large set of feed to grab all the link, but I do not know if the feed is rss or atom or whathever else, I decided to support atom and Rss, and I created this little piece of code that use GenericSyndicationFeed to load the feed from the uri, then check the format and create the correct feed component.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The heartbeat of a project</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/the-heartbeat-of-a-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2008 01:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/the-heartbeat-of-a-project/</guid><description>&lt;p>Continuous Integration is one of the most important part of a project, it gives the heartbeat of the code, when it is green the beat is ok, when it is red something wrong is occurred.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Setting up a good CI environment can be really challenging, but setting up a primitive CC.net is a relative simple task. I realized that even with basic functions, a CI can give you a valuable asset. I’m not a guru of CC.net or CI, but I usually set up a simple CI environment with only two task&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RSS toolkit for aspnet</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/05/rss-toolkit-for-aspnet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2007 01:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2007/05/rss-toolkit-for-aspnet/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you needs to manage some RSS content in your asp.net application maybe&lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/dmitryr/archive/2006/03/26/561200.aspx">RSS Toolkit&lt;/a> is the answer to all of your problems. In &lt;a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2006/02/22/438738.aspx">this post&lt;/a> of Scott Guthrie there is also a good tutorial on the toolkit, it is worth to take a look.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alk.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>