<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NETCORE on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/netcore/</link><description>Recent content in NETCORE on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 20:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/netcore/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unable to execute NET core unit test in VS after uninstalling older sdk</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/11/unable-to-execute-net-core-unit-test-in-vs-after-uninstalling-older-sdk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/11/unable-to-execute-net-core-unit-test-in-vs-after-uninstalling-older-sdk/</guid><description>It is not uncommon to have installed many versions of.NET core framework, especially after many Visual Studio updates. Each installation consumes disk space so I’ve decided to cleanup everything leaving only major version of the framework installed in the system. Everything worked fine, except Visual Studio Test Explorer that, upon test run request, generates this error in Tests output window
[21/11/2019 6:08:03.911] ========== Discovery aborted: 0 tests found (0:00:05,5002292) ==========[21/11/2019 6:08:03.</description></item><item><title>Error when NET461 full framework references NETStandard nuget packages</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/07/error-when-net461-full-framework-references-netstandard-nuget-packages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/07/error-when-net461-full-framework-references-netstandard-nuget-packages/</guid><description>After updating MongoDb driver in a C# big project I start having a problem in a Web Project where we have this error after a deploy in test server (but we have no error in local machine of developers) &amp;gt; An assembly with the same identity ‘System.Runtime, Version=4.1.2.0, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=b03f5f7f11d50a3a’ has already been imported. Try removing one of the duplicate references.
This happens because MongoDB driver &amp;gt; 2.8 reference in the chain System.</description></item><item><title>Multitarget NetStandard for Windows and Linux</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/10/multitarget-netstandard-for-windows-and-linux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/10/multitarget-netstandard-for-windows-and-linux/</guid><description>One of the most important features of DotNetStandard is the ability to run on Linux and Mac, but if you need to use a DotNetStandard compiled library in a project that uses full.NET framework, sometimes you can have little problems. Actually you can reference a dll compiled for DotNetCore from a project that uses full Framework, but in a couple of project we experienced some trouble with some assemblies.
Thanks to multitargeting you can simply instruct DotNet compiler to produce libraries compiled against different versions of frameworks, so you can simply tell the compiler that you want both DotNetStandard 2.</description></item><item><title>NET core 20 errors installing on linux</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/08/net-core-2-0-errors-installing-on-linux/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/08/net-core-2-0-errors-installing-on-linux/</guid><description>.NET Core 2.0 is finally out, and I immediately try to install it on every machine and especially in my linux test machines. In one of my Ubuntu machine I got an installation problem, a generic error of apt-get and I was a little bit puzzled on why the installation fail.
Since in windows the most common cause of.NET Core installation error is the presence of an old package (especially the preview version), I decide to uninstall all previous installation of.</description></item></channel></rss>