<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VCS on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/vcs/</link><description>Recent content in VCS on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 07:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/vcs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Subversion 17 and the new workspace</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/10/subversion-1-7-and-the-new-workspace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/10/subversion-1-7-and-the-new-workspace/</guid><description>Subversion 1.7 has a new format of the workspace, the first important stuff is that there are not a.svn folder for each mapped folder, but it has only a single.svn folder in the root of the local mapping of the repository. This lead to a tremendous improvement in performance with very big repository. Actually doing an update from my SSD on a project that has thousands of folder is almost instantaneous.</description></item><item><title>News for TFS 11 VCS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/news-for-tfs-11-vcs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/news-for-tfs-11-vcs/</guid><description>In this post of Mr. Brian Harry some of the news regarding TFS 11 VCS are unveiled. While there is still no DVCS, there are a lot of improvements with the introduction of local workspaces.
Actually TFS Workspaces status is kept on the server, so whenever you issue a GetLatest, the server check the status of the Workspace and send you only new data. This causes sometimes behavior that surprise most developer coming from other VCS like subversion.</description></item><item><title>Idiomatic VCS usage</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/idiomatic-vcs-usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/idiomatic-vcs-usage/</guid><description>When it is time to compare two VCS there are a lot of features to be taken into account, and in my opinion one of the most important is the team is already used to some VCS?. One of the most difficult part of learning a new VCS, is avoiding to use it in the same way you use a different product, because each VCS could potentially have a different way to do the same thing.</description></item></channel></rss>