<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Silverlight on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/silverlight/</link><description>Recent content in Silverlight on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2008 06:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/silverlight/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>modify silverlight ServiceReferencesClientConfig after a build</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/modify-silverlight-servicereferencesclientconfig-after-a-build/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2008 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/modify-silverlight-servicereferencesclientconfig-after-a-build/</guid><description>&lt;p>I use NANT to automate the build process, now I face a little problem with silverlight. When you reference a service the designer of visual studio generate a ServiceReferences.ClientConfig  with configuration of the service, it contains the address of the service and it gets compiled inside the.xap file generated by compilation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I use to point to a localhost machine during debugging, but in the real environment the service maybe is in another machine, so I need to find a way to point the client to the right service inside a nant build file. Since.xap files are nothing but a zip file I try to setup an action to unzip file, modify the ServiceReferences.ClientConfig, zip the file again and the game is done….exept that this does not works. It seems that Nant task &amp;lt;unzip&amp;gt; generates error when It tries to uncompress the xap file.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Binding combobox to Enum in silverlight</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/binding-combobox-to-enum-in-silverlight/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/binding-combobox-to-enum-in-silverlight/</guid><description>&lt;p>These days I’m playing a bit with Silverlight, to realize a little piece of backoffice of an ASP.NEt classic application. We decided to give a chance to silverligth because the backoffice is used only internally and so we can make experience with a noncritical piece of software.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even If I do not adopt a MVC or &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/johngossman/archive/2005/10/08/478683.aspx">M-V-VM&lt;/a> pattern I like to create a little domain model, than expose it with a &lt;a href="http://martinfowler.com/eaaCatalog/transactionScript.html">transaction script&lt;/a> pattern, make it avaliable through a WCF service, and create interface with really no logic. Each service method return &lt;a href="http://martinfowler.com/eaaCatalog/dataTransferObject.html">DTO&lt;/a> not real domain object,  this make possible for the caller not to worry about all the crap that can exists in the domain. The silverlight interface is a simple series of control, that can be bound to a DTO, so the typical pattern is to ask service for some object, then bind them to a control, let the user play with the interface and thanks to twoway binding we can simply wait for the user to press a “Save” button or other such events to call update method from the service.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Visual studio for big web project8230 so slow</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/visual-studio-for-big-web-project-so-slow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/visual-studio-for-big-web-project-so-slow/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yesterday I moved my first steps on silverlight, I’m working on a big solution with a big Web site, and the solution build time is really increased when I add silverlight project to the solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is really frustrating because I change something in the silverlight control, then I had to at least issue a command of “build page” in the site, to make the xap file updates. This cost me about 45 seconds of waiting for….nothing, and I have a 10K RPM disk, with a 3.0 GHz Dual core CPU. This is absolutely embarrassing.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>