<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>YAML on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/yaml/</link><description>Recent content in YAML on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 05:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/yaml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Converting Existing pipeline to YAML how to avoid double builds</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/05/converting-existing-pipeline-to-yaml-how-to-avoid-double-builds/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/05/converting-existing-pipeline-to-yaml-how-to-avoid-double-builds/</guid><description>Actually YAML build is the preferred way to create Azure DevOps Build Pipeline and converting existing build is really simple thanks to the “View YAML” button that can simply convert every existing pipeline in a YAML definition.
figure 1: Converting existing Pipeline in YAML is easy with the View YAML button present in editor page.
The usual process is, start a new feature branch to test pipeline conversion to YAML, create the YAML file and a Pipeline based on it, then start testing.</description></item><item><title>How to edit a YAML Azure DevOps Pipeline</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/04/how-to-edit-a-yaml-azure-devops-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/04/how-to-edit-a-yaml-azure-devops-pipeline/</guid><description>I cannot stress you enough on how better is the experience of having builds defined in code than having build definition on the server , so I’m here to convince you to move to the new YAML build system in Azure DevOps :).
Having build definition in Code gives you many benefits, the first is that builds evolve with code branches.
If you still think that editing a YAML file is a daunting experience because you have tons of possible tasks and configuration to use, take a peek to the Azure Pipeline extension Visual Studio Code Addin, that brings intellisense for your pipeline editing in Visual Studio Code.</description></item><item><title>YAML Build in Azure DevOps</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/03/yaml-build-in-azure-devops/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/03/yaml-build-in-azure-devops/</guid><description>I’ve blogged in the past about YAML build in azure DevOps, but in that early days, that kind of build was a little bit rough and many people still preferred the old build based on visual editing in a browser. One of the main complaint was that the build was not easy to edit and there were some glitch, especially when it is time to access external services.
After months from the first version, the experience is really improved and I strongly suggest you to start trying to migrate existing build to this new system, to take advantage of having definition of build directly in the code, a practice that is more DevOps oriented and that allows you to have different build tasks for different branches.</description></item><item><title>Converting PowerShell Task in YAML</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/08/converting-powershell-task-in-yaml/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/08/converting-powershell-task-in-yaml/</guid><description>YAML Builds have many advantages over traditional build definitions, especially because YAML build definitions follows branching of code , a killer feature that is fantastic if you use GitFlow.
YAML Build definitions are stored in code, this allows them to follow branches, minimizing the need to maintain builds that should build code in different moment in time.
As an example I have a build where I have tasks to publish some Web Sites, if I had a new Web Site to publish, I can add another task in YAML build, but the build still work for older branches, especially for the master branch that represent my code in production.</description></item></channel></rss>