<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Silverlight on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/silverlight/</link><description>Recent content in Silverlight on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2008 06:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/silverlight/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>modify silverlight ServiceReferencesClientConfig after a build</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/modify-silverlight-servicereferencesclientconfig-after-a-build/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2008 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/modify-silverlight-servicereferencesclientconfig-after-a-build/</guid><description>I use NANT to automate the build process, now I face a little problem with silverlight. When you reference a service the designer of visual studio generate a ServiceReferences.ClientConfig with configuration of the service, it contains the address of the service and it gets compiled inside the.xap file generated by compilation
I use to point to a localhost machine during debugging, but in the real environment the service maybe is in another machine, so I need to find a way to point the client to the right service inside a nant build file.</description></item><item><title>Binding combobox to Enum in silverlight</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/binding-combobox-to-enum-in-silverlight/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/binding-combobox-to-enum-in-silverlight/</guid><description>These days I’m playing a bit with Silverlight, to realize a little piece of backoffice of an ASP.NEt classic application. We decided to give a chance to silverligth because the backoffice is used only internally and so we can make experience with a noncritical piece of software.
Even If I do not adopt a MVC or M-V-VM pattern I like to create a little domain model, than expose it with a transaction script pattern, make it avaliable through a WCF service, and create interface with really no logic.</description></item><item><title>Visual studio for big web project8230 so slow</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/visual-studio-for-big-web-project-so-slow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/07/visual-studio-for-big-web-project-so-slow/</guid><description>Yesterday I moved my first steps on silverlight, I’m working on a big solution with a big Web site, and the solution build time is really increased when I add silverlight project to the solution.
It is really frustrating because I change something in the silverlight control, then I had to at least issue a command of “build page” in the site, to make the xap file updates. This cost me about 45 seconds of waiting for….</description></item></channel></rss>