<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tfs on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/tfs/</link><description>Recent content in Tfs on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 10:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/tfs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Change Work Item Type in a fresh installation of Azure DevOps server</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/01/change-work-item-type-in-a-fresh-installation-of-azure-devops-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2019/01/change-work-item-type-in-a-fresh-installation-of-azure-devops-server/</guid><description>If you want to use Azure DevOps I strongly suggest you to use cloud version https://dev.azure.com, but if you really need to have it on premise, you can install Team Foundation Server, now renamed to Azure DevOps Server.
One of the most waited feature for the on-premise version is the ability to change work item Type and to move work item between project, a feature present in Azure DevOps Server, but that needs a complete disable of Reporting Services to work, as I discussed in an old Post.</description></item><item><title>TFS 2018 Update 3 is out what changes for Search</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/09/tfs-2018-update-3-is-out-what-changes-for-search/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/09/tfs-2018-update-3-is-out-what-changes-for-search/</guid><description>TFS 2018 Update 3 is finally out and in release notes there is a nice news for Search functionality, basic security now enforced through a custom plugin. Here is what you can read in release notes
Basic authorization is now enabled on the communication between the TFS and Search services to make it more secure. Any user installing or upgrading to Update 3 will need to provide a user name / password while configuring Search (and also during Search Service setup in case of remote Search Service).</description></item><item><title>Increase RAM for ElasticSearch for TFS Search</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/01/increase-ram-for-elasticsearch-for-tfs-search/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/01/increase-ram-for-elasticsearch-for-tfs-search/</guid><description>If you are experiencing slow search in TFS with the new Search functionality based on ElasticSearch a typical suggestion is to give more RAM to the machine where ES is installed. Clearly you should use HQ or other tools to really pin down the root cause but most of the time the problem is not enough RAM, or slow disks. The second cause can be easily solved moving data to an SSD disk, but giving more RAM to the machine, usually gives more space for OS File cache and can solve even the problem of slow disk.</description></item><item><title>TFS 2018 search components in different server</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/01/tfs-2018-search-components-in-different-server/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2018/01/tfs-2018-search-components-in-different-server/</guid><description>When it is time to design topology of a TFS installation, for small team the single server is usually the best choice in term of licensing (one one Windows Server license is needed) and simplicity of maintenance. Traditionally the only problem that can occur is: some component (especially the Analysis and Reporting services) starts to slow down the machine if the amount of data starts to become consistent.
Single machine TFS installation is probably the best choice for small teams.</description></item><item><title>Decide to publish artifacts on Server or Network Share at queue time</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/07/decide-to-publish-artifacts-on-server-or-network-share-at-queue-time/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/07/decide-to-publish-artifacts-on-server-or-network-share-at-queue-time/</guid><description>A build usually produces artifacts and thanks to the extreme flexibility of VSTS / TFS Build system, you have complete freedom on what to include as artifacts and where you should locate them.
Actually you have a couple of options out of the box, a network share or directly on your VSTS / TFS Server. This second option is especially interesting because you does not need a special network share and you do not have permission issue (every script or person that can access the server and have build permission can use the artifacts).</description></item><item><title>Development and Related Work missing on new UI form after upgrade to TFS 2017</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/04/development-and-related-work-missing-on-new-ui-form-after-upgrade-to-tfs-2017/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/04/development-and-related-work-missing-on-new-ui-form-after-upgrade-to-tfs-2017/</guid><description>I’ve dealt on How to enable the new work Item in TFS 2017, and you could have noticed some differences from Visual Studio Team Service Work Item layout, or even with new Team Projects created after the upgrade. In Figure 1 you can see in the left the detail of a PBI on a Team Project that exists before the upgrade to TFS 2017, in the right the PBI on a Team Project created after the upgrade.</description></item><item><title>Action required for a VSTS Extension</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/03/action-required-for-a-vsts-extension/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/03/action-required-for-a-vsts-extension/</guid><description>It could happen that you received an Email from VSTS telling you that one of the extension needs some action.
Figure 1: An email telling you that an extension needs action to be updated.
If you go to your account and check the extension page, you find a situation like this one.
Figure 2: Extension is listed in the “action required” section
You could be puzzled, because there is warning icon, but no indication on what you need to do to solve the situation, nor what the problem is.</description></item><item><title>One reason to upgrade to TFS 2017 Code search</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/01/one-reason-to-upgrade-to-tfs-2017-code-search/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/01/one-reason-to-upgrade-to-tfs-2017-code-search/</guid><description>I always suggest teams to use VSTS instead of on-premise TFS. The main reason is avoiding any issue with administration or upgrades. In these years, one of the main risk of having TFS on-premise is not planning for upgrade and keeping the first version installed for years. As a result, it is not uncommon to have teams that still uses TFS 2013 even if version 2017 is out.
For small teams usually there is not a dedicated TFS administrator; in this situation is it strongly advisable not to skip one entire major upgrade, to minimize the risk of a big bang upgrade.</description></item><item><title>Enable new Work Item Form in TFS '15'</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/11/enable-new-work-item-form-in-tfs-15/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/11/enable-new-work-item-form-in-tfs-15/</guid><description>If you installed TFS 15 Preview, one of the news you expected to see is the new Work Item Layout (already available in VSTS). You could get disappointed that actually your existing Work Items still are shown with the old interface, as you can see in Figure 1
Figure 1: After upgrade TFS still shows the old Work Item Form
The new Work Item Form is installed with an opt-in method so it is disabled by default.</description></item><item><title>Re-indexing source in TFS '15' preview</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/10/re-indexing-source-in-tfs-15-preview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/10/re-indexing-source-in-tfs-15-preview/</guid><description>If you installed TFS “15” preview you should give a try to code search, because it is surely one of the coolest feature introduced in this new release.
If for some reason the indexing went wrong, or code is not indexed, you can try reindexing using some powershell scripts that are described in this post.
Happy TFS.</description></item><item><title>Use different Excel TFS VSTS Addin at the same time</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/09/use-different-excel-tfs-vsts-addin-at-the-same-time/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/09/use-different-excel-tfs-vsts-addin-at-the-same-time/</guid><description>If you are a consultant, it is quite common that you work with various version of TFS Server at the same time. I have my personal account on VSTS, always updated to the latest version, but I have also customer that still uses TFS 2012 or TFS 2010.
Microsoft test newer version of TFS against lots of applications to be sure that newer versions of TFS do not break usage of existing tools.</description></item><item><title>Scale out deployment error when migrating Reporting Services</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/07/scale-out-deployment-error-when-migrating-reporting-services/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/07/scale-out-deployment-error-when-migrating-reporting-services/</guid><description>Part of moving your TFS Server on new hardware, or creating a Pre-Production environment is restoring Reporting Server database. Since Datatbase are encrypted, if you simply restore the database then configure Reporting Services on new machine to use restored database, this operation will fail, because the new server cannot read encrypted data.
Restoring Reporting Services database into a new instance involves some manual steps, especially you need to backup / restore encryption keys from your old server to the new one.</description></item><item><title>Isolate your TFS Pre-Production environment for maximum security</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/07/isolate-your-tfs-pre-production-environment-for-maximum-security/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/07/isolate-your-tfs-pre-production-environment-for-maximum-security/</guid><description>In previous post I’ve explained how to create a clone of your TFS Production environment thanks to the new TFS “15” wizard. With this post I want to share you a simple solution I have in my Bags of Tricks to avoid your TFS Cloned environment to interfere with production environment.
The problem In my environment I have all machines in network 10.0.0.0/24, my TFS has address 10.0.0.116 and Primary Domain Controller is 10.</description></item><item><title>Impressions on installing TFS '15' Preview</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/07/impressions-on-installing-tfs-15-preview/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/07/impressions-on-installing-tfs-15-preview/</guid><description>Microsoft released a preview of the new version of Team Foundation Server, codename TFS “15” and as usual I immediately downloaded and installed on some of my test server. I’m not going to show you full steps of installation or upgrade, because installing TFS is now a Next/Next/Next experience, but I want to highlight a couple of really interesting aspect of the new installer.
Support to Pre-Production environment When it is time to upgrade your TFS production server, it is always a good practice to perform the upgrade in a pre-production environment, to avoid having surprises upgrading production instance.</description></item><item><title>Create a release in TFS 2015 VSTS Release Management</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/06/create-a-release-in-tfs-2015-vsts-release-management/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/06/create-a-release-in-tfs-2015-vsts-release-management/</guid><description>This is the end of the journey of the last serie of posts. I’m now at the situation where I have a build that produces a single zip file with everything I need to deploy the software and a bunch of PowerShell scripts that relase the software using that zip as a source artifact.
Now it is time to automate the process with Release Management. I want to use RM because the process is automated on a chain of environments, but also I have traceability, auditing, and verification of the release procedures.</description></item><item><title>Execute powershell code during a build in TFS 2015 Update 2</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/04/execute-powershell-code-during-a-build-in-tfs-2015-update-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/04/execute-powershell-code-during-a-build-in-tfs-2015-update-2/</guid><description>In TFS 2015 build system, running a PowerShell script stored in source code is simple because there is a dedicated action to accomplish this task, but if you want to run a PowerShell script that is not in source control, you have no option out of the Box.
Thanks to Update 2, you have now the ability to use the extensions you can find on Visual Studio Marketplace directly in your on-premise TFS installation.</description></item><item><title>Add Reporting to an existing Team Project</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/04/add-reporting-to-am-existing-team-project/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/04/add-reporting-to-am-existing-team-project/</guid><description>In previous post I demonstrated how you can create a Team Project from Web Interface thanks to TFS 2015 Update 2. The only drawback of this approach is that no Sharepoint Site and no Reporting Services portal are created.
While SharePoint integration is now an uncommon requirement, reporting services are still used. After my new Team Project (namedTest Project 2 ) was created from web interface, I verified that nothing gets created in my Reporting Services instance.</description></item><item><title>TFS 2015 Update 2 is released</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/04/tfs-2015-update-2-is-released/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/04/tfs-2015-update-2-is-released/</guid><description>You can find all the details directly in Visual Studio Site, but I want to emphasize that TFS and VS Updates are much more than Service Packs , because they also intrdoduce a lot of new features. Here is a list of my personal favorites features of TFS Update 2
Introduction of new Release Management System New release management system is completely Web and does not require separate client to download, but this is not the only advantage.</description></item><item><title>Invalidate cache of TFS after a Server Move</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/01/invalidate-cache-of-tfs-after-a-server-move/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/01/invalidate-cache-of-tfs-after-a-server-move/</guid><description>If you move your TFS server in a new hardware be sure to follow the instructions in MSDN: Move or clone Team Foundation Server (hardware move).
There are many reason why you want to move TFS to a different hardware, probably you want to use a new powerful hardware and you have not virtualized TFS, or you need to upgrade TFS and you need to move Sql to a new hardware with a more recent version of SQL.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshoot Error TF14044 in build vNext for TFS2015</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/01/troubleshoot-error-tf14044-in-build-vnext-for-tfs2015/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/01/troubleshoot-error-tf14044-in-build-vnext-for-tfs2015/</guid><description>I upgraded a TFS2012 to TFS2015 Update 1 at a customer site and one of the reason why the customer want to upgrade is the new build system introduced in TFS 2015. Sadly enough, after the upgrade we created a simple build but it failed returning a permission error.
TF14044: Access Denied: User Project Collection Build Service (TEAM FOUNDATION) needs the CreateWorkspace global permission(s).
We were really puzzled, because the user used to run the build (TFSBuild) was correctly set into the Project Collection Build Service account, and that group has all the permissions to create a workspace.</description></item><item><title>Use DNS for your TFS installation</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/01/use-dns-for-your-tfs-installation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/01/use-dns-for-your-tfs-installation/</guid><description>When installing TFS one of the most important and often most forgotten step is using DNS to give TFS Friendly names. The procedure is described in this old post by Ed Blankenship and details all the operations you need to do to use friendly DNS entries for all of machines included in a standard TFS Installation.
Using a DNS friendly name bring a lot of advantages , but essentially it is necessary to mitigate the work needed if you need to migrate TFS to a new hardware / machine.</description></item><item><title>Create a safe clone of your TFS environment</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/08/create-a-safe-clone-of-your-tfs-environment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/08/create-a-safe-clone-of-your-tfs-environment/</guid><description>ChangeServerId to avoid confusion of client tools Around the web there are a lot of resources about how to create a clone of your TFS environment for testing purpose. The most important step was always running the TfsCongfig ChangeServerId Command as described in the Move Team Foundation Server from your hardware configuration to another.
With the new wave of guidance for TFS 2015, a new interesting article cames out on how to do a Dry Run in a pre-production environment.</description></item><item><title>Work Item query by category</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/07/work-item-query-by-category/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 21:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/07/work-item-query-by-category/</guid><description>This is a really old functionality of TFS, but it turns out that sometimes some people missed it. When you create a query, you can add a condition on Work Item Type.
Figure 1: Add condition to Work Item Type
As you can see, you can require the Work Item Type to be equal to specific value, and the UI renders a nice combo box with all permitted values to help the user choose right value.</description></item><item><title>Managing tags with Tag Admin for VS 2013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/07/managing-tags-with-tag-admin-for-vs-2013/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/07/managing-tags-with-tag-admin-for-vs-2013/</guid><description>Tags management in Team Foundation Server is a really good way to add custom information to Work Items without the need to customize process template. The downside of this approach, is that every person is able to add whatever tag to work items with the risk of misspelling and duplication.
As an example if the team is doing T-Shirt sizing for User Stories, we can have people using tag S to identify a Small Story, then people decides to change to SIZE_S to better indicate the purpose of the tag.</description></item><item><title>Limit maximum memory of SQL Server in TFS environment</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/05/limit-maximum-memory-of-sql-server-in-tfs-environment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/05/limit-maximum-memory-of-sql-server-in-tfs-environment/</guid><description>If you are a small shop using on-premise TFS, probably you’ll have a single machine installation for Data and App tier for your TFS. While installing a Build server on App or Data tier is highly discouraged, using a single machine for Data and App tier is a viable solution for small and medium team , and with virtualization is quite easy to move machine to a more powerful hardware or give it more RAM if the usage or TFS increase performances starts to degrade.</description></item><item><title>Tfs2015 Build agent error Access denied xxxxxyyyyy needs Listen permissions for pool zzzzz to perform the action</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/05/tfs2015-build-agent-error-access-denied-xxxxxyyyyy-needs-listen-permissions-for-pool-zzzzz-to-perform-the-action/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/05/tfs2015-build-agent-error-access-denied-xxxxxyyyyy-needs-listen-permissions-for-pool-zzzzz-to-perform-the-action/</guid><description>Tfs 2015 introduces a completely new and redesigned build system and one of the most important change is new lightweight agent system. Instead of installing TFS and then configure Build, to create a new agent you only need to download a zip file, uncompress and launch a PowerShell script. Another great advantage is the ability to run the agent as a service, or running it interactively in a simple console application.</description></item><item><title>User added to Team Project have no permission after upgrade from TFS2010 to TFS2013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/02/user-added-to-team-project-have-no-permission-after-upgrade-from-tfs2010-to-tfs2013/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/02/user-added-to-team-project-have-no-permission-after-upgrade-from-tfs2010-to-tfs2013/</guid><description>I’ve performed an upgrade from TFS2010 to TFS2013 at a customer site last week. The upgrade consisted in moving to a different machine and from a Workstation to an Active Directory Domain. The operation was simple, because the customer uses only Source Control and they want to spent minimal time in the operation, so we decided for this strategy
Stop TFS in the old machine Backup and restore db in the new machine Upgrade and verify that everything works correctly They do not care about user remapping, or reporting services or other stuff, they just want to do a quick migration to new version to use local workspaces new feature (introduced with TFS 2012).</description></item><item><title>Error TF53001 The database operation was canceled by an administrator</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/02/error-tf53001-the-database-operation-was-canceled-by-an-administrator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/02/error-tf53001-the-database-operation-was-canceled-by-an-administrator/</guid><description>A customer updated his TFS 2010 to 2013 in a new machine running Windows Server 2012 R2 and Sql Server 2014. Everything went fine, until after few days they started having an error whenever he tried to do a GetLatest or a Check-in or Check-out operation. Error TF53001: The database operation was canceled by an administrator Actually this error is not really informative, so I asked them to verify Event Viewer on the server (an operation you should always do whenever you have wrong behavior of your TFS).</description></item><item><title>Build controller and agent ready but icon shows stopped</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/10/build-controller-and-agent-ready-but-icon-shows-stopped/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/10/build-controller-and-agent-ready-but-icon-shows-stopped/</guid><description>Today I encountered a strange error during the configuration of a Build Controller in TFS. We installed and configured the first Build Controller for a TFS Instance, everything went good, but both controllers and agent are marked with stopped icon, even if status is “ready”
Figure 1: Controller and agents are marked as stopped even if they are in Ready State
I immediately looked into Event Viewer, but absolutely no clue of what is happening.</description></item><item><title>Download code of a specific changeset in TFVC</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/08/download-code-of-a-specific-changeset-in-tfvc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/08/download-code-of-a-specific-changeset-in-tfvc/</guid><description>Some time ago a friend asked me the easiest way to get code from a specific folder and a specific version in TFVC. The goal is avoiding using Get Specific Version because he do not want to overwrite the Workspace folder he is using, he want also to avoid creating another workspace only to do a one-shot get of a folder.
It turns out that the easiest way to accomplish this task is from Web Interface , because it has the capability of browsing and downloading code as zip.</description></item><item><title>Your TFS keeps asking you for credentials even with Active Directory</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/07/your-tfs-keeps-asking-you-for-credentials-even-with-active-directory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/07/your-tfs-keeps-asking-you-for-credentials-even-with-active-directory/</guid><description>Sometimes, even if you are logged in as a domain user that has all the rights to access TFS, when you navigate to TFS you are prompted for password every time. You simply re-enter your credentials and you access TFS, but each time you close and reopen the browser you need to manually reenter credentials. This problem happens because the browser does not understand that the url of TFS belongs to Intranet Sites and it does not send AD credentials for authenticating.</description></item><item><title>error MSB3147 Could not find required file 8216setupbin8217 in</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/05/error-msb3147-could-not-find-required-file-setup-bin-in/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/05/error-msb3147-could-not-find-required-file-setup-bin-in/</guid><description>I got this error from a powershell script when I call MsBuild.exe to publish a ClickOnce project in a TFS Build, the exact error is.
error MSB3147: Could not find required file ‘setup.bin’ in …
This is not the first time I encounter this error and it is usually caused by missing.NET SDK. The strange fact is that I have both VS 2013 and Windows SDK already installed in the machine hosting the build agent.</description></item><item><title>Keep your Team Foundation Server upgraded to latest version</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/05/keep-your-team-foundation-server-upgraded-to-latest-version/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/05/keep-your-team-foundation-server-upgraded-to-latest-version/</guid><description>When it is time to maintain Team Foundation Server in small companies the major risk is “fear of upgrade”. In a small shops usually there is no dedicated resource to maintain TFS installation , usually you install the first time, schedule backup and everything is done. In small company maintenance is also simple, you usually have not big database and speed is not a problem with current hardware.
Some people also fear the upgrade, because they think it is a complicated process, they are not sure if they are able to restore the old version if the upgrade went wrong, and so on.</description></item><item><title>Upgrading Release Management to Update 1</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/03/upgrading-release-management-to-update-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/03/upgrading-release-management-to-update-1/</guid><description>If you want to upgrade Release Management for TFS 2013 to Update 1 you surely noticed that there is no Update 1 upgrade package, but you should first uninstall the old version of Release Management and the install again the version with Update 1.
While this does not delete any previous settings and simply upgrade the database to the new structure, it is possible that after upgrading when you try to connect with the Release Management Client you get and error telling you that the Release Management Server is not working.</description></item><item><title>Git as a bridge between Subversion and TFS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/01/git-as-a-bridge-between-subversion-and-tfs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/01/git-as-a-bridge-between-subversion-and-tfs/</guid><description>This is the scenario: Nablasoft company uses TFS with standard TFVC (TFS Version Control System) and needs to assign some of the work to some external Company (lets call it Acme), as an example developing for Android or iOs. The simplest solution is giving Acme developers access to TFS server, but then Nablasoft should pay the CAL for Acme developers, moreover, Acme uses subversion and they do not want to use another VCS unless it is strictly necessary.</description></item><item><title>LightWeight Charting in TFS 2013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/09/lightweight-charting-in-tfs-2013/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/09/lightweight-charting-in-tfs-2013/</guid><description>One of the most interesting aspect of TFS is the great ability to give you all the statistics you need about your project thanks to the integration with SQL Analysis Services. The ability to do complex report based on TFS Cube is really exceptional, but it somewhat complicated for small teams , that needs much more simpler data.
The solution has always been loading the result of a certain query in Excel and then create some Excel Chart to have a visual representation of Query Result Data.</description></item><item><title>Team Foundation Server usage in Microsoft</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/08/team-foundation-server-usage-in-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 04:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/08/team-foundation-server-usage-in-microsoft/</guid><description>In this post you can read about some numbers of TFS usage by Microsoft itself. While the number are impressive, I’m really interested in trends for various numbers , you can read from the first table. Microsoft is a really big company and it is really interesting to see where they are investing time in their projects.
While the increase in Source Code files was 3%, the Test Cases had a massive increase of 24%.</description></item><item><title>Aggregate Completed and Estimated Work in Team Foundation Server User Stories using Excel</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/07/aggregate-completed-and-estimated-work-in-team-foundation-server-user-stories-using-excel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/07/aggregate-completed-and-estimated-work-in-team-foundation-server-user-stories-using-excel/</guid><description>If you use the Agile process template, you have three columns related to planning and tracking task duration, they are called:
Original Estimate Completed Work Remaining Work The only problem is that TFS only aggregates the Remaining Work in the agile boards , as you can see in Figure 1 :
Figure 1: Board with Original Estimate and Completed Work columns visible
There is a Server Side plugin called TFS Aggregator available in Codeplex that can mitigate this issue, but using a Server Side plugin could not be the optimal solution.</description></item><item><title>Manage Symbol server on Azure or on-premise VM and TF Service</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/07/manage-symbol-server-on-azure-or-on-premise-vm-and-tf-service/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/07/manage-symbol-server-on-azure-or-on-premise-vm-and-tf-service/</guid><description>One of the coolest capabilities of Team Foundation Server Build is the ability to automatically manage a symbol server. Suppose this scenario: you have a library and you want to distribute to all people in your organization, with the ability to being able to debug code in the dll and to identify the code that build each version of this dll. If you have TF Service you can use a VM in azure, but the overall process is really similar if you want to have a build on-premise.</description></item><item><title>TFSRestoreexe database restored with strange suffix</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/07/tfsrestore-exe-database-restored-with-strange-suffix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/07/tfsrestore-exe-database-restored-with-strange-suffix/</guid><description>This problem happens if you mix Team Foundation Server backup tools, the symptom is: you launch TfsRestore.exe and point to a local folder where a TFS backup is located, and when the database are restored they have strange suffix.
Figure 1: Strange suffix in database names after a restore with TfsRestore.exe
This happens when you use TfsRestore.exe to restore a backup taken with the Tfs Backup Scheduled Backup. Basically you have two distinct way to backup your TFS: the first one is using the TfsBackup.</description></item><item><title>Windows 81 preview is available how can I Build with TFS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/windows-8-1-preview-is-available-how-can-i-build-with-tfs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 21:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/windows-8-1-preview-is-available-how-can-i-build-with-tfs/</guid><description>Now that Windows 8.1 preview is available, people start to think how they could compile W8.1 solutions with TFS. If you use TF Service you need only to enable a new Build Controller in preview, that is enabled to build 8.1 solutions.
Figure 1: Enable the Windows 8.1 Preview Build controller on your TF Service account to build Windows 8.1 applications
It is simple and easy. Now you should only assign the right controller when creating build definition.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Click Once application on Azure Blob Container with TFS Build</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/04/deploy-click-once-application-on-azure-blob-container-with-tfs-build/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/04/deploy-click-once-application-on-azure-blob-container-with-tfs-build/</guid><description>Windows Azure Web sites has a lot of options to automatically deploy web sites, but if you have desktop application deployed with click-once you have nothing out of the box to do continuous deployment in Windows Azure. Lets see how solve this problem.
Deploying on Windows Azure Blob Storage To deploy Click Once applications on Windows azure, the simplest solution is using a Blob Container. All you need to do is creating new public Blob Container and copy inside the blob the result of a Click Once publication.</description></item><item><title>Change user of a workspace in TFS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/03/change-user-of-a-workspace-in-tfs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/03/change-user-of-a-workspace-in-tfs/</guid><description>Suppose you have a workspace made with a certain user and you want to move it to a different user. One of the reason could be, you started working with an account then your account changes for various reason, so you need to migrate all workspaces from your old user to another user. This can be accomplished by command line tool tf.exe
tf workspaces /updateUserName:OldUserName /s:sserverurl
this should be done with your new account, and will assign all workspaces from old account to current account.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio Tools for Git a primer</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/03/visual-studio-tools-for-git-a-primer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/03/visual-studio-tools-for-git-a-primer/</guid><description>If you installed Update 2 CTP 4 (now it has go-live and supports upgrade to RTM) you should also install the Visual Studio Tools for Git that permits to work with Git repository directly from a Team Explorer extension. You can work with GitHub or whatever Git hosting you like and surely you can work with TF Service Git based Team Project. Once you have a Team Project based on Git you can simply to to the Source tab, and grab the url of the repository.</description></item><item><title>Unable to build on TFS with a project managed with Nuget and automatic restore</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/03/unable-to-build-on-tfs-with-a-project-managed-with-nuget-and-automatic-restore/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/03/unable-to-build-on-tfs-with-a-project-managed-with-nuget-and-automatic-restore/</guid><description>To reduce the size of the repository and to easy dependencies management, nuget is a good solution, and when is time to create a build in TFS you can simply Enable Nuget Package Restore and let the build machine download the dependency for you. This works perfectly even on TF Service (tfs.visualstudio.com) because the Elastic Build is configured to restore packages during build. This is really cool, until your build start to fail for missing references.</description></item><item><title>TFS Api to associate work item with check-in using comment tags</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/02/tfs-api-to-associate-work-item-with-check-in-using-comment-tags/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/02/tfs-api-to-associate-work-item-with-check-in-using-comment-tags/</guid><description>In my post “Associate Work Items to check-in in a TF Service Git Enabled repository” I explained how simple is to associate a commit in git to a Work Item simply inserting an hashtag followed by the id of the work item. Some of my friend and colleagues told me that it would be nice to have such kind of integration even in standard TFS VCS. This feature can be extremely useful for people not using Visual Studio, or people that are lovers of command line (TFS has the tf.</description></item><item><title>Remove git-tf tracked branch after a move from standard TF Service project to Git enabled project</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/02/remove-git-tf-tracked-branch-after-a-move-from-standard-tf-service-project-to-git-enabled-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 21:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/02/remove-git-tf-tracked-branch-after-a-move-from-standard-tf-service-project-to-git-enabled-project/</guid><description>In a previous post called “Move a TFService source contorl to TF Service Git based Team Project” I explained how to simple move sources from a standard TF Service project to another one based on Git. Now after a push if I issue a log I got this.
Figure 1: Origin_tfs/tfs branch in my log?
It seems that there is a remote branch called origin_tfs/tfs but it does not get listed in the list of remote branches from the Web Ui, this because that branch was related to git-tf operations.</description></item><item><title>Associate Work Items to check-in in a TF Service Git enabled repository</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/01/associate-work-items-to-check-in-in-a-tf-service-git-enabled-repository/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/01/associate-work-items-to-check-in-in-a-tf-service-git-enabled-repository/</guid><description>Even if we are still in preview, Git support in TF Service already has some nice integration between git and all the rest of the world of TFS. As an example suppose you have a Work Item you are working to.
Figure 1: Simple Work Item in web interface
Now suppose you want to associate a local commit to this Work Item , all you need to do is inserting hashtag followed by the id of the Work Item in the comment of the commit , es #437.</description></item><item><title>Move a TFService source control to TF Service Git based Team Project</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/01/move-a-tfservice-source-control-to-tf-service-git-based-team-project/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/01/move-a-tfservice-source-control-to-tf-service-git-based-team-project/</guid><description>Now that with Update 2 we have Git support on TF Service a standard question arise: “how can I move all source from a TF Service standard project to a TF Service Git based Team Project?” The answer is quite simple
First of all you need to install and Configure Git-Tf, an addin that permits to clone a TFS source control in a local Git repository, this is needed to have a full local clone of the source project you want to migrate.</description></item><item><title>Team Foundation Server support for Git is now live</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/01/team-foundation-server-support-for-git-is-now-live/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/01/team-foundation-server-support-for-git-is-now-live/</guid><description>You can read everything on the Visual Studio Alm Blog: Getting Started With Git in Visual Studio and TFS, but the great news is that TF Service is supporting Git as source control system for TFS Team Projects. Now that TF Service suports git, clearly we have a Visual Studio 2012 CTP addin called “visual Studio Tools for Git” that brings support for git inside Visual Studio, and it works not only with TF Service but with every git hosting like GitHub.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links- Week 42013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/01/visual-studio-alm-links-week-42013/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2013 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/01/visual-studio-alm-links-week-42013/</guid><description>Other enhancements in Microsoft Test Manager in Update 1 Add additional States onto the Agile Task Board in TFS2012 How to enable the Backlog view in TFS 2012 web access Team Foundation Server Vs. Team Foundation Service Team Foundation Service updates – January 21 Bringing Odata to Team Foundation Service Stand Alone installer for TFS Object model Visualize code with Visual Studio 2012 Code Map Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links-Week 32013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/01/visual-studio-alm-linksweek-22013/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2013 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/01/visual-studio-alm-linksweek-22013/</guid><description>OData Service for Team Foundation Server v2 New Build of Git-TF required for use with Team foundation Service TFS Task board Enahancer – Version 0.6 released Renaming your Team Foundation Service Account Skype and the new Team Explorer Modern Lifecycle on the Cloud OS Gian Maria.</description></item><item><title>Collaboration providers for Team Foundation Server</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/01/collaboration-providers-for-team-foundation-server/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/01/collaboration-providers-for-team-foundation-server/</guid><description>I want to signal you this project on codeplex (http://tfscollab.codeplex.com/) that contains some provider to enable collaboration with Team foundation Server power tools.
I’m expecially a fan of the Skype integration (http://blogs.msdn.com/b/bharry/archive/2013/01/14/skype-and-the-new-team-explorer.aspx) and if you use skype and TFS I strongly suggest you to give a look at that project.
Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links wees 512012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/12/visual-studio-alm-links-wees-512012/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/12/visual-studio-alm-links-wees-512012/</guid><description>Visual Studio 2012 and Oracle Development environment Sidekicks available for TFS 2012 TFS 2012 Management Pack available Team Explorer Everywhere Update 1 Troubleshooting tips for Cross Browser testing in Coded UI Tests. Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM Links week 502012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/12/visual-studio-alm-links-week-502012/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/12/visual-studio-alm-links-week-502012/</guid><description>Tfs2012: Monitoring Management Pack Code Coverage in Microsoft Test Manager – Deep Dive Gian Maria.</description></item><item><title>The build process failed validation Details</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/11/the-build-process-failed-validation-details/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/11/the-build-process-failed-validation-details/</guid><description>When it is time to customize TFS build you need to deal with Workflow Foundation, and you need to double check warning in the workflow if you want to have a successful build. As an example after a configuration of a new process template I got this during build run
The build process failed validation. Details: Validation Error: The private implementation of activity ‘1: DynamicActivity’ has the following validation error: Value for a required activity argument ‘Workspace’ was not supplied.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM links 392012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/visual-studio-alm-link-392012/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/visual-studio-alm-link-392012/</guid><description>Tfs 2012 Power Tools Are now available Team Foundation Task Board Enhancer: More features Team Foundation Service Updates 9/17 Virtual Labs in the modern application lifecycle Configuring TFS so your task are estimated in story points Testing in the modern application lifecycle Gian Maria.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM links week 372012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/visual-studio-alm-links-week-372012/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/visual-studio-alm-links-week-372012/</guid><description>Requirement management in the modern application lifecycle. Rangers Flash – August 2012 Where is the Test Toolbar … couldn’t find it anywhere Sam and Neno’s VS 2012 Book available at Launch Visual Studio Express 2012 for Windows Desktop is here Customizable Process Guidance for VS ALM 2012 iOS, iPhone and iPad storyboarding Enjoy.
Alk.</description></item><item><title>Ask to TFS how good was task estimation</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/ask-to-tfs-how-good-was-task-estimation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/ask-to-tfs-how-good-was-task-estimation/</guid><description>One of the information requested by Project Managers is knowing how good was task estimation in the past , and thanks to TFS gathering this data is really simple. If you look at the sample data in Brian Keller’s virtual machine for Project Tailspin Toys you have three field related to estimation of task, as visible in Figure 1.
Figure 1: The three field of MSF For Agile that are used to track estimation and work done on task</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio ALM links week 362012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/visual-studio-alm-links-week-362012/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/visual-studio-alm-links-week-362012/</guid><description>Remote UAC with Standard Environment and Workgroup Machines Convert VB.NET to C# from Visual Studio 2012 Team Foundation TaskBoard: Auto Refresh ALM Rangers Demo Factory Team release their first demo nuggets!!!! Visual studio 2012 cookbook ALM Rangers – ALM Dogfooding and the ANGST Factor Alk.</description></item><item><title>Visual studio ALM links week 342012</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/visual-studio-alm-links-week-342012/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/08/visual-studio-alm-links-week-342012/</guid><description>Tailor-made Visual Studio 2012 installations (aka unattended, the new way) Announcing git-tf: Combining the local repository of Git with the integrated ALM of TFS (interview on channel9) 2012 ALM Catalyst Double Feature: Test Manager and IntelliTrace and Test Impact Analysis Introducing an Integrated Work Item Field Reference for Visual Studio ALM and TFS Where are my backlog management and sprint planning features in TFS 2012? Getting Typemock Isolator running within a TFS 2012 build – part 2 Few tips on implementing a Coded UI Test Plugin Extension Gian Maria</description></item><item><title>Work Item Only View in TFS 11</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/04/work-item-only-view-in-tfs-11/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/04/work-item-only-view-in-tfs-11/</guid><description>What is WIOV in TFS 2010 TFS 2010 contains a special Group called the Work Item Only View Users, used to identify special users users that can only submit bugs and modify bugs submitted by them. The reason behind this special group is to allow your customer to directly add bug into your TFS without giving them full access to the system, but the main reason to use WIOV is that such users do not need a CAL to access TFS.</description></item><item><title>Installing on-premise component against TFS Service TFS On Azure</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/04/installing-on-premise-component-against-tfs-service-tfs-on-azure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/04/installing-on-premise-component-against-tfs-service-tfs-on-azure/</guid><description>Tfs on azure is a a perfectly valid solution to have your TFS hosted by Microsoft , no worries about upgrading, maintaining, backup and most important, it is available from every computer that has an internet connection. This last factor can be really interesting for companies where people sometimes works from home, or from an hotel during transfers because the only solution with an On-Premise server is exposing the server as Https, or using a VPN, but with TFS on Azure all that you need is a simple internet connection.</description></item><item><title>Upgrade TFS2010 to TFS11 with Detach and Attach</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/upgrade-tfs2010-to-tfs11-with-detach-and-attach/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/upgrade-tfs2010-to-tfs11-with-detach-and-attach/</guid><description>One of the simplest way to upgrade with minimum risk a Project Collection from TFS 2010 to TFS11 Beta is using the detach/attach feature of TFS, introduced with version 2010. Basically all you need to do is Detach the project collection from the old TFS 2010 server and reattach to a brand new TFS11 server, you can read about the whole procedure in an old post that explain how to Move a Team Project Collection from one server to another one.</description></item><item><title>List of interesting open source project for TFS hosted on Codeplex</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/codeplex-project-for-tfs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2012 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/codeplex-project-for-tfs/</guid><description>Some times ago I blogged a series of links of useful tools for TFS. Today I want to give you a series of Codeplex Project of useful tools. These tools are not only useful to use, but they are invaluable example of using TFS API, so they deserves a special list of their own. It is not a comprehensive list, but it contains some of the most interesting project that you can find on Codeplex.</description></item><item><title>TFS 11 and Kanban</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/tfs-11-and-kanban/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/tfs-11-and-kanban/</guid><description>Visual studio ALM Rangers just published a good pratical guide for using kanban on TFS 11, I suggest you to have a look at the guide, because is really interesting.
The link is here.</description></item><item><title>Interesting links for Visual Studio 11 and TFS 11</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/interesting-links-for-visual-studio-11-and-tfs-11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/interesting-links-for-visual-studio-11-and-tfs-11/</guid><description>Yesterday Microsoft released a really huge wave of tools as well as the consumer preview of the upcoming operating system Windows 8. For Developers there are a lots of news to learn, especially on the new version of Visual Studio called VS11 , so I decided to create a blog post where I’ll try to list all interesting links related to VS11 Beta. I’ll try to keep this post updated</description></item><item><title>Add existing project to TFS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/01/add-existing-project-to-tfs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/01/add-existing-project-to-tfs/</guid><description>This is a super basic and easy question, but I found quite often people asking me how to add an existing project to a TFS Team Project. It turns out that there are more than one way of doing this, but I usually suggests this simple path that is quite simple and is understandable from people that comes from the subversion world.
First of all be sure that you have a valid workspace in your computer that maps the folder in the Team Project where you want to put your existing project and issue a GetLatest.</description></item><item><title>Search in Tfs Work Items never was so easy</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/12/search-in-tfs-work-items-never-was-so-easy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/12/search-in-tfs-work-items-never-was-so-easy/</guid><description>The search box functionality was introduced with the August release, but I see that some people still does not know it. This question arose during a talk about how to handle the lifecycle of a bug, and when it was time to deal with the “avoid duplication” issue, people told me that they want a simple way to search work item by text, because this is the fastest way to verify if a bug has some duplicate.</description></item><item><title>Team Foundation Server power tools December release</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/12/team-foundation-server-power-tools-december-release/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/12/team-foundation-server-power-tools-december-release/</guid><description>You can read all the details Here, but basically it is a release mainly focused for “non visual studio developers”. This new release has a MSSCCI provider for 64 bit, and a version of Power Tools for eclipse, and it is available from the Eclipse update site.
For those ones interested in knowing the news for VS Power Tools, basically it add the capability to search for number in the “Work Item Search Box” and a bunch of rules in the Best Practice Analyzer to identify issues with Project Server interaction, so, for Visual Studio Users it is a minor release, and probably the last for Visual Studio 2010, as stated by Brian</description></item><item><title>Avoid expiring of Brian Keller VS2010 virtual machine</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/11/avoid-expiring-of-brian-keller-vs2010-virtual-machine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/11/avoid-expiring-of-brian-keller-vs2010-virtual-machine/</guid><description>Brian Keller always does a great work releasing a Demo Machine with all the goodness of VS2010 and TFS2010, really useful for making demo and courses. The only drawback is that this machine expires after 6 months, and if you did some customization on it, or prepared some customized hands-on-lab, you usually need to do everything again with the new machine. (Brian release a new machine updated with the latest tool some days before the expiration of the old machine).</description></item><item><title>Power point storyboarding and Feedback Tool</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/10/power-point-storyboarding-and-feedback-tool/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/10/power-point-storyboarding-and-feedback-tool/</guid><description>In TFS 11 there are some cool new tools to easy the communication with customers, since the main reason for building software is to satisfy customers and users, at least in agile world, these kind of tools are really valuable in the process. A key point is being able to communicate easily with Stakeholders and have rapid feedback during each sprint to avoid the risk of “implementing the wrong stuff”.</description></item><item><title>Local workspaces</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/local-workspaces/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2011 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/local-workspaces/</guid><description>In Tfs11 one of the most important change in source control system is the introduction of the “local workspaces”. A Workspace is a mapping between the server source control system and a local folder of a computer and until Tfs11 its state is managed by the server. One advantage of this approach is: when I ask for a “Get Latest”, the server knows the status of my workspace and can send me only the files that are changed.</description></item><item><title>Convert Brian Keller dev11 Virtual Machine to vmWare</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/convert-brian-keller-dev11-virtual-machine-to-vmware/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2011 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/convert-brian-keller-dev11-virtual-machine-to-vmware/</guid><description>The Brian Keller’s Virtual Machine with all the goodness of dev11 developer preview is an Hyper-V one, so if you have a windows 7 environment (like me) you cannot use it. A possible solution is using a Virtual Disk converter like the Starwind one (http://www.starwindsoftware.com/download-starwind-converter) that permits you to convert a.VHD hyper-v virtual disk to a standard VmWare disk, then you can create a new VmWare virtual machine, use the converted disk and everything should be ok.</description></item><item><title>Deep dive in Process templatersquos states and transitions</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/deep-dive-in-process-templates-states-and-transitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/deep-dive-in-process-templates-states-and-transitions/</guid><description>1 – Customize Tfs Process Template
2 – Basic of TFS Process Template Customization
3 – Adding Field to a Work Item Definition
4 – Customize Work Item Fields with Rules
5 – Interesting rules to customize work items.
6 – Customize States and Transitions of a Work Item
In previous post I did a brief introduction to the concept of States and Transitions of Work Items and it is time to do a little deep dive to understand how you can configure complex rules on transition between states.</description></item><item><title>Tfs and VS 11 virtual machine</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/tfs-and-vs-11-virtual-machine/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/tfs-and-vs-11-virtual-machine/</guid><description>As usual Brian Keller has produced a test VM with all sort of goodness regarding TFS 11 and VS 11, you can find details here. The machine is full of useful staff, as described in Brian Keller’s post:
Microsoft Windows Server 2008 R2 Standard Edition Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2 Microsoft Visual Studio 11 Ultimate Developer Preview Microsoft Team Foundation Server 11 Developer Preview Microsoft SharePoint Foundation 2010 Microsoft Project 2010 Microsoft Office Professional 2010 (Word, PowerPoint, Excel) Sample users and data required to support hands-on-lab scripts which accompany this download and exercise some of the new Visual Studio 11 application lifecycle management capabilities introduced in this release The only drawback is that it is only an Hyper-V machine, no more Virtual PC version, this is mainly due to the need to have a 64 bit machine (that is currently unsupported in virtual pc).</description></item><item><title>I love virtual machines</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/i-love-virtual-machines/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/i-love-virtual-machines/</guid><description>I’m installing TFS 11 developer preview and I got this.
So I clicked settings, added another 4 gb ram to the machine (to a total of 6 GB), vmWare workstation suspend the machine for a bunch of seconds, then I rerun check and magically I can move on.
And I’m a few seconds away to have a TFS 11 to play with dev11 bits :), I’m exited.
Gian Maria.</description></item><item><title>How to configure a build controller against tfspreview</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/how-to-configure-a-build-controller-against-tfspreview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/how-to-configure-a-build-controller-against-tfspreview/</guid><description>I’ve blogged yesterday about the video on channel 9 that explains how to configure a build server against a TfsPreview account and this morning Brian Harry made a post that explains this process in great detail.
The good part is that you have a lot of possible configuration.
You can install the build server on any machine you use – a workgroup machine at home, a domain machine at work, an Azure VM Role, an Amazon VM, whatever you like.</description></item><item><title>Installing a Build controller against an Hosted TFS on Azure</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/installing-a-build-controller-against-an-hosted-tfs-on-azure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/installing-a-build-controller-against-an-hosted-tfs-on-azure/</guid><description>One of the greatest news of yesterday was the availability of the TEam Foundation Server on Windows Azure. I can assure you that there is a huge hunting for invitation code (mine 5 are terminated after few minutes ;) ) and this demonstrates the high interest that people have against TFS on Azure.
Clearly the other interesting news is the availability of the Developer Preview for the next version of Visual Studio (you can read the details here).</description></item><item><title>Using Power Tools Shell Extension with VS2008</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/using-power-tools-shell-extension-with-vs2008/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/using-power-tools-shell-extension-with-vs2008/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a great fan of TFS power tools, and working as a consultant it is normal for me to use TFS2010 as well TFS2008 servers, because some of my customers still uses TFS2008. In my laptop I&amp;rsquo;ve installed VS2008, team explorer and the latest power tools (August 2011), then I mapped a workspace from VS2008, but when I right click on mapped folder, no Team Foundation Server menu appears in contextual menu.</description></item><item><title>Patch to speedup editing of TFS Build template</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/patch-to-speedup-editing-of-tfs-build-template/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2011 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/08/patch-to-speedup-editing-of-tfs-build-template/</guid><description>You can find all details here. If you edit workflow definition quite often, this hotfix can really improve your experience.
Alk.</description></item><item><title>Customize State and Transitions of a Work Item</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/customize-state-and-transitions-of-a-work-item/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/customize-state-and-transitions-of-a-work-item/</guid><description>1 – Customize Tfs Process Template
2 – Basic of TFS Process Template Customization
3 – Adding Field to a Work Item Definition
4 – Customize Work Item Fields with Rules
5 – Interesting rules to customize work items.
Now that we know how to add information to a Work Item definition, it is time to deal with “state” management. Each Work Item has a field called * Status *that is completely different from any other field, because has an associated workflow that manages transactions from various allowed status values.</description></item><item><title>Visual Studio 2010 RTM Virtual Machine Speed up</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/visual-studio-2010-rtm-virtual-machine-speed-up/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/visual-studio-2010-rtm-virtual-machine-speed-up/</guid><description>I usually use the Brian Keller&amp;rsquo;s RTM Virtual Machine to do TFS demo in talk or to customers. It comes on two flavors, a Virtual PC version and an Hyper-V version. If you use the Virtual PC version, is is originally configured to use 2 GB of ram and if you give it the maximum amount (3.6 GB) you can notice that the gain in speed is not so big.</description></item><item><title>Interesting rules to customize Work Items</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/interesting-rules-to-customize-work-items/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2011 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/interesting-rules-to-customize-work-items/</guid><description>1 – Customize Tfs Process Template
2 – Basic of TFS Process Template Customization
3 – Adding Field to a Work Item Definition
4 – Customize Work Item Fields with Rules
In fourth chapter we familiarized with Rules and how you can customize a Work Items adding rules to it. You can find a complete list of Rules at this link, but I want to show you the most useful ones (at least in my opinion).</description></item><item><title>A bunch of links for TFS ecosystem</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/a-bunch-of-links-for-tfs-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2011 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/a-bunch-of-links-for-tfs-ecosystem/</guid><description>TFS is not a tool, but a platform/ecosystem and if you miss to install / consider to use all of the free or commercial tools based on Tfs, you are actually missing the most part of it. Surely TFS comes with a very huge amount of features out of the box, but there are also an extremely high number of useful tools developed by third party developers.
Here is a surely incomplete list (I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep it updated) and in random order of a bunch of tools I know for TFS ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Customize Work Itemrsquos fields with Rules</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/customize-work-items-fields-with-rules/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2011 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/customize-work-items-fields-with-rules/</guid><description>1 – Customize Tfs Process Template
2 – Basic of TFS Process Template Customization
3 – Adding Field to a Work Item Definition
In the third part of this tutorial I showed how to add a field to a Work Item Definition, in this post I’ll show how you can customize field’s behavior with the addition of Rules.
If I select the new field I just created (called Note di revisione), I can press edit to modify its definition and in the “Field Definition” form I can manage all the Rulesapplied to the field.</description></item><item><title>Customization of TFS process template - adding field to a Work Item Definition</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/customization-of-tfs-process-template-adding-field-to-a-work-item-definition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/customization-of-tfs-process-template-adding-field-to-a-work-item-definition/</guid><description>1 – Customize Tfs Process Template
2 – Basic of TFS Process Template Customization
In this third part it is time to configure the definition of a Work Item. This is the most complex and more useful section of the process template that you can modify to adapt to your needs. We can modify a WI definition in two distinct way: on a local process template as explained in the previous articles and directly on a Team Process that exists on the server.</description></item><item><title>Basic of TFS Process Template customization</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/basic-of-tfs-process-template-customization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/basic-of-tfs-process-template-customization/</guid><description>1 – Customize Tfs Process Template
In the first post I showed how to download the definition of a process template into a local folder and how to open it with the Process Template Editor; in this post I&amp;rsquo;ll show you some of the very basic customizations that you can do with the PTE.
In the Methodology section you can simply change the name of the Process Template as well as including a textual description.</description></item><item><title>Customize TFS Process Template</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/customize-tfs-process-template/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/customize-tfs-process-template/</guid><description>One of the best aspect of TFS is that it is customizable: we can interact with API, customize builds, handle events and many other interaction, but one of the most important is the ability to customize the process template.
This capability is fundamental, because permit to adapt TFS to own process, the mantra is ** do not adapt your process to the tool, but adapt the tool to your process **.</description></item><item><title>Getting code coverage result in drop folder during a TFS2010 buils</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/05/getting-code-coverage-result-in-drop-folder-during-a-tfs2010-buils/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/05/getting-code-coverage-result-in-drop-folder-during-a-tfs2010-buils/</guid><description>In a very old post I explained how to enable code coverage in TFS2010 builds and today I received a mail asking an interesting question.
The question is: Is it possible to have Code Coverage result to be included in drop folder?.
Answering this question is a two phase process, the first one is understanding where MsTest store results of code coverage and verify that is possible to do something useful with them.</description></item><item><title>Installing Tfs with SP1</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/05/installing-tfs-with-sp1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/05/installing-tfs-with-sp1/</guid><description>One of the cool feature of TFS2010 is the separation between installationand *configuration.*If you need to install a fresh TFS2010 now that SP1 is out, you can simply install tfs, skip the configuration phase and immediately install SP1. This will install SP1 bits on the machine, now you can proceed to configuration.
After everything is done you can verify that the server is really running with SP1 enabled.
As you can see, after configuration the Version tells me that I&amp;rsquo;m running with SP1 installed</description></item><item><title>Idiomatic VCS usage</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/idiomatic-vcs-usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/04/idiomatic-vcs-usage/</guid><description>When it is time to compare two VCS there are a lot of features to be taken into account, and in my opinion one of the most important is the team is already used to some VCS?. One of the most difficult part of learning a new VCS, is avoiding to use it in the same way you use a different product, because each VCS could potentially have a different way to do the same thing.</description></item><item><title>A not well known feature of TFS web access</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/03/a-not-well-known-feature-of-tfs-web-access/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/03/a-not-well-known-feature-of-tfs-web-access/</guid><description>For those of you thinking that TFS Web Access is only another interface for TFS, I want to signal a couple of interesting feature that are available only in the web interface. When you open a bug for editing, you have a tools menu with an interesting command called State Diagram.
Figure 1: Menu command to visualize the State Diagram for the Work Item type
This command will show a diagram showing the state diagram of the Work Item type, and it is really cool to have a graphical idea on how a Bug or other Work Item is handled by this project template.</description></item><item><title>Use credential manager to use TFS shell extension in a workgroup or outside a domain</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/03/use-credential-manager-to-use-tfs-shell-extension-in-a-workgroup-or-outside-a-domain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/03/use-credential-manager-to-use-tfs-shell-extension-in-a-workgroup-or-outside-a-domain/</guid><description>Yesterday I&amp;rsquo;ve blogged about TFS Power tools Shell Extension, and today my friend Michele told me that he has a problem, the extension always told him to Reconnect to server and he is not able to use them.
This is probably due to an authentication request, so you can try to open Team Explorer, and if it asks for credential on connecting to TFS this is the reason. Shell extension are not able to ask for different user, so if you are outside the TFS domain or if you are in workgroup the only solution is going to Control Panel and fire the Credential Manager.</description></item><item><title>Distributing Visual Studio addin for the team</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/12/distributing-visual-studio-addin-for-the-team/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2010 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/12/distributing-visual-studio-addin-for-the-team/</guid><description>One of the most requested feature for TFS is the ability to distribute automatically Visual Studio adding to team member. This needs is especially important for addin like Custom Check-in policies, because if developers do not install check-in policies they would not be run during a Check-in. Every time you show check-in policies to a customer, it immediately ask you how to distribute them to all developers pc automatically.
I found that some people are not aware that such a feature is already there, but is included in TFS power tools, so it is not available out of the box with a plain installation of Visual Studio and TFS.</description></item><item><title>Keep Codeplex projects and local TFS projects syncronized</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/09/keep-codeplex-projects-and-local-tfs-projects-syncronized/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/09/keep-codeplex-projects-and-local-tfs-projects-syncronized/</guid><description>Codeplex is Microsoft hosting site for open source projects, based on TFS or mercurial. Now suppose you have this scenario: an open source project, with a core team that work actively on it, and some occasional contributors that do little work. Since Codeplex does not support every feature of tfs, (especially you lack the build machine), sharepoint integration and other stuff you loose many useful feature if you use only Codeplex for the project.</description></item><item><title>Codeplex is upgraded-how to map to the new server</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/codeplex-is-upgradedhow-to-map-to-the-new-server/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2010 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/codeplex-is-upgradedhow-to-map-to-the-new-server/</guid><description>My frient Guardian blogged some minutes ago explaining how you can change the mapping of your codeplex project now that codeplex is migrated to TFS2010. There is even a simpler solution, first of all open Visual Studio, then connect to the new tfs server. As you can see in Figure 1 I have projects in three project collection, I select to connect to the TFS08 project collection where I&amp;rsquo;m contributor to two project</description></item><item><title>Merging and resolving conflicts</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/01/merging-and-resolving-conflicts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2010 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/01/merging-and-resolving-conflicts/</guid><description>Sometimes I hear people that does not like the way TFS manages merge conflicts, and quite all of the time the problem is that they does not like the Visual Studio Integrated tool to merge two files. I must admit that I do not like that tool too, but this is not related to TFS, because conflicts resolution is an operation that must be done by people locally.
For those people, like me, that work a lot with subversion, probably winmerge is the right tool to resolve merge conflicts, and it is really simple to instruct Visual Studio to use winmerge instead of the standard tool to merge two files.</description></item><item><title>Another one from the TFS Rangers</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/01/another-one-from-the-tfs-rangers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2010 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/01/another-one-from-the-tfs-rangers/</guid><description>If you are interested in implementing TFS 2010 in your company, or if you already implemented TFS 2010 beta2 but you want to go deeper because you want to use your tfs in a optimal way, you can check the Visual Studio 2010 Team Foundation SERver REquirements Management guide from the TFS Rangers. You will find tons of useful information :)
Alk
Tags: Tfs</description></item><item><title>Managing different config file with TFS Branching</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/01/managing-different-config-file-with-tfs-branching/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2010 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/01/managing-different-config-file-with-tfs-branching/</guid><description>I begin working on a open source project, hosted on codeplex. The first thing I need to do is to modify configuration files to make it work on my machine (in my situation I need only to change the sql connection string). In this scenario a big problem arise, if every developer has a different configuration file, there is the possibility that someone will do a wrong checkin, and send to the server his configuration file.</description></item><item><title>Using graphical editor with custom action in tfs2010 buils</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/12/using-graphical-editor-with-custom-action-in-tfs2010-buils/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2009 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/12/using-graphical-editor-with-custom-action-in-tfs2010-buils/</guid><description>In last post I showed how to build a custom code activity to customize tfsbuild for beta2 of tfs2010. In that post I inserted custom action manually in the xaml file of the build definition, and I know that this can be a pain, if you want to insert a custom action in a specific part of the workflow.
A simple trick is the following, copy the build definition into a test project that belong to the solution where your custom action belong, then add to the project, and you will see that your custom action magically appears into the toolbox.</description></item><item><title>Custom Activities in TFS2010</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/12/custom-activities-in-tfs2010/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/12/custom-activities-in-tfs2010/</guid><description>There is a good post on Jim Lamb&amp;rsquo;s blog on how to customize tfs2010 build, but I decided to blog my experience because I need some more time to make it work.
The steps to create a custom activities in tfs2010 are the following ones. First of all create an activity, like this simple TweetActivity one. Respect the example of Jim, I need to add also the BuildExtensionAttribute to make it run.</description></item><item><title>TF255070 User account xxxaccount not found</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/tf255070-user-account-xxxaccount-not-found/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2009 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/tf255070-user-account-xxxaccount-not-found/</guid><description>In tfs 2010 beta2, when you configure the build agent, you start the wizard choosing the team foundation server that contains the project collection you want to build. If you choose tfs with ip address, you will end with an error like
This error is probably caused to the fact that windows does not support user name with ip address, in this situation the user 10.0.0.242\tfsBuildAgent really does not exists on the server.</description></item><item><title>Installing TFS2010 Beta2 first try</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/installing-tfs2010-beta2-first-try/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2009 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/installing-tfs2010-beta2-first-try/</guid><description>Installing TFS is an operation that scares most people. With TFS2010 beta 2 the installation process is really more friendly. I installed a new windows server 2008 machine, update everything and begin the installation to verify the new installer.
You start setup.exe, tells what you want to install, and press next, then after some minutes tfs is installed&amp;hellip; this is amazing respect to the older version. Now that everything needed was installed we need to start configuration.</description></item><item><title>Automatic deployment of a web application with TFS Build</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/automatic-deployment-of-a-web-application-with-tfs-build/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2009 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/automatic-deployment-of-a-web-application-with-tfs-build/</guid><description>When you develop web applications you usually have X developers solving bugs and implementing features, and a series of testers that test application during developing process. A must to have requirement is that
Modifications to the trunk are visible as soon as possible to testers. Data in test database gets preserved Point 2 is especially important, testers usually work with the site and fills database with data. Suppose that tester John find a bug that occurs only with specific data, a developer correct the bug, then a deploy is done, all test data are wiped away, and the tester is not able to verify if the bug is gone.</description></item><item><title>Deploy a database project with TFS Build</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/deploy-a-database-project-with-tfs-build/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/10/deploy-a-database-project-with-tfs-build/</guid><description>When you develop web application you often have this scenario. Some people are testers, they are testing the application in dev all day, and they want always to test latest version. Moreover testers usually fills data into web application, so they want their data to be preserved between various deploy. If you simply clear all data in test database you will end with a lot of furious tester :) so do not even think to do this.</description></item><item><title>Team foundation server and excel</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/team-foundation-server-and-excel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2009 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/team-foundation-server-and-excel/</guid><description>One of the greatest features of Tfs is that it is a single product that is able to manage the whole ALM of an application, but another strength point is high level of integration with other tools. One of the coolest feature is the ability to use Excel to manage workitems, without the need to even open visual studio.
It is enough for you to install the team exploer, and you will get office integration.</description></item><item><title>Tfs Web access and some tinyurl magic to signal test failure</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/tfs-web-access-and-some-tinyurl-magic-to-signal-test-failure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/tfs-web-access-and-some-tinyurl-magic-to-signal-test-failure/</guid><description>In the last post of Tfs series, I showed how to build a msbuild custom action to tweet when build test run fails. Using twitter can seem strange at first, and probably not so professional to associate to a project build, but this is not true. Twitter is a free service that can be consumed from many devices, you can use tool such as twitterDeck to manage all of your tweets in your desktop environment and to categorize them, but you can also use any mobile phone, so it is probably the most serious way to signal build problems to everyone is interested in the build process of a certain project.</description></item></channel></rss>