<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogging on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/blogging/</link><description>Recent content in Blogging on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 06:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/blogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Azure DevOps: complete Pull Requests via web interface</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/azdo/misc/complete-pull-request-via-web-interface/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 06:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/azdo/misc/complete-pull-request-via-web-interface/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pull Requests are the Heart Beat of your code, you have a request/bugfix/feature in a form of work item, the team start a branch, write code, then when the code is finished &lt;strong>a Pull Request is opened to ask the team for review before the code is merged into the stable branch and goes to production&lt;/strong>. When you deploy regularly your product in an automatic way, you need to &lt;strong>minimize the risk that new code can break existing one&lt;/strong> and having other members of the team to review the code increment, is an invaluable feature. Also Pull Requests can include discussion about code increment, so you can examine that discussions in the future when you wonder why a piece of code was written in that specific way, and why.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moving old posts from WordPress to Hugo</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/conversion-of-wordpress/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/conversion-of-wordpress/</guid><description>&lt;p>It was almost one year from my switch from WordPress to Hugo and I&amp;rsquo;m really really satisfied from the result. After some months the only thing that bother me is &lt;strong>the fact that I still need to maintain an instance of WordPress just to keep old posts&lt;/strong>. The only thing that prevented me to migrate was the loss of comments, but actually, after looking to all of my old blog posts, I&amp;rsquo;ve not such a big amount of comments that worth migrating, &lt;strong>the only thing that is important to me is the ability to keep my old post without comments&lt;/strong> so I can get rid of WordPress. I&amp;rsquo;m sorry for all of you that spent time commenting on my blog, but migrating the comments would be a huge work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GitHub Codespaces first impression</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/github-codespaces-first-impression/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/github-codespaces-first-impression/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="what-is-github-codespaces">What is GitHub codespaces&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Visual Studio Code is becoming one of the most used and productive editors in all operating system and it is used by most developers. During these years Visual Studio Code introduced lots of interesting features, like the &lt;strong>ability to connect to Linux or Docker Container and develop inside that container&lt;/strong>. This means that your machine can run Windows / Linux / MacOS or whatever, but you can connect to a Linux machine or Linux Docker instance and &lt;strong>develop inside that container&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Some fix for Word Exporter</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/azdo/misc/export-to-word-img-and-work-item-type/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/azdo/misc/export-to-word-img-and-work-item-type/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is another post in the series &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>how to export Work Item data to Word Document&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Complete code for project can be found in &lt;a href="https://github.com/alkampfergit/AzureDevopsWordPlayground">GitHub - https://github.com/alkampfergit/AzureDevopsWordPlayground&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Post in the series:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2018/12/28/azure-devops-api-connection/">API Connection&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2018/12/28/azure-devops-api-retrieve-work-items-information/">Retrieve Work Items Information&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2018/12/31/azure-devops-api-embed-images-into-html/">Azure DevOps API, Embed images into HTML&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2018/12/31/create-word-document-from-work-items/">Create Word Document For Work Items&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2019/07/10/retrieve-image-in-work-item-description-with-tfs-api/">Retrieve image in Work Item Description with TFS API&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2019/07/25/retrieve-attachment-in-azure-devops-with-rest-api/">Retrieve Attachment in Azure DevOps with REST API in C#&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Exporter project was updated a little bit in past months, I had no time for blogging about it but probably it is the time to give further information on &lt;strong>how to export all of your Work Items to a Word File.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Advantage of Hugo</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/advantage-of-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/advantage-of-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p>I should admit that I was one of the people that loved blogging with Windows Live Writer and in general with software that is able to simple &lt;strong>edit content, paste images, press a button and your post is online&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes you just need to go out from your comfort zone a little bit to change perspective and to find what you are doing wrong. Let me do an example: &lt;strong>I used different plugins to print formatted code in my blog&lt;/strong> and after some migration you can see what happened to very first posts (around 2007).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moving to Hugo</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/firstpost/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 17:17:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/general/firstpost/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve started blogging in English in 2007 and clearly the choice was WordPress. I must admit that in lots of years of WordPress I always was quite satisfied by the result, lots of plugin, lots of resources on the internet and the ability to post from programs like Windows Live Writer having a WYSIWYG program.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also read one of the first post where I &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2007/05/03/the-advantage-of-word2007-blogging/">enjoyed blogging in Word&lt;/a>, really long time passed since that really old post.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google probably does not like cloudflare</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/google-probably-does-not-like-cloudflare/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/09/google-probably-does-not-like-cloudflare/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve signed up months ago for a &lt;a href="http://www.cloudflare.com/">Cloudflare&lt;/a> during a refactoring of my web site, at the same time I changed the theme of the blog, cleaned up a little bit the HTML of the page and optimized few stuffs. I was very satisfied of the gain of performance I got with Cloudflare, but after a month stats of blog started to went down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The trend was continuous, each week traffic is slightly less than previous week and all traffic loss is mostly from Google organic&lt;/em>. I started thinking that &lt;strong>the change to HTML structure I’ve done during refactoring is the root cause of this&lt;/strong> , after a month I realized that wordpress version is old and since this information is visible even in Google Webmaster tools I suspected that Google is penalizing me for having an old version of wordpress (maybe it has some security bug) so I upgraded, but nothing changed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Test posting in the future</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/test-posting-in-the-future/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/test-posting-in-the-future/</guid><description>&lt;p>Probably one of the most missed feature of wordpress is the possibility to post in the future. There are days when you have tons of ideas, but you simply avoid to blog just because you&amp;rsquo;ve already blogged a lot in the last days. One of the most interesting feature of wordpress, as well as other blog engine is the ability to post in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The good stuff is that windows live writer is able to decide date of the post directly on the post page, I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post 03 July 2009, but it will be published only the next day. Moreover in the net there are some suggestions on how to &lt;a href="http://webdemar.com/wordpress/display-future-posts-in-your-wordpress-theme/">show a list of future post in the sidebar&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>