<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scrum on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/scrum/</link><description>Recent content in Scrum on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 08:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/scrum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The advantage of Scrum in evaluating 'new stuff'</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/04/the-advantage-of-scrum-in-evaluating-new-stuff/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2014/04/the-advantage-of-scrum-in-evaluating-new-stuff/</guid><description>One of the greatest problem in Software industry is the rapid change in Technologies and Tools, a change so rapid that your knowledge become stale or obsolete before you have the time to fully master your new toys. In this scenario the major problem is how to evaluate some new “stuff”, while not losing money and, most important, how to understand if the new “stuff” is really better than the old one so it worth continue spending time on it and not moving on other newer “stuff”.</description></item><item><title>Risk of not being agile</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/risk-of-not-being-agile/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/06/risk-of-not-being-agile/</guid><description>Deciding if it worth change own process towards agile ones, es Scrum, should be done not only estimating the advantage of using the new process, but also estimating the risk of not using agile procedures developing software in these days. Lets speak about a fail story that could be avoided with scrum (if you do not know what Scrum is you can read What is Scrum on Scrum.org).
A project started with a set of requirements approved by the stakeholder, after initial basic features were implemented, developers started to work on an “advanced search functionality” requirement, that had * quite technical difficulties and took quite a bit of time to develop *.</description></item></channel></rss>