<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Net on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/net/</link><description>Recent content in Net on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 14:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Weak reference to delegate never do it</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/weak-reference-to-delegate-never-do-it/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/06/weak-reference-to-delegate-never-do-it/</guid><description>In previous post I explained how I modified the Broker class to store WeakReference to Action&amp;lt;Message&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&amp;gt; delegate to avoid the broker preventing garbage collection of the subscribers. This is a strong requirement, an object register an handler to the broker, but it does not want to share the same lifecycle of the broker because it is singleton. After this modification I have a strange bug, the program works, but after some minutes messages stops flowing, I scratched my head and then understand that this is normal, because my code that uses a WeakReference to an even is flawed.</description></item><item><title>Changing appconfig value at runtime</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/02/changing-app-config-value-at-runtime/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 15:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/02/changing-app-config-value-at-runtime/</guid><description>Sometimes there is the need to modify the value of some part of the configuration file of a.NET application at runtime, this is an example: I have a software that read some content from xml files, and have several paths listed in the AppSettings section of application configuration file.
During the very first run the software should extract xml data from a zip file to a directory chosen by the user, then the software should update all these settings to reflect this changes.</description></item><item><title>Error during clickonce deploy with mshtml 8211 Strong name signature not valid for this assembly</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/error-during-clickonce-deploy-with-mshtml-strong-name-signature-not-valid-for-this-assembly/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/error-during-clickonce-deploy-with-mshtml-strong-name-signature-not-valid-for-this-assembly/</guid><description>To deploy application that use mshtml with clickonce, you need to be sure that microsoft.mshtml.dll is included in the setup of click once, or the application will not install if mshtml.dll is not present on the machine at the time of deploy. But if you include it sometimes clients are not able to install application due to the following error
Strong name signature not valid for this assembly Microsoft.mshtml.dll
this is due to the fact that you reference a partially signed version in your project.</description></item><item><title>Pass a serialized object in querystring with less chars</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/pass-a-serialized-object-in-querystring-with-less-chars/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/11/pass-a-serialized-object-in-querystring-with-less-chars/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve some legacy code where stuff have to be passed with querystring, because we need to issue Get request to the server, and I need to pass various set of parameters for some reporting functions, but those parameters have 20 field, and are somewhat used as a tree. I decided to serialize everything and pass the result with querystring using HttpUtility.UrlEncoding&amp;hellip; the result was frustrating because the url are simply too long.</description></item></channel></rss>