<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Experiences on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/experiences/</link><description>Recent content in Experiences on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 12:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/categories/experiences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SonarQube UTF-8 error after upgrading</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/12/sonarqube-utf-8-error-after-upgrading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 12:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/12/sonarqube-utf-8-error-after-upgrading/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve upgraded a SonarQube instance, and then, suddently I realyze that some builds start failing due to to a &lt;strong>strange error in the SonarQube complete analysis task&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">
&lt;table style="border-spacing:0;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">&lt;tr>&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">1
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">2
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">3
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;;width:100%">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>2016-12-09T11:41:00.8695497Z &lt;span style="color:#75715e">##[error]WARN:&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> Invalid character encountered in file C:&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">\v&lt;/span>so&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">\_&lt;/span>work&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">\3\s\s&lt;/span>rc&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">\J&lt;/span>arvis.ConfigurationService.Client.CastleIntegration&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">\P&lt;/span>roperties&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">\A&lt;/span>ssemblyInfo.cs at line &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">25&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">for&lt;/span> encoding UTF-8.
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> Please fix file content or configure the encoding to be used using property &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;sonar.sourceEncoding&amp;#39;&lt;/span>.&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Thiserror in turns made the entire task execution failing with a really strange error&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Budget for Hardware</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/11/budget-for-hardware/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/11/budget-for-hardware/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve just read &lt;a href="http://davybrion.com/blog/2011/11/faster-hardware-not-on-our-budget/">this blog post&lt;/a> that deals about the benefit of having the right hardware to work for developers. Quite often having or not having an SSD is not the real problem, because developers works with machine with low ram and slow disks and this is especially true for people working with laptop, that often uses 5.400 standard RPM disks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is difficult to understand how much minutes or hours per day a developer can save moving &lt;em>from an average speed hardware to a top speed hardware&lt;/em> and without these numbers it is difficult to justify the expense of buying top speed hardware. On the opposite, if it is difficult to demonstrate the&lt;em>gain in productivity with&lt;/em> &lt;em>fast hardware&lt;/em>, it is quite simpler to demonstrate the &lt;em>lack of productivity with crappy hardware.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The good part of having a lot of RAM</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/the-good-part-of-having-a-lot-of-ram/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 13:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/the-good-part-of-having-a-lot-of-ram/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve learned in the past a precious rule about hardware: try to imagine how you will use your pc in at least one or two years period before thinking to buy some piece of hardware.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I remember a lot of years ago, when I bought a pc with a 1.6 GB Hard Disk, a size that was really big for these period, when standard pc had 512 MB Hard Disk or less. I remember a couple of friends of mine told me “why you spent money on such a big Hard Disk, it is really too big, you will never need such a big space”. After one year, I ran in those machine a partition of Windows 95, one for DOS, a stable partition with Linux Slackware distribution and a fourth partition to experiment the new distribution of linux that we downloaded from the university. I’ve plenty of space while my friends strived themselves to keep everything inside 512 MB.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I love virtual machines</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/i-love-virtual-machines/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/09/i-love-virtual-machines/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m installing TFS 11 developer preview and I got this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/image1.png">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/image_thumb1.png"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/image_thumb1.png" alt="image" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I clicked settings, added another 4 gb ram to the machine (to a total of 6 GB), vmWare workstation suspend the machine for a bunch of seconds, then I rerun check and magically I can move on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I’m a few seconds away to have a TFS 11 to play with dev11 bits :), I’m exited.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gian Maria.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How could I work without resharper</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/02/how-could-i-work-without-resharper/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2011 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/02/how-could-i-work-without-resharper/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a system that use heavily IoC principle, it is common during component modification, to discover that to add a new functionality that component need to add a dependency on some interface. Here is the constructor of a component&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">
&lt;table style="border-spacing:0;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">&lt;tr>&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">1
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">2
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">3
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">4
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;;width:100%">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">public&lt;/span> MainNavigator(
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>IEBrochureService brochureService,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>IBroker broker)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>{&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Now I need to add dependency from the IWpfSystem interface, so I simply add another parameter to the constructor, and R# suggests me a lot of action that could be triggered from this modification&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Add a cache andhellip yoursquove created a security bug</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/01/add-a-cache-and-youve-created-a-security-bug/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2011/01/add-a-cache-and-youve-created-a-security-bug/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the history of a nasty bug happened today. There is some service that has a method called GetCustomers() and this function is used from a web application and a Windows application. Since landing web page use this function to show all customers data, and since  Customers entity changes rarely we decide to put the result of this service call in Cache with 1 hour absolute expiration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Web interface is made in WebForms, so we used an ObjectDataSource to communicate with the service, here is the code.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>When it is time of quick and dirty hotfix</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/11/when-it-is-time-of-quick-and-dirty-hotfix/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/11/when-it-is-time-of-quick-and-dirty-hotfix/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve a software composed by many pieces, one of them was deployed 9 month ago and works well, today we find a little bug and need to change a string in it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The obvious solution is, take the release branch, change the string, compile and deploy again, but there is even a dirtier approach, I&amp;rsquo;ve simply disassembled the file with ildasm, changed the string and finally assemble it again (and clearly I changed the string even in the branch).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Did you start programming on</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/08/what-did-you-start-programming-on/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2010 11:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/08/what-did-you-start-programming-on/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve just read this &lt;a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/bleroy/archive/2010/08/02/what-did-you-start-programming-on.aspx">nice blog post&lt;/a>, and I want to give my contribute to it :).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve started programming on a Vic20 Commodore computer, I began just with copying a couple of programs that are in the manual, and immediately being curious about the &lt;em>Basic&lt;/em> language.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I moved to a Vic20 programming course in Cassette and this was the very first thing that amazed me, the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m able to record a program on a audio cassette, I believed that they could be used only for music. I realize now, how many years are passed. After the course I was a &lt;em>Basic programmer&lt;/em> :P, being able to manage memory with Peek and Poke and started realizing some little programs. My first programs are full of GOTO and were really &lt;em>spaghetti code&lt;/em>, but when I began high school I moved to Pascal, and I began to learn how to give better structure to my programs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Primitive broker class</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/primitive-broker-class/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2010 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/07/primitive-broker-class/</guid><description>&lt;p>I need in a simple project the ability to communicate various type of messages through different View Model in a WPF application, some VM raise some message about something that is happened in the system, and other VM can listen for messages and doing something with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know that there are a lot of framework out of there, but sometimes you need a quick implementation that you can share with the team, without the need to tell to others &lt;em>Hey you need to master xxx framework for understanding what is happening&lt;/em>. The result is a really 30 minutes implementation of a primitive broker. I want a central component where every View Model can register/unregister for a specific kind of a message, and send messages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Brian Harry programming practices</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/brian-harry-programming-practices/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2010/03/brian-harry-programming-practices/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m exited on Brian Harry&amp;rsquo;s plan to do a series of posts regarding programming practices in his blog. The main reason is that Brian had really wrote tons of good code and it is really interesting knowing how he organize his projects. From this &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/bharry/archive/2010/03/09/programming-practices-part-1-watching-from-a-distance.aspx">first post&lt;/a> I strongly agree with a couple of concepts, the first is having a clean code at regular interval, no longer than few hours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I made mistake in the past, and sometimes in the present, I begin coding a super new feature, with a lot of code, and after some hours I have nothing working because I&amp;rsquo;m still doing infrastructure code, etc etc. This is sometimes due to the fact that I&amp;rsquo;d like to start with beautiful and well architected code, but the risk is getting lost in development. Quite often it is better to start with some &lt;em>quick and dirty&lt;/em> functional prototype, that gets you straight into the point, then refactor to a more clean solution if the prototype is going well. This avoid you the risk to work for a couple of days just to find that you took the wrong solution path. Proceeding step by step is the best way to reach a working solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speedup Visual Studio with faster disk</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/speedup-visual-studio-with-faster-disk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2009 04:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/speedup-visual-studio-with-faster-disk/</guid><description>&lt;p>We always know that to speedup visual studio a &lt;a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/scottgu/archive/2007/11/01/tip-trick-hard-drive-speed-and-visual-studio-performance.aspx">fast disk is quite always a good choice&lt;/a>, but what is best configuration?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve done some little benchmark on the compilation of a project with a msbuild script and here is the result.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When all sources are stored in C:\ drive (A velociraptor 10k disk) it compiles in 58 sec the first time, and 44 sec the second time and subsequent ones.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Power of virtualization</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/power-of-virtualization/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/power-of-virtualization/</guid><description>&lt;p>I really do not remember when was the first time I heard of &lt;a href="http://info.vmware.com/content/GLP_IT_virt_LP1Buy?urlcode=PaidSearch_Google_EMEA-South_Italian_VI_General_VMware_Search_IT_virt_LP1Buy&amp;amp;amp;src=PaidSearch_Google_EMEA-South_Italian_VI_General_VMware_Search_IT_virt_LP1Buy&amp;amp;amp;ossrc=PaidSearch_Google_EMEA-South_Italian_VI_General_VMware_Search_IT_virt_LP1Buy&amp;amp;amp;CMP=KNC-google&amp;amp;amp;HBX_OU=50&amp;amp;amp;HBX_PK=IT_virt_LP1Buy&amp;amp;amp;gclid=COqPqt69xpwCFQcTzAodgh-6Jg">VmWare&lt;/a>,  I clearly remember that at those time I used both windows and Linux, and one day a friend of mine sent me a mail with an image showing Windows Maker desktop, with a windows inside that shows the install phase of windows 95. I was curios about how to take a snapshot of windows installer phase, but reading the mail my friend told me of virtualization :D, and explained me that he was able to run a windows 95 instance inside a linux system.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Good paper come back to use</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/good-paper-come-back-to-use/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2009 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/08/good-paper-come-back-to-use/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve just read another &lt;a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/archives/001292.html">good post of Jeff Atwood&lt;/a>, that speak about &lt;a href="http://ollydbg.de/Paperbak/">PaperBack&lt;/a>. I must admit that in 2009 it seems an oddity to claim for backup on paper, but it is an interesting and viable option to backup data. I must admit that I really love books, I like to have a book in my hand and I really love paper. Doing a backup on paper is really cool, because you can really touch your backup, with hands, and you can visually states that it is in good condition using only your eyes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Balsamiq mockup to the rescue</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/balsamiq-mockup-to-the-rescue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/balsamiq-mockup-to-the-rescue/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I have to add some features to a wpf application and the interface was already quite cluttered with controls. Things are becoming messy, so I decided that I need to spent a little time restructuring the UI. I decided to use collapsible panels, but I need users feelings about this change, so I open &lt;a href="http://www.balsamiq.com/">balsamiq&lt;/a> and created some mockup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The good stuff about balsamiq is that is incredible simple to use and really versatile, first of all I noticed that there are no collapsible panel control but it is simple to simulate one, first of all you can create a rectangle&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts on software engineering</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/thoughts-on-software-engineering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2009 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/07/thoughts-on-software-engineering/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was reading &lt;a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/archives/001288.html">this post&lt;/a> of Jeff Atwood that link &lt;a href="http://www2.computer.org/cms/Computer.org/ComputingNow/homepage/2009/0709/rW_SO_Viewpoints.pdf">this interesting article&lt;/a>. One of the key point in the article was to consider two different kind of projects&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Project  A  will  eventually  cost  about  a  million dollars and produce value of around $1.1 million.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Project B will  eventually  cost about a million dollars  and  produce  value  of more  than  $50 million.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>And the conclusion is that *control is more important in project A and not in project B,*and another astonishing sentence in the article was&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Publish a project with ClickOnce via NANT and CCNet</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/publish-a-project-with-clickonce-via-nant-and-ccnet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/publish-a-project-with-clickonce-via-nant-and-ccnet/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have a project that needs to be published automatically through IIS directory, clickonce and CC.net machine. The easiest way to make this happens is to follow these simple instructions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First of all goes into the machine where the CC.Net runs, prepare the IIS directory where the clickonce generated setup will be copied, open the solution into visual studio, goes to the project you want to publish and set everything needed for clickonce, set version to 1.0.0.0 and publish through visual studio IDE. This will create the folder structure in IIS and the application is published for the first time with the version number 1.0.0.0. Now take the publish.htm file and copy into the trunk of your project into a specific directory (I used Configuration\ClickOnce), rename it in OriginalPublish.htm, edit it and find the place where visual studio ide wrote the string 1.0.0.0, replace it with the string VERSIONNUMBERTOKEN.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cannot create project in a newly installed TFS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/cannot-create-project-in-a-newly-installed-tfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/cannot-create-project-in-a-newly-installed-tfs/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve just installed Tfs For Workgroup in a small virtual machine to make some experiments. After setting up the machine (Windows 2008) I installed TFS SErvice pack 1 then tfs power toys and finally I opened up visual studio in my desktop machine. I simply connect to the team foundation server and tried to create a new &lt;em>Team Project&lt;/em>, inserted some values for my test project and then tried to create the project, but here is the result&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Error the specified windows sharepoint services site url is not the default site collection site</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/error-the-specified-windows-sharepoint-services-site-url-is-not-the-default-site-collection-site/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2009 14:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/error-the-specified-windows-sharepoint-services-site-url-is-not-the-default-site-collection-site/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m installing Tfs 2008 on a Virtual machine. Following the guide I saw that I need first to install Share Point Services 3.0 SP2 before installing team foundation server. You can find those part in the &lt;a href="http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?familyid=FF12844F-398C-4FE9-8B0D-9E84181D9923&amp;amp;amp;displaylang=en">guide&lt;/a> with the title &lt;em>How to: Install SharePoint Products and Technologies on Windows Server&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I followed all the instruction, but when team foundation server installer asked me the address of sharepoint site I tried some url but I got the infamous error&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Do not forget Array</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/do-not-forget-array/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/06/do-not-forget-array/</guid><description>&lt;p>I wrote a stupid util that does this operation: it scans a folder with 500.000 + files (in various subfolder), all files have name that contains an integer that is an id of a row in a database. I need to find orphan files, so I simply take file name, es: myfile_1002.txt, extracts the number 1002 and then verify if in a specific table of the database there is a row with index 1002.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Going in production as often as you can</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/05/going-in-production-as-often-as-you-can/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/05/going-in-production-as-often-as-you-can/</guid><description>&lt;p>I really care the concept of &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2009/05/09/good-programmers-put-code-in-production/">going in production&lt;/a>&lt;/em>, because it is the moment when the software bring to life. Going in production can be sometimes a really difficult thing to do, and there are a lot of reasons behind it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First of all we have the syndrome of * &lt;strong>It works on my machine&lt;/strong> *. The software run perfectly in developer&amp;rsquo;s machines, but when you move in production servers or into customers machines nothing work. If you ask developer, quite always you get this answer: &lt;em>HAve You installed library XYZ? Then have you wrote into the registry the SuperSecretKey XYXCWKDSAF, after you done this you should run for a mile, turn yourself for three time with fingers on your nose, &amp;hellip;.&lt;/em> This is the sign that you need at least a &lt;strong>document that explain how to deploy software,&lt;/strong> or you&amp;rsquo;re gonna kill your developers&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Occamrsquos Razor probably is the better principle to keep in mind</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/05/occams-razor-probably-is-the-better-principle-to-keep-in-mind/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2009 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/05/occams-razor-probably-is-the-better-principle-to-keep-in-mind/</guid><description>&lt;p>This morning I completely wasted 2 hours of my life, here is the history.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m rewriting some nant script for a series of articles in italian language, this morning I did some modification to the base script, and I applied this new base script to a solution with 6 projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everything went fine, except for the Test project, that does not compile because it does not see internals members of a project. I immediately did a verification, if I convert from internal to public, methods from base project, everything compiled.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What university misses to taught</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/05/what-university-misses-to-taught/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2009 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/05/what-university-misses-to-taught/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some time ago I had a discussion with a younger friend that goes to university. The argument of the discussion is &lt;em>what university misses to taught&lt;/em>, this question arise because a lot of persons that comes out of university are not immediately productive in a company.  Except people that had previously experiences while studying, quite often freshly graduated programmer needs some time to be really productive at work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These days I was thinking about this specific discussion, and I realized that probably the reason is related to &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2009/05/09/good-programmers-put-code-in-production/">this post&lt;/a>. I think that university misses the concept of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Production">Production&lt;/a> (&lt;em>Wikipedia: Production(information technology). software or hardware in active use&lt;/em>). When I was at university I did very interesting projects, but none of them was really gone in production. When a software does not go in production it does not become &lt;em>alive&lt;/em>, is like an unborn children, full of possibility, but still not alive.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Good programmers put code in production</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/05/good-programmers-put-code-in-production/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2009 03:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/05/good-programmers-put-code-in-production/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some days ago I did a post that generates a lot of comments, it is called &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2009/04/28/java-versus-net-programmers/">Java Versus.Net Programmers&lt;/a>, and it made me think that there are a lot of ideas out of there on &lt;strong>what are the characteristics that makes a good programmer&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of the time I hear people claiming that &lt;em>this is better than that&lt;/em>, &lt;em>programmers that does not knows concepts A B and C are not good ones&lt;/em>, etc. The problem is that the question remains not answered: &lt;em>What are the characteristics that make a programmer a good one?&lt;/em>. I think we could eventually speak for decades to search the answer for this question, and maybe after a long time we&amp;rsquo;ll find that the answer is 42, but we completely forget the question.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Web site VS Web application in Net</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/05/web-site-vs-web-application-in-net/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 01:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2009/05/web-site-vs-web-application-in-net/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had a big project that contains a big site written in asp.net webform and Visual Basic language. This site was created as &lt;em>web site&lt;/em>, and when it became really big, it start being really really slooowwww..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To give some number, in my machine I usually need about 30 seconds to compile it, and I have RAID disk array of Velociraptor (10.000 RPM), it was unacceptable. After long debate I follow &lt;a href="http://www.nablasoft.com/guardian/">Guardian&lt;/a> suggestion , and found &lt;a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/meligy/archive/2008/08/03/converting-vs-2008-website-to-web-application.aspx">this link&lt;/a> that explain how to convert a web site to a web application. It took about 6 hours to convert everything, but it worth time spent. Now the project in my computer compiles in about 3 seconds :o, the nant script that deploy the entire site now executes in 6 minutes against 7:30 of the previous version (it have to compile a lot of project, not only the web site). Solution opening time is also improved dramatically.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Faster invoke method of unknown objects with Expression tree part2</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/10/faster-invoke-method-of-unknown-objects-with-expression-tree-part2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2008 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/10/faster-invoke-method-of-unknown-objects-with-expression-tree-part2/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/index.php/2008/10/04/expression-tree-vs-reflection/">last post&lt;/a> I described a technique that uses Expression Tree to invoke dynamically methods of objects of types unknown at compile time. You can use this technique to build the &lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/expressiontreereflection.zip">ExpressionTreeReflection&lt;/a> class.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can now write code like this&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">
&lt;table style="border-spacing:0;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">&lt;tr>&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">1
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">2
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">3
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">4
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">5
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">6
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">7
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="white-space:pre;-webkit-user-select:none;user-select:none;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">8
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;;width:100%">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-xml" data-lang="xml">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>private static readonly Type suType = Type.GetType(&amp;#34;DotNetMarche.Common.Test.AuxClasses.SimpleUnknown, DotNetMarche.Common.Test&amp;#34;);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>private static readonly Object suInstance = Activator.CreateInstance(Type.GetType(&amp;#34;DotNetMarche.Common.Test.AuxClasses.SimpleUnknown, DotNetMarche.Common.Test&amp;#34;));
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[Test]
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>public void TestFuncNoArgInt32()
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>{ 
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> Func&lt;span style="color:#f92672">&amp;lt;Object&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010">,&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010">Int32&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">&amp;gt;&lt;/span> func = ExpressionTreeReflection.ReflectFunction&lt;span style="color:#f92672">&amp;lt;Int32&amp;gt;&lt;/span>(suType, &amp;#34;AMethod&amp;#34;);
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> Assert.That(func(suInstance), Is.EqualTo(1));
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>} &lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;!-- Code inserted with Steve Dunn's Windows Live Writer Code Formatter Plugin. http://dunnhq.com -->
&lt;p>You load a type unknown at compile time, the only information you know is the signature of one of its method, in the example is called AMethod and accepts no parameters and returns an Int32. The ReflectFunction() method of ExpressionTreeReflection helps you to build a Func&amp;lt;Object, Int32&amp;gt; you can use to call the method. This function accepts as first argument an instance of the object that contain the method to invoke, then all needed parameters. The first advantage is that you have a more strongly typed way to dynamically invoke the function instead of using reflection. Here is the code that invoke a function that need a string parameter.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The eternal conflict between customers and programmers</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/the-eternal-conflicts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2008 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/09/the-eternal-conflicts/</guid><description>&lt;p>In my experience it is not a good idea to put in direct communication stakeholders (customers) and programmers, here is the typical result&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/09/drawing.jpg">&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/09/drawing-thumb.jpg"> &lt;img src="https://www.codewrecks.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2008/09/drawing-thumb.jpg" alt="drawing" />&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lets analyze this typical situation from the perspective of the stakeholder; he have all the reason to ask for new features, he does not possess strong technical skills, and since he is the one who actually &lt;em>pay to build the software&lt;/em>, he does not understand why he cannot ask for a simple modification. Moreover the developer is speaking some obscure technical jargon, so he could not understand the reason behind these difficulties.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is policies for password really useful</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/is-policies-for-password-really-useful/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/is-policies-for-password-really-useful/</guid><description>&lt;p>This argument is discussed in the excellent book “&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Why-Software-Sucks-What-About/dp/0321466756/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;amp;qid=1219333268&amp;amp;amp;sr=8-1">Why Software Sucks&lt;/a>“, password policies are really useful?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I give you my opinion. I have really a lot of username/password ranges from my home banking account to various sites like, flickr, dotnetkick etc etc. My problem is that the amount of passwords is becoming really huge and I need a way to remember them with easy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The obvious solution is &lt;em>using the same password for every site&lt;/em>, but this is really insecure, if some site does not protects well my password (store it in clear text), a malicious user can grab username and password and can try to use it for other sites. Choosing only one password is not secure. At the other end of the spectrum is &lt;em>generate some random password, different for any site&lt;/em>, this is really more secure, but almost impossible to remember, so you have to write down them somewere…actually making this technique not so secure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crunch mode is effective</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/crunch-mode-is-effective/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2008 04:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/08/crunch-mode-is-effective/</guid><description>&lt;p>I stumbled on this &lt;a href="http://www.codemetropolis.com/archive/2008/07/31/crunch-mode-is-a-pure-waste-of-time-energy-and.aspx">post of Marco&lt;/a>, that directed me on the &lt;a href="http://www.igda.org/articles/erobinson_crunch.php">original post&lt;/a>, speaking about crunch time. In my experience it is a very abused technique, expecially here in Italy, where managers tells you “We are late, we are not in time, we must hurry, we must work more!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The original articles shows a lot of reasons why crunch time is not the solution to speed up the process, but in the end there are more, not really related to productivity, or sleep time or some other physical condition. In my experiences when you always work in crunch time you * &lt;strong>feel the hurry&lt;/strong> *, I do not know how to express this concept in good English, but it means that each day, when you begin to work, you really does not feel comfortable, you know that you are late, you are an overwhelming amount of code to write, you know that you will code even if in the weekend, you feel tired but you cannot stop working.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Share documents in a distributed team</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/share-documents-in-a-distributed-team/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2008 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/share-documents-in-a-distributed-team/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some days ago I received a mail with an analysis document for a Project I’m working to. Since we are a distributed team of programmers, someone still uses mail to share document with members of the team.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>This is simply WRONG!!!&lt;/strong> *&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The reason are&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It lacks tracking. Some people uses to append a version such as Document_Ver32.doc, but this is prone to error. If A and B modify the same document at the same time then we will have two version of Document_Ver33.doc….too bad.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The importance of good communication</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/the-importance-of-good-communication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2008 05:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/the-importance-of-good-communication/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a team, communication between members is of great importance. I found that a lot of bug or mistakes in software development, quite often derive from incomplete or not well conducted analysis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m not an expert of software analysis, but I found that a quite good analysis, even an informal one, can give great benefit to whole software development process. It is not important to conduct &lt;em>perfect analysis&lt;/em>, or that it covers all details, but there are some aspects that are really more important than anothers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>History of a merge</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/history-of-a-merge/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 00:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/06/history-of-a-merge/</guid><description>&lt;p>Source control management is the key to work on a team, but to work with it efficiently there is the need of experience. In a project, I’m working with some windows services that gather some data that is to be showed in a web application. I’m not supposed to work with the web application, that is developed by other two people of the team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>some days ago one of these programmer goes into big refactoring of the front end of the site, so he tells the other programmer not to modify a series of pages, to avoid conflicts. At the same time I was refactoring the database, I changed some stored procedures, and I move sorting and pagination in the server to speedup the application, this force me to do some little change on some pages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Programmer as a user friend or enemy</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/programmer-as-a-user-friend-or-enemy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 22:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/programmer-as-a-user-friend-or-enemy/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a project I’m working to, there is a point where the user is supposed to enter a series of word separated by space. A user call you telling that the routine does not work, you check the data and see that the object contains such a string&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“key1, key2, key3,key4”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What you will do as the programmer that write that part of the software.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Complain with the user, how he dare to call it a bug when he inserted data in the wrong format? The specification does not speak of comma separated values, moreover sometimes there is a space, sometimes no.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Distributed team 8211 wiki and documentation</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/distributed-team-wiki-and-documentation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 01:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/distributed-team-wiki-and-documentation/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the key problem with a distributed environment is a good sharing of documentation. It is not important what kind of Lifecycle you can have, from waterfall to Extreme programming, you will have some sort of documentation that needs to be shared among team members. The format of this documentation can vary, it can be composed by word document, UML diagrams, and whatever you like but it must satisfy some key requirements&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Working with distributed team 8211 VPN and source control</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/working-with-distributed-team-vpn-and-source-control/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2008 23:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/working-with-distributed-team-vpn-and-source-control/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another great tool for distributed teams is VPN (Virtual Private Network), with a VPN all the team members can live in the same virtual local network. This is important, first of all for security. VPN estabilish a secure channel between computer using an insecure transport as the internet, with wpn all the data is ciphered, so you can transmit company sensitive data with easy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To estabilish a vpn you should have the &lt;a href="http://www.codewrecks.com/blog/?p=272">Dedicated Server&lt;/a> I told you some days ago, and then you should decide how to create VPN. Windows have its native VPN that you can estabilish with a fews clicks, but I prefer to install Open VPN, that it’s easy to install, easy to mantain, and gives me good performance. Once you have your VPN running, you can share printer, folder, and you are working in a distributed office :D.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Working on a distributed enviroment 8211 The server</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/working-on-a-distributed-enviroment-the-server/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2008 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/working-on-a-distributed-enviroment-the-server/</guid><description>&lt;p>As I said in a previous post I worked mainly in a distributed environment. Such a kind of development requires some attention to avoid losing productivity because each member of the team is physically far from the other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first think you need is buy a Dedicated Server on some web farm. You need a dedicated server, and not a simple hosting, because you need full control of the machine, you should be able to install services, restart the machine and so on. You can also use a virtual server, but quite often it is best to have a machine on your own, this is necessary to avoid share hardware resources with all other people that share with you the physical server.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Working in distributed environment</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/working-in-distributed-environment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2008 02:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/working-in-distributed-environment/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the last years I worked mainly in distributed environment, with a &lt;a href="http://www.actvalue.com">company&lt;/a> based in Milan (Italy), We have a development group distributed along the nation, and I would share my opinion and experiences about such a particular environment. First of all I wish to enlist the good and bad thing based on this experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I work mainly at home, no need to get machine to go to work, I do no waste time in physically  move my person to an office, my house is my office.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Programming Experience a reflection on</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/programming-experience-a-reflection-on/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2008 06:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2008/05/programming-experience-a-reflection-on/</guid><description>&lt;p>This evening I’ve added a new category on the blog, and it’s called “*Experiences”,*and someone could ask why.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In these days I was thinking about my past experiences in programming or related stuff in these years. I’ve begin programming with the Vic20, when the prefix Mega appears only in science Fiction, now we speak about &lt;em>Tera&lt;/em> and the world of technology is definitively changed a lot since these days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This makes me think about how a person increase his/her knowledge during his/hers life. There are a lot of notions that are technologically bound, for example building a WPF application, Using NHibernate or Castle or some other libraries and so on. The problem is that technology is evolving incredibly fast, You still finished a project using.NET WebService (asmx) technology, and WCF renders all your work quite obsolete, you spent time to learn ajax technology when Microsoft Ajax gets out, but now we have silverlight….and it seems that for each new stuff you learn, there are ten new stuffs you do not have time to learn…to bad. We are reaching the point where the time needed to really master one technology is enough for that technology to become obsolete. But this does not means that the effort you did to master it is wasted, every thing we did as human being increase our &lt;em>Experience.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>