<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Zero Trust Security on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/zero-trust-security/</link><description>Recent content in Zero Trust Security on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 10:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/zero-trust-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Home Made Zero trust Security step 2</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/03/home-made-zero-trust-security-step-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 10:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/03/home-made-zero-trust-security-step-2/</guid><description>If you read my old post about how to create a simple program that can manage Windows Firewall to open ports with a simple udp request you surely got disappointed by the complete lack of security in the request. That program was no more than a mere proof of concept to understand if I can manage windows firewall programmatically in.NET Core. &amp;gt; The absolute critical problem in that program is that, UDP request to open a Tcp port is sent in clear text.</description></item><item><title>Home Made zero trust security</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/01/home-made-zero-trust-security/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 16:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2020/01/home-made-zero-trust-security/</guid><description>I have a small office with some computers and servers and since I’m a fan of Zero Trust Security, I have firewall enabled even in local network. I’m especially concerned about my primary workstation, a Windows Machine where I have explicitly created firewall rules to block EVERY packet from another machine of the network. I have backups, I have antivirus, but that machine is important and I do not want it to be compromised, working with a rule that block every contact from external code is nice and make it secure, but sometimes it is inconvenient.</description></item></channel></rss>