<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Upgrade on Codewrecks</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/upgrade/</link><description>Recent content in Upgrade on Codewrecks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 17:00:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codewrecks.com/tags/upgrade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One reason to upgrade to TFS 2017 Code search</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/01/one-reason-to-upgrade-to-tfs-2017-code-search/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2017/01/one-reason-to-upgrade-to-tfs-2017-code-search/</guid><description>I always suggest teams to use VSTS instead of on-premise TFS. The main reason is avoiding any issue with administration or upgrades. In these years, one of the main risk of having TFS on-premise is not planning for upgrade and keeping the first version installed for years. As a result, it is not uncommon to have teams that still uses TFS 2013 even if version 2017 is out.
For small teams usually there is not a dedicated TFS administrator; in this situation is it strongly advisable not to skip one entire major upgrade, to minimize the risk of a big bang upgrade.</description></item><item><title>Scale out deployment error when migrating Reporting Services</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/07/scale-out-deployment-error-when-migrating-reporting-services/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/07/scale-out-deployment-error-when-migrating-reporting-services/</guid><description>Part of moving your TFS Server on new hardware, or creating a Pre-Production environment is restoring Reporting Server database. Since Datatbase are encrypted, if you simply restore the database then configure Reporting Services on new machine to use restored database, this operation will fail, because the new server cannot read encrypted data.
Restoring Reporting Services database into a new instance involves some manual steps, especially you need to backup / restore encryption keys from your old server to the new one.</description></item><item><title>Isolate your TFS Pre-Production environment for maximum security</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/07/isolate-your-tfs-pre-production-environment-for-maximum-security/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/07/isolate-your-tfs-pre-production-environment-for-maximum-security/</guid><description>In previous post I’ve explained how to create a clone of your TFS Production environment thanks to the new TFS “15” wizard. With this post I want to share you a simple solution I have in my Bags of Tricks to avoid your TFS Cloned environment to interfere with production environment.
The problem In my environment I have all machines in network 10.0.0.0/24, my TFS has address 10.0.0.116 and Primary Domain Controller is 10.</description></item><item><title>Create a Pre-Production Test environment for your TFS</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/07/create-a-pre-production-test-environment-for-your-tfs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 08:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/07/create-a-pre-production-test-environment-for-your-tfs/</guid><description>There are a lot of legitmate reasons to create a clone of your TFS installation: verifying an upgrade, testing some customization and so on, but traditionally creating a test environment is not an easy task.
The problem is avoiding that the test installation could interfere and corrupt your production instance and since TFS is a complex product, there are a series of steps you need to do to perform this kind of operations.</description></item><item><title>TFS 2015 Update 2 is released</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/04/tfs-2015-update-2-is-released/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 09:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/04/tfs-2015-update-2-is-released/</guid><description>You can find all the details directly in Visual Studio Site, but I want to emphasize that TFS and VS Updates are much more than Service Packs , because they also intrdoduce a lot of new features. Here is a list of my personal favorites features of TFS Update 2
Introduction of new Release Management System New release management system is completely Web and does not require separate client to download, but this is not the only advantage.</description></item><item><title>Invalidate cache of TFS after a Server Move</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/01/invalidate-cache-of-tfs-after-a-server-move/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 17:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2016/01/invalidate-cache-of-tfs-after-a-server-move/</guid><description>If you move your TFS server in a new hardware be sure to follow the instructions in MSDN: Move or clone Team Foundation Server (hardware move).
There are many reason why you want to move TFS to a different hardware, probably you want to use a new powerful hardware and you have not virtualized TFS, or you need to upgrade TFS and you need to move Sql to a new hardware with a more recent version of SQL.</description></item><item><title>User added to Team Project have no permission after upgrade from TFS2010 to TFS2013</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/02/user-added-to-team-project-have-no-permission-after-upgrade-from-tfs2010-to-tfs2013/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 07:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2015/02/user-added-to-team-project-have-no-permission-after-upgrade-from-tfs2010-to-tfs2013/</guid><description>I’ve performed an upgrade from TFS2010 to TFS2013 at a customer site last week. The upgrade consisted in moving to a different machine and from a Workstation to an Active Directory Domain. The operation was simple, because the customer uses only Source Control and they want to spent minimal time in the operation, so we decided for this strategy
Stop TFS in the old machine Backup and restore db in the new machine Upgrade and verify that everything works correctly They do not care about user remapping, or reporting services or other stuff, they just want to do a quick migration to new version to use local workspaces new feature (introduced with TFS 2012).</description></item><item><title>TFSRestoreexe database restored with strange suffix</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/07/tfsrestore-exe-database-restored-with-strange-suffix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 18:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2013/07/tfsrestore-exe-database-restored-with-strange-suffix/</guid><description>This problem happens if you mix Team Foundation Server backup tools, the symptom is: you launch TfsRestore.exe and point to a local folder where a TFS backup is located, and when the database are restored they have strange suffix.
Figure 1: Strange suffix in database names after a restore with TfsRestore.exe
This happens when you use TfsRestore.exe to restore a backup taken with the Tfs Backup Scheduled Backup. Basically you have two distinct way to backup your TFS: the first one is using the TfsBackup.</description></item><item><title>Upgrade TFS2010 to TFS11 with Detach and Attach</title><link>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/upgrade-tfs2010-to-tfs11-with-detach-and-attach/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 20:00:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.codewrecks.com/post/old/2012/03/upgrade-tfs2010-to-tfs11-with-detach-and-attach/</guid><description>One of the simplest way to upgrade with minimum risk a Project Collection from TFS 2010 to TFS11 Beta is using the detach/attach feature of TFS, introduced with version 2010. Basically all you need to do is Detach the project collection from the old TFS 2010 server and reattach to a brand new TFS11 server, you can read about the whole procedure in an old post that explain how to Move a Team Project Collection from one server to another one.</description></item></channel></rss>